<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name></name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="backgrounds.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/van-richtens-guide-to-ravenloft/backgrounds.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--General Background Features-->
	<element name="Optional Feature: Inhereritor" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_INHERERITOR">
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An ancestor or mentor’s deeds earned them a place in legend. Now it’s your turn. You are the clear inheritor of a famed legacy. You’ve inherited a token from your predecessor, something that marks you as their inheritor, such as a signet ring, signature piece of clothing, or notable weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, any time you reveal your legacy, you swiftly learn the local opinion of your predecessor. If locals have never heard of your predecessor, nothing changes. If they have, rumors of your connection spread swiftly, and many locals consider you either a hero or a threat. Heroes are welcomed and might easily gain an audience with local leaders. Threats are encouraged to leave before they invite danger.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Inhereritor">
			<description>An ancestor or mentor’s deeds earned them a place in legend. Now it’s your turn. You are the clear inheritor of a famed legacy. You’ve inherited a token from your predecessor, something that marks you as their inheritor, such as a signet ring, signature piece of clothing, or notable weapon.&#13;
			Additionally, any time you reveal your legacy, you swiftly learn the local opinion of your predecessor. If locals have never heard of your predecessor, nothing changes. If they have, rumors of your connection spread swiftly, and many locals consider you either a hero or a threat. Heroes are welcomed and might easily gain an audience with local leaders. Threats are encouraged to leave before they invite danger.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Optional Feature: Mist Wanderer" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MIST_WANDERER">
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>After a fateful experience, you believe you’re aligned with spirits and can serve as a conduit for their insights and goals. You have advantage on any Arcana or Religion check you make to remember or research information about spirits and the afterlife. Additionally, you begin your adventuring career with a custom-made device for communing with otherworldly forces, perhaps a spirit board, a tarokka deck, an automatic writing planchette, dowsing rods, a cup for tea leaves, or a device of your own design. Add your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make using this type of divining tool.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Mist Wanderer">
			<description>After a fateful experience, you believe you’re aligned with spirits and can serve as a conduit for their insights and goals. You have advantage on any Arcana or Religion check you make to remember or research information about spirits and the afterlife. Additionally, you begin your adventuring career with a custom-made device for communing with otherworldly forces, perhaps a spirit board, a tarokka deck, an automatic writing planchette, dowsing rods, a cup for tea leaves, or a device of your own design. Add your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make using this type of divining tool.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Optional Feature: Spirit Medium" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SPIRIT_MEDIUM">
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Mists whisper to you and guide you through their mysterious eddies. You immediately know if an object you’re touching is a Mist talisman. You recognize where the talisman originates from if you have been to its domain of origin.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Spirit Medium">
			<description>The Mists whisper to you and guide you through their mysterious eddies. You immediately know if an object you’re touching is a Mist talisman. You recognize where the talisman originates from if you have been to its domain of origin.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Optional Feature: Trauma Survivor" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TRAUMA_SURVIVOR">
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You survived. Whatever it was, you made it through, and you can help others do the same. People view you as an expert on the traumatic situation you faced—be it a specific sort of violence, illness, or otherwise. You are aware of nonmagical recovery techniques, common resources, and misinformation. You know how to speak to sympathetic doctors, clergy, and local leaders and can convince them to shelter one person (other than yourself) at a modest lifestyle for up to one month.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Trauma Survivor">
			<description>You survived. Whatever it was, you made it through, and you can help others do the same. People view you as an expert on the traumatic situation you faced—be it a specific sort of violence, illness, or otherwise. You are aware of nonmagical recovery techniques, common resources, and misinformation. You know how to speak to sympathetic doctors, clergy, and local leaders and can convince them to shelter one person (other than yourself) at a modest lifestyle for up to one month.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Optional Feature: Traveler" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TRAVELER">
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You come from somewhere else, a place others couldn’t begin to understand. Perhaps your home is a unique corner of the Land of the Mists or another world entirely. In any case, you and other travelers have shared experiences. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among sympathetic trading caravans, itinerant families, or displaced groups, so long as you don’t present yourself as a danger. Such groups will hide you from the law or anyone searching for you, though they won’t risk their lives for you. Additionally, you can tell whether an object you can see and touch is from your homeland with near perfect accuracy.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Traveler">
			<description>You come from somewhere else, a place others couldn’t begin to understand. Perhaps your home is a unique corner of the Land of the Mists or another world entirely. In any case, you and other travelers have shared experiences. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among sympathetic trading caravans, itinerant families, or displaced groups, so long as you don’t present yourself as a danger. Such groups will hide you from the law or anyone searching for you, though they won’t risk their lives for you. Additionally, you can tell whether an object you can see and touch is from your homeland with near perfect accuracy.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Haunted One-->
	<element name="Haunted One" type="Background" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_HAUNTED_ONE">
		<description>
			<p>You are haunted by something so terrible that you dare not speak of it. You’ve tried to bury it and run away from it, to no avail. Whatever this thing is that haunts you can’t be slain with a sword or banished with a spell. It might come to you as a shadow on the wall, a bloodcurdling nightmare, a memory that refuses to die, or a demonic whisper in the dark. The burden has taken its toll, isolating you from most people and making you question your sanity. You must find a way to overcome it before it destroys you.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from among Arcana, Investigation, Religion, or Survival</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> Choose two, one of which must be Abyssal, Celestial, Deep Speech, Draconic, Infernal, Primordial, Sylvan, or Undercommon</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A monster hunter’s pack (containing a chest, a crowbar, a hammer, three wooden stakes, a holy symbol, a flask of holy water, a set of manacles, a steel mirror, a flask of oil, a tinderbox, and 3 torches), one trinket of special significance, a set of common clothes, and 1 sp.</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>HARROWING EVENT</h5>
			<p>Prior to becoming an adventurer, your path in life was defined by one dark moment, one fateful decision, or one tragedy. Now you feel a darkness threatening to consume you, and you fear there may be no hope of escape. Choose a harrowing event that haunts you, or roll one on the Harrowing Events table.</p>
			<h5>Harrowing Event</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Event</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>A monster that slaughtered dozens of innocent people spared your life, and you don’t know why.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You were born under a dark star. You can feel it watching you, coldly and distantly. Sometimes it beckons you in the dead of night.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>An apparition that has haunted your family for generations now haunts you. You don’t know what it wants, and it won’t leave you alone.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Your family has a history of practicing the dark arts. You dabbled once and felt something horrible clutch at your soul, whereupon you fled in terror.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>An oni took your sibling one cold, dark night, and you were unable to stop it.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>You were cursed with lycanthropy and later cured. You are now haunted by the innocents you slaughtered.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>A hag kidnapped and raised you. You escaped, but the hag still has a magical hold over you and fills your mind with evil thoughts.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>You opened an eldritch tome and saw things unfit for a sane mind. You burned the book, but its words and images are burned into your psyche.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>A fiend possessed you as a child. You were locked away but escaped. The fiend is still inside you, but now you try to keep it bottled up.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>You did terrible things to avenge the murder of someone you loved. You became a monster, and it haunts your waking dreams.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HEART_OF_DARKNESS" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">2 Skills from Arcana/Investigation/Religion/Survival, 1 Exotic and 1 other Language</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HEART_OF_DARKNESS" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Harrowing Event">
				<item id="1">A monster that slaughtered dozens of innocent people spared your life, and you don’t know why.</item>
				<item id="2">You were born under a dark star. You can feel it watching you, coldly and distantly. Sometimes it beckons you in the dead of night.</item>
				<item id="3">An apparition that has haunted your family for generations now haunts you. You don’t know what it wants, and it won’t leave you alone.</item>
				<item id="4">Your family has a history of practicing the dark arts. You dabbled once and felt something horrible clutch at your soul, whereupon you fled in terror.</item>
				<item id="5">An oni took your sibling one cold, dark night, and you were unable to stop it.</item>
				<item id="6">You were cursed with lycanthropy and later cured. You are now haunted by the innocents you slaughtered.</item>
				<item id="7">A hag kidnapped and raised you. You escaped, but the hag still has a magical hold over you and fills your mind with evil thoughts.</item>
				<item id="8">You opened an eldritch tome and saw things unfit for a sane mind. You burned the book, but its words and images are burned into your psyche.</item>
				<item id="9">A fiend possessed you as a child. You were locked away but escaped. The fiend is still inside you, but now you try to keep it bottled up.</item>
				<item id="10">You did terrible things to avenge the murder of someone you loved. You became a monster, and it haunts your waking dreams.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Haunted One)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA | ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION | ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION | ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
			<select type="Language" name="Exotic Language (Haunted One)" supports="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL|ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL|ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH|ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC|ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL|ID_LANGUAGE_PRIMORDIAL|ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN|ID_LANGUAGE_UNDERCOMMON" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Haunted One)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Feature: Heart of Darkness" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HEART_OF_DARKNESS">
		<description>
			<p>Those who look into your eyes can see that you have faced unimaginable horror and that you are no stranger to darkness. Though they might fear you, commoners will extend you every courtesy and do their utmost to help you. Unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them, they will even take up arms to fight alongside you, should you find yourself facing an enemy alone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Heart of Darkness">
			<description>Those who look into your eyes can see that you have faced unimaginable horror and that you are no stranger to darkness. Though they might fear you, commoners will extend you every courtesy and do their utmost to help you. Unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them, they will even take up arms to fight alongside you, should you find yourself facing an enemy alone.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!--Investigator-->
	<element name="Investigator" type="Background" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_INVESTIGATOR">
		<description>
			<p>You relentlessly seek the truth. Perhaps you’re motivated by belief in the law and a sense of universal justice, or maybe that very law has failed you and you seek to make things right. You could have witnessed something remarkable or terrible, and now you must know more about this hidden truth. Or maybe you’re a detective for hire, uncovering secrets for well-paying clients. Whether the mysteries you’re embroiled in are local crimes or realm-spanning conspiracies, you’re driven by a personal need to hunt down even the most elusive clues and reveal what others would keep hidden in the shadows.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from among Insight, Investigation, or Perception</li>
				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Disguise kit, Thieves’ tools</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A magnifying glass, evidence from a past case, a set of common clothes, and 10 gp</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>Path to Mystery</h5>
			<p>Your first case influenced the types of mysteries you’re interested in. Why was this case so impactful, personal, or traumatic? Whom did it affect besides you? Why and how did you get involved? Was it solved? How did it set you on the path to investigating other mysteries? Roll on or choose details from the First Case table to develop the mystery that started your career as an investigator.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d8</td><td>First Case</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>A friend was wrongfully accused of murder. You tracked down the actual killer, proving your friend’s innocence and starting your career as a detective.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You’re told you went missing for weeks. When you were found, you had no memory of being gone. Now you search to discover what happened to you.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>You helped a spirit find peace by finding its missing corpse. Ever since, other spectral clients have sought you out to help them find rest.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>You revealed that the monsters terrorizing your home were illusions created by a cruel mage. The magic-user escaped, but you’ve continued to uncover magical hoaxes.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>You were wrongfully accused and convicted of a crime. You managed to escape and seek to help others avoid the experience you suffered, even while still being pursued by the law.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>You survived the destructive use of a magic device that wiped out your home. Members of a secret organization found you. You now work with them, tracking down dangerous supernatural phenomena and preventing them from doing harm.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>You found evidence of a conspiracy underpinning society. You tried to expose this mysterious cabal, but no one believed you. You’re still trying to prove what you know is true.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>You got a job with an agency that investigates crimes that local law enforcement can’t solve. You often wonder which you value more, the truth or your pay.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_OFFICIAL_INQUIRY" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">2 Skills from Insight/Investigation/Perception, Disguise kit, Thieves’ tools</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_OFFICIAL_INQUIRY" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="First Case">
				<item id="1">A friend was wrongfully accused of murder. You tracked down the actual killer, proving your friend’s innocence and starting your career as a detective.</item>
				<item id="2">You’re told you went missing for weeks. When you were found, you had no memory of being gone. Now you search to discover what happened to you.</item>
				<item id="3">You helped a spirit find peace by finding its missing corpse. Ever since, other spectral clients have sought you out to help them find rest.</item>
				<item id="4">You revealed that the monsters terrorizing your home were illusions created by a cruel mage. The magic-user escaped, but you’ve continued to uncover magical hoaxes.</item>
				<item id="5">You were wrongfully accused and convicted of a crime. You managed to escape and seek to help others avoid the experience you suffered, even while still being pursued by the law.</item>
				<item id="6">You survived the destructive use of a magic device that wiped out your home. Members of a secret organization found you. You now work with them, tracking down dangerous supernatural phenomena and preventing them from doing harm.</item>
				<item id="7">You found evidence of a conspiracy underpinning society. You tried to expose this mysterious cabal, but no one believed you. You’re still trying to prove what you know is true.</item>
				<item id="8">You got a job with an agency that investigates crimes that local law enforcement can’t solve. You often wonder which you value more, the truth or your pay.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Investigator)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT | ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION | ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Feature: Official Inquiry" type="Background Feature" source="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" id="ID_WOTC_VRGTR_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_OFFICIAL_INQUIRY">
		<description>
			<p>You’re experienced at gaining access to people and places to get the information you need. Through a combination of fast-talking, determination, and official-looking documentation, you can gain access to a place or an individual related to a crime you’re investigating. Those who aren’t involved in your investigation avoid impeding you or pass along your requests. Additionally, local law enforcement has firm opinions about you, viewing you as either a nuisance or one of their own.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Official Inquiry">
			<description>You’re experienced at gaining access to people and places to get the information you need. Through a combination of fast-talking, determination, and official-looking documentation, you can gain access to a place or an individual related to a crime you’re investigating. Those who aren’t involved in your investigation avoid impeding you or pass along your requests. Additionally, local law enforcement has firm opinions about you, viewing you as either a nuisance or one of their own.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
