<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/van-richtens-guide-to-ravenloft/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Van Richten's Guide To Ravenloft" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_VAN_RICHTENS_GUIDE_TO_RAVENLOFT">
		<description>
			<h5 style="margin-top:-1em">FACE YOUR FEARS</h5>
			<p><strong>Unleash the horrors of Ravenloft in this campaign sourcebook for the world's greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p>
			<p>Terror stalks the nightmare realms of Ravenloft. No one knows this better than monster scholar Rudolph Van Richten. To arm a new generation against the creatures of the night, Van Richten has compiled his correspondence and case files into this tome of eerie tales and chilling truths.</p>
			<p>Discover the mysteries of Ravenloft, mist-shrouded lands where infamous Darklords lurk among ageless vampires, zombie hordes, cosmic terrors, and worse. Then make your choice. Will you create your own Domains of Dread, settings to host endless terrifying adventures? Or will you join the ranks of haunted heroes who embrace macabre lineages, dual-edged Dark Gifts, haunted subclasses, and other forbidden powers?</p>
			<p><i>Van Richten's Guide to Ravenloft</i> contains everything you need to craft a horror-themed campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. Unleash a treasure trove of new story hooks, character options, and campaign customization to bring one of the most exciting Dungeons &amp; Dragons settings to life!</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Travel (perhaps even by choice) to familiar domains and discover new ones—as Ravenloft’s expanded Domains of Dread return for the first time in fifth edition! Includes rules and advice for building custom domains and Darklords using established horror tropes or your own special blend.</li>
				<li>Discover a host of new backgrounds and trinkets themed specifically for a horror setting, as well as new character lineages, including the dhampir, hexblood, and reborn.</li>
				<li>Find two new subclasses, the College of Spirits for bards and the Undead pact for warlocks.</li>
				<li>Explore Dark Gifts for characters that flesh out your place in the Domains of Dread.</li>
				<li>Encounter a horrific assortment of creatures from the monstrous bestiary.</li>
				<li>And includes a brand-new adventure!</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">VRGTR</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/van-richtens-guide-ravenloft</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/van-richtens-guide-to-ravenloft/VRGTR.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20210518</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
