<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/players-handbook-2024/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Player’s Handbook (2024)" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_PLAYERS_HANDBOOK_2024">
		<description>
			<h5 style="margin-top:-1em">THE ESSENTIAL RESOURCE FOR DUNGEONS &amp; DRAGONS PLAYERS</h5>
			<p><strong>Dive into the biggest Player’s Handbook in Dungeons &amp; Dragons history, thoughtfully redesigned based on 10 years of feedback from the D&amp;D community.</strong></p>
			<p>Introducing the <i>2024 Player’s Handbook</i>, the new and improved guide for fifth edition DUNGEONS &amp; DRAGONS. We’ve loved hearing from you and built this book to deliver what you want—and more! Packed with endless character options, striking illustrations, and a streamlined design, every part of this 384-page book is a joy to experience. Play however you want with optimized rules for character creation and advancement, exploration, combat, equipment, spells, and much more. Create characters you’ll love from an expanded selection of character options, revised and balanced for maximum fun.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>UNLEASH NEW POSSIBILITIES.</b> Introducing the <i>2024 Player’s Handbook</i>, the new and improved guide for fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons. Redesigned with 10 years of feedback from the D&amp;D community, the essential Dungeons &amp; Dragons rulebook is bigger and better than ever before!</li>
				<li><b>NEW CHARACTER OPTIONS YOU’LL LOVE.</b> Create unforgettable characters with 12 core classes, 48 intriguing subclasses, and 10 distinctive species. Buff up your character’s backstory with 16 compelling backgrounds and 75 fantastic feats.</li>
				<li><b>STUNNING ARTWORK.</b> With vibrant new illustrations of every single character class, subclass, background, species, weapon, and armor, our thrilling artwork also features new and familiar spells, brought to life for the first time ever.</li>
				<li><b>FRESH &amp; ENGAGING GAMEPLAY.</b> Change up your combat style with fascinating new Weapon Masteries for your character class. Our new Tools and Crafting system lets you use your tools to craft items and impact travel and exploration.</li>
				<li><b>DESIGNED JUST FOR YOU.</b> We’ve thoughtfully redesigned this book with an improved layout, better organization, and an alphabetized Rules Glossary. Find whatever you’re looking for with ease!</li>
				<li><b>PART OF THE 2024 CORE COLLECTION.</b> 1 of 3 revised core rulebooks, the <i>2024 Player’s Handbook</i> is designed for use with the fifth edition <i>2024 Dungeon Master’s Guide</i> and <i>2024 Monster Manual</i>.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">PHB24</set>
			<set name="url">https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/en/product/1001494/2024-player-s-handbook-digital-plus-physical-bundle</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/players-handbook-2024/PHB24.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="information">D&amp;D 5.5e</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="core">false</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20240917</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
