<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Weapons</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.8">
			<file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/dungeon-masters-guide/items/items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Weapon, +1" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_1">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} +{{enhancement}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon, +2" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_2">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} +{{enhancement}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon, +3" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_3">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} +{{enhancement}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Javelin of Lightning" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_JAVELIN_OF_LIGHTNING">
		<description>
			<p>This javelin is a magic weapon. When you hurl it and speak its command word, it transforms into a bolt of lightning, forming a line 5 feet wide that extends out from you to a target within 120 feet. Each creature in the line excluding you and the target must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 lightning damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The lightning bolt turns back into a javelin when it reaches the target. Make a ranged weapon attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes damage from the javelin plus 4d6 lightning damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The javelin's property can't be used again until the next dawn. In the meantime, the javelin can still be used as a magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">javelin</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Javelin</set>
			<set name="name-format">Javelin of Lightning</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Vengeance" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_VENGEANCE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> This sword is cursed and possessed by a vengeful spirit. Becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the sword, keeping it on your person at all times. While attuned to this weapon, you have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while the sword is on your person, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw whenever you take damage in combat. On a failed save you must attack the creature that damaged you until you drop to 0 hit points or it does, or until you can't reach the creature to make a melee attack against it.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can break the curse in the usual ways. Alternatively, casting banishment on the sword forces the vengeful spirit to leave it. The sword then becomes a +1 weapon with no other properties.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Vengeance</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Trident of Fish Command" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_TRIDENT_OF_FISH_COMMAND">
		<description>
			<p>This trident is a magic weapon. It has 3 charges. While you carry it, you can use an action and expend 1 charge to cast <em>dominate beast</em> (save DC 15) from it on a beast that has an innate swimming speed. The trident regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">trident</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="trident">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Trident</set>
			<set name="name-format">Trident of Fish Command</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon of Warning" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_OF_WARNING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon warns you of danger. While the weapon is on your person, you have advantage on initiative rolls. In addition, you and any of your companions within 30 feet of you can't be surprised, except when incapacitated by something other than nonmagical sleep. The weapon magically awakens you and your companions within range if any of you are sleeping naturally when combat begins.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Warning</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Berserker Axe" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BERSERKER_AXE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, while you are attuned to this weapon, your hit point maximum increases by 1 for each level you have attained.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> This axe is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the axe, keeping it within reach at all times.  You also have disadvantage on attack rolls with weapons other than this one, unless no foe is within 60 feet of you that you can see or hear.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever a hostile creature damages you while the axe is in your possession, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or go berserk. While berserk, you must use your action each round to attack the creature nearest to you with the axe. If you can make extra attacks as part of the Attack action, you use those extra attacks, moving to attack the next nearest creature after you fell your current target. If you have multiple possible targets, you attack one at random.  You are berserk until you start your turn with no creatures within 60 feet of you that you can see or hear.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any axe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
			<set name="name-format">Berserker {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dagger of Venom" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DAGGER_OF_VENOM">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action to cause thick, black poison to coat the blade. The poison remains for 1 minute or until an attack using this weapon hits a creature. That creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or take 2d10 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 minute. The dagger can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dagger</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dragon Slayer" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DRAGON_SLAYER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a dragon with this weapon, the dragon takes an extra 3d6 damage of the weapon's type. For the purpose of this weapon, "dragon" refers to any creature with the dragon type, including dragon turtles and wyverns.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flame Tongue" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FLAME_TONGUE">
		<description>
			<p>You can use a bonus action to speak this magic sword's command word, causing flames to erupt from the blade. These flames shed bright light in a 40-foot radius and dim light for an additional 40 feet. While the sword is ablaze, it deals an extra 2d6 fire damage to any target it hits. The flames last until you use a bonus action to speak the command word again or until you drop or sheathe the sword.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire, damage</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Giant Slayer" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_GIANT_SLAYER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a giant with it, the giant takes an extra 2d6 damage of the weapon's type and must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or fall prone. For the purpose of this weapon, "giant" refers to any creature with the giant type, including ettins and trolls.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">axe, sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe or sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mace of Disruption" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_DISRUPTION">
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a fiend or an undead with this magic weapon, that creature takes an extra 2d6 radiant damage. If the target has 25 hit points or fewer after taking this damage, it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be destroyed. On a successful save, the creature becomes frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you hold this weapon, it sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mace of Smiting" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_SMITING">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The bonus increases to +3 when you use the mace to attack a construct.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, the target takes an extra 2d6 bludgeoning damage, or 4d6 bludgeoning damage if it's a construct. If a construct has 25 hit points or fewer after taking this damage, it is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mace of Terror" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_TERROR">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon has 3 charges. While holding it, you can use an action and expend 1 charge to release a wave of terror. Each creature of your choice in a 30-foot radius extending from you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute. While it is frightened in this way, a creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If it has nowhere it can move, the creature can use the Dodge action. At the end of each of its turns, a creature can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">The mace regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sun Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SUN_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This item appears to be a longsword hilt. While grasping the hilt, you can use a bonus action to cause a blade of pure radiance to spring into existence, or make the blade disappear. While the blade exists, this magic longsword has the finesse property. If you are proficient with shortswords or longswords, you are proficient with the <em>sun blade</em>.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, which deals radiant damage instead of slashing damage. When you hit an undead with it, that target takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sword's luminous blade emits bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. The light is sunlight. While the blade persists, you can use an action to expand or reduce its radius of bright and dim light by 5 feet each, to a maximum of 30 feet each or a minimum of 10 feet each.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword,radiant</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Life Stealing" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_LIFE_STEALING">
		<description>
			<p>When you attack a creature with this magic weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, that target takes an extra 3d6 necrotic damage, provided that the target isn't a construct or an undead. You gain temporary hit points equal to the extra damage dealt.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Life Stealing</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Wounding" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_WOUNDING">
		<description>
			<p>Hit points lost to this weapon's damage can be regained only through a short or long rest, rather than by regeneration, magic, or any other means.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once per turn, when you hit a creature with an attack using this magic weapon, you can wound the target. At the start of each of the wounded creature's turns, it takes 1d4 necrotic damage for each time you've wounded it, and it can then make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, ending the effect of all such wounds on itself on a success. Alternatively, the wounded creature, or a creature within 5 feet of it, can use an action to make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check, ending the effect of such wounds on it on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Wounding</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vicious Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_VICIOUS_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>When you roll a 20 on your attack roll with this magic weapon, your critical hit deals an extra 2d6 damage of the weapon's type.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Vicious {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dancing Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DANCING_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>You can use a bonus action to toss this magic sword into the air and speak the command word. When you do so, the sword begins to hover, flies up to 30 feet, and attacks one creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The sword uses your attack roll and ability score modifier to damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the sword hovers, you can use a bonus action to cause it to fly up to 30 feet to another spot within 30 feet of you. As part of the same bonus action, you can cause the sword to attack one creature within 5 feet of it.</p>
			<p class="indent">After the hovering sword attacks for the fourth time, it flies up to 30 feet and tries to return to your hand. If you have no hand free, it falls to the ground at your feet. If the sword has no unobstructed path to you, it moves as close to you as it can and then falls to the ground.  It also ceases to hover if you grasp it or move more than 30 feet away from it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Dancing {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dwarven Thrower" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DWARVEN_THROWER">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the thrown property with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with a ranged attack using this weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 damage or, if the target is a giant, 2d8 damage. Immediately after the attack, the weapon flies back to your hand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">warhammer, dwarf</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a dwarf">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Frost Brand" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_FROST_BRAND">
		<description>
			<p>When you hit with an attack using this magic sword, the target takes an extra 1d6 cold damage. In addition, while you hold the sword, you have resistance to fire damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">In freezing temperatures, the blade sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you draw this weapon, you can extinguish all nonmagical flames within 30 feet of you. This property can be used no more than once per hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Nine Lives Stealer" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_NINE_LIVES_STEALER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sword has 1d8 + 1 charges. If you score a critical hit against a creature that has fewer than 100 hit points, it must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be slain instantly as the sword tears its life force from its body (a construct or an undead is immune). The sword loses 1 charge if the creature is slain. When the sword has no charges remaining, it loses this property.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="charges">1d8+1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Oathbow" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_OATHBOW">
		<description>
			<p>When you nock an arrow on this bow, it whispers in Elvish, "Swift defeat to my enemies." When you use this weapon to make a ranged attack, you can, as a command phrase, say, "Swift death to you who have wronged me." The target of your attack becomes your sworn enemy until it dies or until dawn seven days later. You can have only one such sworn enemy at a time. When your sworn enemy dies, you can choose a new one after the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you make a ranged attack roll with this weapon against your sworn enemy, you have advantage on the roll. In addition, your target gains no benefit from cover, other than total cover, and you suffer no disadvantage due to long range. If the attack hits, your sworn enemy takes an extra 3d6 piercing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">While your sworn enemy lives, you have disadvantage on attack rolls with all other weapons.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longbow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Scimitar of Speed" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SCIMITAR_OF_SPEED">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, you can make one attack with it as a bonus action on each of your turns.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">scimitar</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Sharpness" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_SHARPNESS">
		<description>
			<p>When you attack an object with this magic sword and hit, maximize your weapon damage dice against the target.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you attack a creature with this weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, that target takes an extra 4d6 slashing damage. Then roll another d20. If you roll a 20, you lop off one of the target's limbs, with the effect of such loss determined by the GM. If the creature has no limb to sever, you lop off a portion of its body instead.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, you can speak the sword's command word to cause the blade to shed bright light in a 10- foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. Speaking the command word again or sheathing the sword puts out the light.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword that deals slashing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS,ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Sharpness</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Defender" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_DEFENDER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The first time you attack with the sword on each of your turns, you can transfer some or all of the sword's bonus to your Armor Class, instead of using the bonus on any attacks that turn. For example, you could reduce the bonus to your attack and damage rolls to +1 and gain a +2 bonus to AC. The adjusted bonuses remain in effect until the start of your next turn, although you must hold the sword to gain a bonus to AC from it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hammer of Thunderbolts" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMMER_OF_THUNDERBOLTS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Giant's Bane (Requires Attunement).</em></strong> You must be wearing a <em>belt of giant strength</em> (any variety) and <em>gauntlets of ogre power</em> to attune to this weapon. The attunement ends if you take off either of those items. While you are attuned to this weapon and holding it, your Strength score increases by 4 and can exceed 20, but not 30. When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon against a giant, the giant must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or die.</p>
			<p class="indent">The hammer also has 5 charges. While attuned to it, you can expend 1 charge and make a ranged weapon attack with the hammer, hurling it as if it had the thrown property with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. If the attack hits, the hammer unleashes a thunderclap audible out to 300 feet. The target and every creature within 30 feet of it must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn. The hammer regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">maul</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="maul">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MAULS</set>
			<set name="charges">5</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="4" />
			<stat name="strength:max" value="10" />
			<!-- todo: set stacking bonus on base [strength:max] -->
			<!-- todo: requirement for [equipped (attunement is not required)] -->
			<!-- requirement="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_GAUNTLETS_OF_OGRE_POWER,(ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_HILL_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_STONE_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_FROST_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_FIRE_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_CLOUD_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_STORM_GIANT_STRENGTH)" -->
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Holy Avenger" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_HOLY_AVENGER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit a fiend or an undead with it, that creature takes an extra 2d10 radiant damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you hold the drawn sword, it creates an aura in a 10-foot radius around you. You and all creatures friendly to you in the aura have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. If you have 17 or more levels in the paladin class, the radius of the aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword, paladin</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a paladin">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Luck Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_LUCK_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While the sword is on your person, you also gain a +1 bonus to saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Luck.</em></strong> If the sword is on your person, you can call on its luck (no action required) to reroll one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you dislike. You must use the second roll. This property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Wish.</em></strong> The sword has 1d4-1 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 charge and cast the <em>wish</em> spell from it. This property can't be used again until the next dawn. The sword loses this property if it has no charges.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="charges">1d4-1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Answering" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_ANSWERING">
		<!-- todo: create 9 seperate weapons based on alignment ? -->
		<description>
			<p>In the world of Greyhawk, only nine of these blades are known to exist. Each is patterned after the legendary sword Fragarach, which is variously translated as "Final Word." Each of the nine swords has its own name and alignment, and each bears a different gem in its pommel.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this sword. In addition, while you hold the sword, you can use your reaction to make one melee attack with it against any creature in your reach that deals damage to you. You have advantage on the attack roll, and any damage dealt with this special attack ignores any damage immunity or resistance the target has.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Name</td><td>Alignment</td><td>Gem</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Answerer</td><td>Chaotic good</td><td>Emerald</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Back Talker</td><td>Chaotic evil</td><td>Jet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Concluder</td><td>Lawful neutral</td><td>Amethyst</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Last Quip</td><td>Chaotic neutral</td><td>Tourmaline</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Rebutter</td><td>Neutral good</td><td>Topaz</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Replier</td><td>Neutral</td><td>Peridot</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Retorter</td><td>Lawful good</td><td>Aquamarine</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Scather</td><td>Lawful evil</td><td>Garnet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Squelcher</td><td>Neutral evil</td><td>Spinel</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with the same alignment as the sword">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vorpal Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_VORPAL_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, the weapon ignores resistance to slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you attack a creature that has at least one head with this weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, you cut off one of the creature's heads. The creature dies if it can't survive without the lost head. A creature is immune to this effect if it is immune to slashing damage, doesn't have or need a head, has legendary actions, or the GM decides that the creature is too big for its head to be cut off with this weapon. Such a creature instead takes an extra 6d8 slashing damage from the hit.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword that deals slashing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Whelm" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WHELM">
		<description>
			<p><em>Whelm</em> is a powerful warhammer forged by dwarves and lost in the dungeon of White Plume Mountain.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. At dawn the day after you first make an attack roll with <em>Whelm</em>, you develop a fear of being outdoors that persists as long as you remain attuned to the weapon. This causes you to have disadvantage on attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks while you can see the daytime sky.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Thrown Weapon.</b></i> <em>Whelm</em> has the thrown property, with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with a ranged weapon attack using it, the target takes an extra 1d8 bludgeoning damage, or an extra 2d8 bludgeoning damage if the target is a giant. Each time you throw the weapon, it flies back to your hand after the attack. If you don't have a hand free, the weapon lands at your feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Shock Wave.</b></i> You can use an action to strike the ground with <em>Whelm</em> and send a shock wave out from the point of impact. Each creature of your choice on the ground within 60 feet of that point must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or become stunned for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Supernatural Awareness.</b></i> While you are holding the weapon, it alerts you to the location of any secret or concealed doors within 30 feet of you. In addition, you can use an action to cast <i>detect evil and good</i> or <i>locate object</i> from the weapon. Once you cast either spell, you can't cast it from the weapon again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sentience.</b></i> <em>Whelm</em> is a sentient lawful neutral weapon with an Intelligence of 15, a Wisdom of 12, and a Charisma of 15. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and can speak, read, and understand Dwarvish. Giant, and Goblin. It shouts battle cries in Dwarvish when used in combat.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Personality.</b></i> <em>Whelm's</em> purpose is to slaughter giants and goblinoids. It also seeks to protect dwarves against all enemies. Conflict arises if the wielder fails to destroy goblins and giants or to protect dwarves. </p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Whelm</em> has ties to the dwarf clan that created it, variously called the Dankil or the Mightyhammer clan. It longs to be returned to that clan. It would do anything to protect those dwarves from harm. </p>
			<p class="indent">The hammer also carries a secret shame. Centuries ago, a dwarf named Ctenmiir wielded it valiantly for a time. But Ctenmiir was turned into a vampire. His will was strong enough that he bent Whelm to his evil purposes, even killing members of his own clan.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">warhammer</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a dwarf"> true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Wave" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_WAVE">
		<description>
			<p>Held in the dungeon of White Plume Mountain, this trident is an exquisite weapon engraved with images of waves, shells, and sea creatures. Although you must worship a god of the sea to attune to this weapon, <em>Wave</em> happily accepts new converts.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. If you score a critical hit with it, the target takes extra necrotic damage equal to half its hit point maximum.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon also functions as a <em>trident of fish command</em> and a <em>weapon of warning</em>. It can confer the benefit of a <em>cap of water breathing</em> while you hold it, and you can use it as a <em>cube of force</em> by choosing the effect, instead of pressing cube sides to select it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sentience.</b></i> <em>Wave</em> is a sentient weapon of neutral alignment, with an Intelligence of 14, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 18. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and can speak, read, and understand Aquan. It can also speak with aquatic animals as if using a <i>speak with animals</i> spell, using telepathy to involve its wielder in the conversation.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Personality.</b></i> When it grows restless, <em>Wave</em> has a habit of humming tunes that vary from sea chanteys to sacred hymns of the sea gods. </p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Wave</em> zealously desires to convert mortals to the worship of one or more sea gods, or else to consign the faithless to death. Conflict arises if the wielder fails to further the weapon's objectives in the world. The trident has a nostalgic attachment to the place where it was forged, a desolate island called Thunderforge. A sea god imprisoned a family of storm giants there, and the giants forged Wave in an act of devotion to—or rebellion against—that god.</p> 
			<p class="indent"><em>Wave</em> harbors a secret doubt about its own nature and purpose. For all its devotion to the sea gods, <em>Wave</em> fears that it was intended to bring about a particular sea god's demise. This destiny is something <em>Wave</em> might not be able to avert.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">trident</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="trident">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature that worships a god of the sea"> true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Trident</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Moonblade" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_MOONBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>Of all the magic items created by the elves, one of the most prized and jealously guarded is a <em>moonblade</em>. In ancient times, nearly all elven noble houses claimed one such blade. Over the centuries, some blades have faded from the world, their magic lost as family lines have become extinct. Other blades have vanished with their bearers during great quests. Thus, only a few of these weapons remain.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <em>moonblade</em> passes down from parent to child. The sword chooses its bearer and remains bonded to that person for life. If the bearer dies, another heir can claim the blade. If no worthy heir exists, the sword lies dormant. It functions like a normal longsword until a worthy soul finds it and lays claim to its power.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <em>moonblade</em> serves only one master at a time. The attunement process requires a special ritual in the throne room of an elven regent or in a temple dedicated to the elven gods.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <em>moonblade</em> won't serve anyone it regards as craven, erratic, corrupt, or at odds with preserving and protecting elvenkind. If the blade rejects you, you make ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws with disadvantage for 24 hours. If the blade accepts you, you become attuned to it and a new rune appears on the blade. You remain attuned to the weapon until you die or the weapon is destroyed.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <em>moonblade</em> has one rune on its blade for each master it has served (typically 1d6 + 1). The first rune always grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Each rune beyond the first grants the <em>moonblade</em> an additional property. The DM chooses each property or determines it randomly on the Moon Blade Properties table.</p>
			<h5>MOONBLADE PROPERTIES</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d100</td><td>Property</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1-40</td><td>Increase the bonus to attack and damage rolls by 1, to a maximum of +3. Reroll if the <em>moonblade</em> already has a +3 bonus.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>41-80</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> gains a randomly determined minor property (see "Special Features" in <i>Dungeon Master’s Guide</i> on page 143).</td></tr>
				<tr><td>81-82</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> gains the finesse property.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>83-84</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> gains the thrown property (range 20/60 feet).</td></tr>
				<tr><td>85-86</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> functions as a <em>defender</em>.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>87-90</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> scores a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>91-92</td><td>When you hit with an attack using the <em>moonblade</em>, the attack deals an extra 1d6 slashing damage.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>93-94</td><td>When you hit a creature of a specific type (such as dragon, fiend, or undead) with the <em>moonblade</em>, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage of one of these types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>95-96</td><td>You can use a bonus action to cause the <em>moonblade</em> to flash brightly. Each creature that can see you and is within 30 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or become blinded for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. This property can't be used again until you take a short rest while attuned to the weapon.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>97-98</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> functions as a <em>ring of spell storing</em>.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>99</td><td>You can use an action to call forth an elfshadow, provided that you don't already have one serving you. The elfshadow appears in an unoccupied space within 120 feet of you. It uses the statistics for a shadow, except it is neutral, immune to effects that turn undead, and doesn't create new shadows. You control this creature, deciding how it acts and moves. It remains until it drops to 0 hit points or you dismiss it as an action.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>100</td><td>The <em>moonblade</em> functions as a <em>vorpal sword</em>.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sentience.</b></i> A <em>moonblade</em> is a sentient neutral good weapon with an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 12. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates by transmitting emotions, sending a tingling sensation through the wielder's hand when it wants to communicate something it has sensed. It can communicate more explicitly, through visions or dreams, when the wielder is either in a trance or asleep.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Personality.</b></i> Every <em>moonblade</em> seeks the advancement of elvenkind and elven ideals. Courage, loyalty, beauty, music, and life are all part of this purpose.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon is bonded to the family line it is meant to serve. Once it has bonded with an owner who shares its ideals, its loyalty is absolute.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a <em>moonblade</em> has a flaw, it is overconfidence. Once it has decided on an owner, it believes that only that person should wield it, even if the owner falls short of elven ideals.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an elf or half-elf of neutral good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blackrazor" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_BLACKRAZOR">
		<description>
			<p>Hidden in the dungeon of White Plume Mountain, <em>Blackrazor</em> shines like a piece of night sky filled with stars. Its black scabbard is decorated with pieces of cut obsidian.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the following additional properties.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Devour Soul.</b></i> Whenever you use it to reduce a creature to 0 hit points, the sword slays the creature devours its soul, unless it is a construct or an undead. A creature whose soul has been devoured by <em>Blackrazor</em> can be restored to life only by a <i>wish</i> spell.</p> 
			<p class="indent">When it devours a soul, <em>Blackrazor</em> grants you temporary hit points equal to the slain creature's hit point maximum. These hit points fade after 24 hours. As long as these temporary hit points last and you keep <em>Blackrazor</em> in hand, you have advantage on attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks.</p> 
			<p class="indent">If you hit an undead with this weapon, you take 1d10 necrotic damage and the target regains 1d10 hit points. If this necrotic damage reduces you to 0 hit points, <em>Blackrazor</em> devours your soul.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Soul Hunter.</b></i> While you hold the weapon, you are aware of the presence of Tiny or larger creatures within 60 feet of you that aren't constructs or undead. You also can't be charmed or frightened.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Blackrazor</em> can cast the <i>haste</i> spell on you once per day. It decides when to cast the spell and maintains concentration on it so that you don't have to.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sentience.</b></i> <em>Blackrazor</em> is a sentient chaotic neutral weapon with an Intelligence of 17, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 19. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The weapon can speak, read, and understand Common, and can communicate with its wielder telepathically. Its voice is deep and echoing. While you are attuned to it, <em>Blackrazor</em> also understands every language you know.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Personality.</b></i> <em>Blackrazor</em> speaks with an imperious tone, as though accustomed to being obeyed.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The sword's purpose is to consume souls. It doesn't care whose souls it eats, including the wielder's. The sword believes that all matter and energy sprang from a void of negative energy and will one day return to it. <em>Blackrazor</em> is meant to hurry that process along.</p>
			<p class="indent">Despite its nihilism, <em>Blackrazor</em> feels a strange kinship to <em>Wave</em> and <em>Whelm</em>, two other weapons locked away under White Plume Mountain. It wants the three weapons to be united again and wielded together in combat, even though it violently disagrees with <em>Whelm</em> and finds <em>Wave</em> tedious.</p> 
			<p class="indent"><em>Blackrazor's</em> hunger for souls must be regularly fed. If the sword goes three days or more without consuming a soul, a conflict between it and its wielder occurs at the next sunset.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature of non-lawful alignment"> true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Axe of the Dwarvish Lords" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_AXE_OF_THE_DWARVISH_LORDS">
		<description>
			<p>Seeing the peril his people faced, a young dwarf prince came to believe that his people needed something to unite them. Thus, he set out to forge a weapon that would be such a symbol.</p>
			<p class="indent">Venturing deep under the mountains, deeper than any dwarf had ever delved, the young prince came to the blazing heart of a great volcano. With the aid of Moradin, the dwarven god of creation, he first crafted four great tools: the <em>Brutal Pick</em>, the <em>Earthheart Forge</em>, the <em>Anvil of Songs</em>, and the <em>Shaping Hammer</em>. With them, he forged the <em>Axe of the Dwarvish Lords</em>.</p>
			<p class="indent">Armed with the artifact, the prince returned to the dwarf clans and brought peace. His axe ended grudges and answered slights. The clans became allies, and they threw back their enemies and enjoyed an era of prosperity. This young dwarf is remembered as the First King. When he became old, he passed the weapon, which had become his badge of office, to his heir. The rightful inheritors passed the axe on for many generations.</p>
			<p class="indent">Later, in a dark era marked by treachery and wickedness, the axe was lost in a bloody civil war fomented by greed for its power and the status it bestowed. Centuries later, the dwarves still search for the axe, and many adventurers have made careers of chasing after rumors and plundering old vaults to find it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Magic Weapon.</b></i> The <em>Axe of the Dwarvish Lords</em> is a magic weapon that grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. The axe also functions as a <em>belt of dwarvenkind</em>, a <em>warven thrower</em>, and a <em>sword of sharpness</em>.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Random Properties.</b></i> The axe has the following randomly determined properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Blessings of Moradin.</b></i> If you are a dwarf attuned to the axe, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You have immunity to poison damage.</li>
				<li>The range of your darkvision increases by 60 feet.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency with artisan's tools related to blacksmithing, brewing, and stonemasonry.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Conjure Earth Elemental.</b></i> If you are holding the axe, you can use your action to cast the <i>conjure elemental</i> spell from it, summoning an earth elemental. You can't use this property again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Travel the Depths.</b></i> You can use an action to touch the axe to a fixed piece of dwarven stonework and cast the <i>teleport</i> spell from the axe. If your intended destination is underground, there is no chance of a mishap or arriving somewhere unexpected. You can't use this property again until 3 days have passed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Curse.</b></i> The axe bears a curse that affects any non-dwarf that becomes attuned to it. Even if the attunement ends, the curse remains. With each passing day, the creature's physical appearance and stature become more dwarflike. After seven days, the creature looks like a typical dwarf, but the creature neither loses its racial traits nor gains the racial traits of a dwarf. The physical changes wrought by the axe aren't considered magical in nature (and therefore can't be dispelled), but they can be undone by any effect that removes a curse, such as a <i>greater restoration</i> or <i>remove curse</i> spell.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Destroying the Axe.</b></i> The only way to destroy the axe is to melt it down in the <em>Earthheart Forge</em>, where it was created. It must remain in the burning forge for fifty years before it finally succumbs to the fire and is consumed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" requirements="ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF"/>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" requirements="ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_BREWERS_SUPPLIES" requirements="ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS" requirements="ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_MASONS_TOOLS" requirements="ID_SRD_RACE_DWARF"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Kas" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master's Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_KAS">
		<description>
			<p>When Vecna grew in power, he appointed an evil and ruthless lieutenant, Kas the Bloody Handed, to act as his bodyguard and right hand. This despicable villain served as advisor, warlord, and assassin. His successes earned him Vecna's admiration and a reward: a sword with as dark a pedigree as the man who would wield it.</p>
			<p class="indent">For a long time, Kas faithfully served the lich but as Kas's power grew, so did his hubris. His sword urged him to supplant Vecna, so that they could rule the lich's empire in Vecna's stead. Legend says Vecna's destruction came at Kas's hand, but Vecna also wrought his rebellious lieutenant's doom, leaving only Kas's sword behind. The world was made brighter thereby.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Sword of Kas</em> is a magic, sentient longsword that grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. It scores a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20, and deals an extra 2d10 slashing damage to undead.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the sword isn't bathed in blood within 1 minute of being drawn from its scabbard, its wielder must make a DC 15 Charisma saving throw. On a successful save, the wielder takes 3d6 psychic damage. On a failed save, the wielder is dominated by the sword, as if by the <i>dominate monster</i> spell, and the sword demands that it be bathed in blood. The spell effect ends when the sword's demand is met.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Random Properties.</b></i> The <em>Sword of Kas</em> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spirit of Kas.</b></i> While the sword is on your person, you add a d10 to your initiative at the start of every combat. In addition, when you use an action to attack with the sword, you can transfer some or all of its attack bonus to your Armor Class instead. The adjusted bonuses remain in effect until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spells.</b></i> While the sword is on your person, you can use an action to cast one of the following spells (save 18) from it: <i>call lightning</i>, <i>divine word</i>, or <i>finger of death</i>. Once you use the sword to cast a spell, you can't cast that spell again from it until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sentience.</b></i> The <em>Sword of Kas</em> is a sentient chaotic evil weapon with an Intelligence of 15, a Wisdom of 13, and a Charisma of 16. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and can speak, read, and understand Common</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Personality.</b></i> The sword's purpose is to bring ruin to Vecna. Killing Vecna's worshipers, destroying the lich's works, and foiling his machinations all help to fulfill this goal.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The <em>Sword of Kas</em> also seeks to destroy anyone corrupted by the <em>Eye and Hand of Vecna</em>. The sword's obsession with those artifacts eventually becomes a fixation for its wielder.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Destroying the Sword.</b></i> A creature attuned to both the <em>Eye of Vecna</em> and the <em>Hand of Vecna</em> can use the wish property of those combined artifacts to unmake the <em>Sword of Kas</em>. The creature must cast the <i>wish</i> spell and make a Charisma check contested by the Charisma check of the sword. The sword must be within 30 feet of the creature, or the spell fails. If the sword wins the contest, nothing happens, and the <i>wish</i> spell is wasted. If the sword loses the contest, it is destroyed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- ammunition -->
	<element name="Arrow of Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_ARROW_OF_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>An <em>arrow of slaying</em> is a magic weapon meant to slay a particular kind of creature. Some are more focused than others; for example, there are both <em>arrows of dragon slaying</em> and <em>arrows of blue dragon slaying</em>. If a creature belonging to the type, race, or group associated with an <em>arrow of slaying</em> takes damage from the arrow, the creature must make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once an <em>arrow of slaying</em> deals its extra damage to a creature, it becomes a nonmagical arrow.</p>
			<p class="indent">Other types of magic ammunition of this kind exist, such as <em>bolts of slaying</em> meant for a crossbow, though arrows are most common.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="type" addition="arrow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition, +1" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_1">
		<description>
			<p>You have a bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this piece of magic ammunition. The bonus is determined by the rarity of the ammunition. Once it hits a target, the ammunition is no longer magical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition, +2" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_2">
		<description>
			<p>You have a bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this piece of magic ammunition. The bonus is determined by the rarity of the ammunition. Once it hits a target, the ammunition is no longer magical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition, +3" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_3">
		<description>
			<p>You have a bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this piece of magic ammunition. The bonus is determined by the rarity of the ammunition. Once it hits a target, the ammunition is no longer magical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
