<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Elf</name>
		<description>The Elf species from the Player’s Handbook 2024.</description>
		<author url="https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/en/product/1001494/2024-player-s-handbook-digital-plus-physical-bundle">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-elf.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/players-handbook-2024/races/race-elf.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Elf" type="Race" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACE_ELF">
		<description>
			<p>Created by the god Corellon, the first elves could change their forms at will. They lost this ability when Corellon cursed them for plotting with the deity Lolth, who tried and failed to usurp Corellon’s dominion. When Lolth was cast into the Abyss, most elves renounced her and earned Corellon’s forgiveness, but that which Corellon had taken from them was lost forever.</p>
			<p class="indent">No longer able to shape-shift at will, the elves retreated to the Feywild, where their sorrow was deepened by that plane’s influence. Over time, curiosity led many of them to explore other planes of existence, including worlds in the Material Plane.</p>
			<p class="indent">Elves have pointed ears and lack facial and body hair. They live for around 750 years, and they don’t sleep but instead enter a trance when they need to rest. In that state, they remain aware of their surroundings while immersing themselves in memories and meditations.</p>
			<p class="indent">An environment subtly transforms elves after they inhabit it for a millennium or more, and it grants them certain kinds of magic. Drow, high elves, and wood elves are examples of elves who have been transformed thus.</p>
			<h5>ELF TRAITS</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled" style="text-indent:-1em; margin-left:1em; margin-bottom:5px">
				<li><strong>Creature Type:</strong> Humanoid</li>
				<li><strong>Size:</strong> Medium (about 5–6 feet tall)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed:</strong> 30 feet</li>
			</ul>
			
			<p>As an Elf, you have these special traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You have Darkvision with a range of 60 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Elven Lineage.</em></strong> You are part of a lineage that grants you supernatural abilities. Choose a lineage from the Elven Lineages table. You gain the level 1 benefit of that lineage.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn a higher-level spell, as shown on the table. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select the lineage).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fey Ancestry.</em></strong> You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Charmed condition.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Trance.</em></strong> You don’t need to sleep, and magic can’t put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</p>
			<h5>Elven Lineage</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Lineage</td><td class="col-50">Level 1</td><td>Level 3</td><td>Level 5</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Drow</td><td>The range of your Darkvision increases to 120 feet. You also know the <i>Dancing Lights</i> cantrip.</td><td><i>Faerie Fire</i></td><td><i>Darkness</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>High Elf</td><td>You know the <i>Prestidigitation</i> cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list.</td><td><i>Detect Magic</i></td><td><i>Misty Step</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>Wood Elf</td><td>Your Speed increases to 35 feet. You also know the <i>Druidcraft</i> cantrip.</td><td><i>Longstrider</i></td><td><i>Pass without Trace</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_RACE_ELF" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Option (Elf)" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_BACKGROUND_ASI" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />

			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language (Elf)" supports="Custom Race Language" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Elf)" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="2" />

			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_FEY_ANCESTRY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_KEEN_SENSES" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_TRANCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Elven Lineage" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You are part of a lineage that grants you supernatural abilities. Choose a lineage from the Elven Lineages table. You gain the level 1 benefit of that lineage.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you reach character levels 3 and 5, you learn a higher-level spell, as shown on the table. You always have that spell prepared. You can cast it once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast it in that way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast the spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait (choose the ability when you select the lineage).</p>
			<h5>Elven Lineage</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Lineage</td><td class="col-50">Level 1</td><td>Level 3</td><td>Level 5</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Drow</td><td>The range of your Darkvision increases to 120 feet. You also know the <i>Dancing Lights</i> cantrip.</td><td><i>Faerie Fire</i></td><td><i>Darkness</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>High Elf</td><td>You know the <i>Prestidigitation</i> cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list.</td><td><i>Detect Magic</i></td><td><i>Misty Step</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>Wood Elf</td><td>Your Speed increases to 35 feet. You also know the <i>Druidcraft</i> cantrip.</td><td><i>Longstrider</i></td><td><i>Pass without Trace</i></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Elven Lineage" supports="Elven Lineage 2024" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Drow" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW">
		<supports>Elven Lineage 2024</supports>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Drow typically dwell in the Underdark and have been shaped by it. Some drow individuals and societies avoid the Underdark altogether yet carry its magic. In the Eberron setting, for example, drow dwell in rainforests and cyclopean ruins on the continent of Xen’drik.</p>
			<p>As a Drow, your Darkvision increases to 120 feet and you learn the <i>Dancing Lights</i> cantrip.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you learn <i>Faerie Fire</i> spell when you reach 3rd level, and <i>Darkness</i> spell once you reach 5th level. You can cast each of these spells once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast them in this way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_RACE_DARK_ELF" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="120" bonus="base" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Spellcasting Ability (Elven Lineage)" supports="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW_INTELLIGENCE|ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW_WISDOM|ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW_CHARISMA" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (Drow)">
			<description>You know the Dancing Lights cantrip. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Dancing Lights cantrip, and you can cast the Faerie Fire spell once per Long Rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Dancing Lights cantrip, and you can cast the Faerie Fire and Darkness spells once each per Long Rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DARKNESS" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (Drow)">
			<description>You know the Dancing Lights cantrip. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Dancing Lights cantrip, and you can cast the Faerie Fire spell once per Long Rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Dancing Lights cantrip, and you can cast the Faerie Fire and Darkness spells once each per Long Rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DARKNESS" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_DROW_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (Drow)">
			<description>You know the Dancing Lights cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Dancing Lights cantrip, and you can cast the Faerie Fire spell once per Long Rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Dancing Lights cantrip, and you can cast the Faerie Fire and Darkness spells once each per Long Rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DARKNESS" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="High Elf" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF">
		<supports>Elven Lineage 2024</supports>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>High elves have been infused with the magic of crossings between the Feywild and the Material Plane. On some worlds, high elves refer to themselves by other names. For example, they call themselves sun or moon elves in the Forgotten Realms setting, Silvanesti and Qualinesti in the Dragonlance setting, and Aereni in the Eberron setting.</p>
			<p>As a High Elf, you learn the <i>Prestidigitation</i> cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you learn <i>Detect Magic</i> spell when you reach 3rd level, and <i>Misty Step</i> spell once you reach 5th level. You can cast each of these spells once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast them in this way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_RACE_HIGH_ELF" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Spellcasting Ability (Elven Lineage)" supports="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF_INTELLIGENCE|ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF_WISDOM|ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF_CHARISMA" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (High Elf)">
			<description>You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Additionally, you can cast the Detect Magic spell once per Long Rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Additionally, you can cast the Detect Magic and Misty Step spells once each per Long Rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Wizard Cantrip (High Elf)" supports="Wizard,0" default="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (High Elf)">
			<description>You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Additionally, you can cast the Detect Magic spell once per Long Rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Additionally, you can cast the Detect Magic and Misty Step spells once each per Long Rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Wizard Cantrip (High Elf)" supports="Wizard,0" default="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_HIGH_ELF_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (High Elf)">
			<description>You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Additionally, you can cast the Detect Magic spell once per Long Rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know a Wizard cantrip. Whenever you finish a Long Rest, you can replace that cantrip with a different cantrip from the Wizard spell list. Additionally, you can cast the Detect Magic and Misty Step spells once each per Long Rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Wizard Cantrip (High Elf)" supports="Wizard,0" default="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Wood Elf" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF">
		<supports>Elven Lineage 2024</supports>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Wood elves carry the magic of primeval forests within themselves. They are known by many other names, including wild elves, green elves, and forest elves. Grugach are reclusive wood elves of the Greyhawk setting, while the Kagonesti and the Tairnadal are wood elves of the Dragonlance and Eberron settings, respectively.</p>
			<p>As a Wood Elf, your Speed increases to 35 feet and you learn the <i>Druidcraft</i> cantrip.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you learn <i>Longstrider</i> spell when you reach 3rd level, and <i>Pass without Trace</i> spell once you reach 5th level. You can cast each of these spells once without a spell slot, and you regain the ability to cast them in this way when you finish a Long Rest. You can also cast these spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_RACE_WOOD_ELF" />
			<stat name="speed" value="35" bonus="base" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Spellcasting Ability (Elven Lineage)" supports="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF_INTELLIGENCE|ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF_WISDOM|ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF_CHARISMA" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Intelligence" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF_INTELLIGENCE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (Wood Elf)">
			<description>You know the Druidcraft cantrip. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Druidcraft cantrip, and you can cast the Longstrider spell once per Long Rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Druidcraft cantrip, and you can cast the Longstrider and Pass without Trace spells once each per Long Rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wisdom" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF_WISDOM">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (Wood Elf)">
			<description>You know the Druidcraft cantrip. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Druidcraft cantrip, and you can cast the Longstrider spell once per Long Rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Druidcraft cantrip, and you can cast the Longstrider and Pass without Trace spells once each per Long Rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Charisma" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE_WOOD_ELF_CHARISMA">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with Elven Lineage trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Elven Lineage (Wood Elf)">
			<description>You know the Druidcraft cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Druidcraft cantrip, and you can cast the Longstrider spell once per Long Rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast this spell using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Druidcraft cantrip, and you can cast the Longstrider and Pass without Trace spells once each per Long Rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for the spells you cast with this trait. You can also cast either of those spells using any spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Fey Ancestry" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_FEY_ANCESTRY">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_FEY_ANCESTRY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Charmed condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have Advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the Charmed condition.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Keen Senses" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_KEEN_SENSES">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_KEEN_SENSES</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency in the Insight, Perception, or Survival skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Keen Senses)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT||ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Customized Skill Proficiency (Keen Senses)" supports="Skill" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Trance" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_TRANCE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_TRANCE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You don’t need to sleep, and magic can’t put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You don’t need to sleep, and magic can’t put you to sleep. You can finish a Long Rest in 4 hours if you spend those hours in a trancelike meditation, during which you retain consciousness.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!--Racial Trait Replacement Grants-->
	<element name="Darkvision Trait Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_DARKVISION" />
	<element name="Elven Lineage Trait Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_ELVEN_LINEAGE" />
	<element name="Fey Ancestry Trait Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_FEY_ANCESTRY" />
	<element name="Keen Senses Trait Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_KEEN_SENSES" />
	<element name="Trance Trait Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_ELF_TRANCE" />

</elements>
