<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items from Keys From The Golden Vault</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/keys-from-the-golden-vault/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--Magic Items-->
	<element name="Constantori's Portrait" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_CONSTANTORIS_PORTRAIT">
		<description>
			<p>This painting by famed artist Dkesii Kwan depicts Constantori, a beautiful courtier, who was paid a staggering sum to be Dkesii's model. Whether Constantori's actual appearance matches the painting remains a subject of debate. The portrait is one of several paintings commissioned by the late Daiyani Grysthorn, a crime lord who frequently gave magical paintings as gifts to her most esteemed associates.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sentience.</b> Constantori's Portrait</i> is a sentient, lawful evil item with an Intelligence score of 14, a Wisdom score of 12, and a Charisma score of 8. It can hear within a range of 120 feet and has darkvision within a range of 60 feet, but it can't see anything behind itself.</p>
			<p class="indent">The painting can converse in Common, Draconic, and Elvish as if it were a living person, though Constantori's mouth doesn't move. Whenever conversation occurs within the portrait's auditory range, the painting eagerly gathers secrets, the names of secret tellers, significant events, or any political conversations.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Personality.</b> Constantori's Portrait</i> is demanding, condescending, and vain. It doesn't like being covered or placed out of sight, and it loudly condemns anyone who tries to remove it from its gold-leaf frame.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Wealth of Information.</b></i> The painting's primary purpose is to observe and recall conversations. Over the past few decades, <i>Constantori's Portrait</i> has quietly observed countless conversations and now possesses an unquantifiable amount of lore—everything from criminal conspiracies to secret passwords. The DM decides what the painting knows and what it doesn't.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attuned to the painting, you can take an action to telepathically contact it over any distance, provided you and the painting are on the same plane of existence. The painting can't telepathically contact you, however. Maintaining telepathic contact with the painting requires your concentration (as if concentrating on a spell).</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Guardian Portrait.</b></i> The painting's primary purpose is to observe and recall conversations. Over the past few decades, <i>Constantori's Portrait</i> has quietly observed countless conversations and now possesses an unquantifiable amount of lore—everything from criminal conspiracies to secret passwords. The DM decides what the painting knows and what it doesn't.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you are attuned to the painting, you can command it to guard its location against one or more creatures you identify as the painting's enemies. The painting performs this function until you command it to stop or until your attunement to the painting ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">The painting has 3 charges. When a creature the painting identifies as its enemy starts its turn in a space the painting can see, the painting expends 1 of its charges to cast <i>magic missile</i> (3 missiles), targeting that creature. The painting regains all expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">The painting is a Small object with AC 12, 20 hit points, and immunity to poison damage. In its gold-leaf frame, the painting weighs 15 pounds. If the painting has at least 1 hit point and is targeted by a <i>mending</i> spell, it regains 2d6 hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Shard of Xeluan" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_OF_XELUAN">
		<description>
			<p>This 1-foot-long shard of obsidian has veins of silver and gold beneath its cold surface.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Empowered Magic.</b></i> While holding the shard, you can use it as a spellcasting focus, and it gives you a +1 bonus to your spell attack rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Enhanced Strength.</b></i> Your Strength score increases by 4 while the shard is on your person. The shard can't raise your Strength score above 22.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Curse.</b></i> Attuning to this item extends its curse to you. You remain cursed until you are targeted by a <i>remove curse</i> spell or similar magic, or until the shard is reattached to Xeluan's petrified heart.</p>
			<p class="indent">The shard's curse causes misfortune to befall you. When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, roll on the Shard Misfortunes table to determine the misfortune. For as long as this misfortune lasts, no other shard misfortunes befall you.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Misfortune</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>You accidentally cut yourself with the shard and are poisoned until the next dawn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You experience a vision of an ancient calamity—a beautiful city threatened by crumbling mountains and erupting volcanoes—and are stunned until the end of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>For a few seconds, the ground shakes under you. You and each creature within 10 feet of you must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>The shard releases three glowing darts of magical force that target one random creature within 30 feet of you. If no such target exists, you become the target. Each dart hits automatically and deals 3 (1d4 + 1) force damage to the target.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Until the next dawn, Beasts with an Intelligence score of 3 or lower are hostile to you.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Nothing seems to go your way. Until the next dawn, you have disadvantage on ability checks.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">focus, spellcasting, spell attack, strength, curse, cursed</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="strength" value="4" />
			<stat name="strength:max" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shard Solitaire (Black Sapphire)" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_SOLITAIRE_BLACK_SAPPHIRE">
		<description>
			<p>This gemstone contains an unstable extradimensional rift. Its facets are ribboned with iridescent veins that seem to move of their own accord. Five types of <i>shard solitaire</i> are known to exist, each one a different type of gemstone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Rift Step.</b></i> As a bonus action, while wearing or holding the <i>shard solitaire</i>, you can teleport yourself, along with anything you're wearing or carrying, to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this property, you can tap into the unstable power of the stone's extradimensional rift to increase the teleport distance by up to 30 feet, but if you teleport more than 30 feet using Rift Step, you must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or take 3d10 force damage immediately after you teleport.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spellcasting.</b></i> The stone has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can cast one of the stone's spells by expending the requisite number of charges, requiring no material components (save DC16). The black sapphire <i>shard solitaire</i> can be used to cast the following spells: <i>banishment</i> (3 charges; the target is banished to the stone's extradimensional space for the spell's duration), <i>mirror image</i> (1 charge), <i>blight</i> (3 charges), <i>finger of death</i> (6 charges).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, teleport, spells, spellcasting, action, banishment, mirror image, blight, finger of death</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shard Solitaire (Diamond)" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_SOLITAIRE_DIAMOND">
		<description>
			<p>This gemstone contains an unstable extradimensional rift. Its facets are ribboned with iridescent veins that seem to move of their own accord. Five types of <i>shard solitaire</i> are known to exist, each one a different type of gemstone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Rift Step.</b></i> As a bonus action, while wearing or holding the <i>shard solitaire</i>, you can teleport yourself, along with anything you're wearing or carrying, to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this property, you can tap into the unstable power of the stone's extradimensional rift to increase the teleport distance by up to 30 feet, but if you teleport more than 30 feet using Rift Step, you must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or take 3d10 force damage immediately after you teleport.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spellcasting.</b></i> The stone has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can cast one of the stone's spells by expending the requisite number of charges, requiring no material components (save DC16). The diamond <i>shard solitaire</i> can be used to cast the following spells: <i>banishment</i> (3 charges; the target is banished to the stone's extradimensional space for the spell's duration), <i>mirror image</i> (1 charge), <i>ice storm</i> (3 charges), <i>simulacrum</i> (6 charges; the duplicate created by the spell has the same number of hit points as the creature it imitates).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SIMULACRUM" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, teleport, spells, spellcasting, action, banishment, mirror image, ice storm, simulacrum</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shard Solitaire (Jacinth)" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_SOLITAIRE_JACINTH">
		<description>
			<p>This gemstone contains an unstable extradimensional rift. Its facets are ribboned with iridescent veins that seem to move of their own accord. Five types of <i>shard solitaire</i> are known to exist, each one a different type of gemstone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Rift Step.</b></i> As a bonus action, while wearing or holding the <i>shard solitaire</i>, you can teleport yourself, along with anything you're wearing or carrying, to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this property, you can tap into the unstable power of the stone's extradimensional rift to increase the teleport distance by up to 30 feet, but if you teleport more than 30 feet using Rift Step, you must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or take 3d10 force damage immediately after you teleport.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spellcasting.</b></i> The stone has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can cast one of the stone's spells by expending the requisite number of charges, requiring no material components (save DC16). The jacinth <i>shard solitaire</i> can be used to cast the following spells: <i>banishment</i> (3 charges; the target is banished to the stone's extradimensional space for the spell's duration), <i>mirror image</i> (1 charge), <i>fireball</i> (2 charges), <i>fire storm</i> (6 charges).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_STORM" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, teleport, spells, spellcasting, action, banishment, mirror image, fireball, fire storm</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shard Solitaire (Rainbow Pearl)" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_SOLITAIRE_RAINBOW_PEARL">
		<description>
			<p>This gemstone contains an unstable extradimensional rift. Its facets are ribboned with iridescent veins that seem to move of their own accord. Five types of <i>shard solitaire</i> are known to exist, each one a different type of gemstone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Rift Step.</b></i> As a bonus action, while wearing or holding the <i>shard solitaire</i>, you can teleport yourself, along with anything you're wearing or carrying, to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this property, you can tap into the unstable power of the stone's extradimensional rift to increase the teleport distance by up to 30 feet, but if you teleport more than 30 feet using Rift Step, you must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or take 3d10 force damage immediately after you teleport.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spellcasting.</b></i> The stone has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can cast one of the stone's spells by expending the requisite number of charges, requiring no material components (save DC16). The rainbow pearl <i>shard solitaire</i> can be used to cast the following spells: <i>banishment</i> (3 charges; the target is banished to the stone's extradimensional space for the spell's duration), <i>mirror image</i> (1 charge), <i>prismatic spray</i> (6 charges), <i>water breathing</i> (2 charges).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_SPRAY" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, teleport, spells, spellcasting, action, banishment, mirror image, prismatic spray, water breathing</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shard Solitaire (Ruby)" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_SOLITAIRE_RUBY">
		<description>
			<p>This gemstone contains an unstable extradimensional rift. Its facets are ribboned with iridescent veins that seem to move of their own accord. Five types of <i>shard solitaire</i> are known to exist, each one a different type of gemstone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Rift Step.</b></i> As a bonus action, while wearing or holding the <i>shard solitaire</i>, you can teleport yourself, along with anything you're wearing or carrying, to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this property, you can tap into the unstable power of the stone's extradimensional rift to increase the teleport distance by up to 30 feet, but if you teleport more than 30 feet using Rift Step, you must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or take 3d10 force damage immediately after you teleport.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Spellcasting.</b></i> The stone has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can cast one of the stone's spells by expending the requisite number of charges, requiring no material components (save DC16). The ruby <i>shard solitaire</i> can be used to cast the following spells: <i>banishment</i> (3 charges; the target is banished to the stone's extradimensional space for the spell's duration), <i>mirror image</i> (1 charge), <i>fly</i> (2 charges), <i>teleport</i> (6 charges).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, teleport, spells, spellcasting, action, banishment, mirror image, fly, teleport</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Book of Vile Darkness" type="Magic Item" source="Keys From The Golden Vault" id="ID_WOTC_KFTGV_MAGIC_ITEM_BOOK_OF_VILE_DARKNESS">
		<description>
			<p>The contents of this foul manuscript of ineffable wickedness are the meat and drink of those in evil's thrall. No mortal was meant to know the secrets it contains, knowledge so horrid that to even glimpse the scrawled pages invites madness.</p>
			<p class="indent">Most believe the lich-god Vecna authored the <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em>. He recorded in its pages every diseased idea, every unhinged thought, and every example of blackest magic he came across or devised. Vecna covered every vile topic he could, making the book a gruesome catalog of all mortal wrongs.</p>
			<p class="indent">Other practitioners of evil have held the book and added their own input to its catalog of vile knowledge. Their additions are clear, for the writers of later works stitched whatever they were writing into the tome or, in some cases, made notations and additions to existing text. There are places where pages are missing, torn. or covered so completely with ink, blood, and scratches that the original text can't be divined.</p>
			<p class="indent">Nature can't abide the book's presence. Ordinary plants wither in its presence, animals are unwilling to approach it, and the book gradually destroys whatever it touches. Even stone cracks and turns to powder if the book rests on it long enough.</p>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5>VILE LORE</h5>
				<p>The <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em> touches on every evil in the cosmos. A character can use the lore the book contains to unearth terrible secrets no mortal should know. Among the contents a character might find are the following, plus whatever else you choose:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><b>Vile Apotheosis.</b> The book could hold a ritual that allows a character to become a lich or death knight.</li>
					<li><b>True Names.</b> The true names of any number of fiends might be in the book.</li>
					<li><b>Dark Magic.</b> Several spells of horrific evil of the DM's design and choosing could be in the book. Spells could impose dreadful curses, disfigure others, require human sacrifice, afflict creatures with crippling pain, spread vile plagues, and so on.</li>
				</ul>
			</div>
			<p class="indent">A creature attuned to the book must spend 80 hours reading and studying it to digest its contents and reap its benefits. The creature can then freely modify the book's contents, provided that those modifications advance evil and expand the lore already contained within.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever a non-evil creature attunes to the <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em>, that creature must make a DC 17 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the creature's alignment changes to neutral evil.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em> remains with you only as long as you strive to work evil in the world. If you fail to perform at least one evil act within the span of 10 days, or if you willingly perform a good act, the book disappears. If you die while attuned to the book, an entity of great evil claims your soul. You can't be restored to life by any means while your soul remains imprisoned.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Circle of Death.</b></i> While attuned to the book, you can cast <i>circle of death</i> (save DC 20) from it as an action. After you cast the spell, roll a d6. On a roll of 1-5, you can't use this property again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Condition Immunities.</b></i> While attuned to the book, you can't be charmed or frightened.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Evil Presence.</b></i> The book houses an evil spirit that is hostile toward you. When you become attuned to the book, the spirit tries to leave the book and enter your body. If you fail a DC 20 Charisma saving throw, it succeeds, and you become an NPC under the DM's control until the intruding spirit is banished using magic such as the dispel evil and good spell. The banished spirit returns to the book.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Adjusted Ability Scores.</b></i> After you spend the requisite amount of time reading and studying the book, one ability score of your choice increases by 2, to a maximum of 24. Another ability score of your choice decreases by 2, to a minimum of 3. The book can't adjust your ability scores again.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Mark of Darkness.</b></i> After you spend the requisite amount of time reading and studying the book, you acquire a physical disfigurement as a hideous sign of your devotion to vile darkness. An evil rune might appear on your face, your eyes might become glossy black, or horns might sprout from your forehead. Or you might become wizened and hideous, lose all facial features, gain a forked tongue, or some other feature the DM chooses. The mark of darkness grants you advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to interact with evil creatures and Charisma (Intimidation) checks made to interact with non-evil creatures.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Command Evil.</b></i> While you are attuned to the book and holding it, you can use an action to cast the <em>dominate monster</em> spell on an evil target (save DC 18). You can't use this property again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Dark Lore.</b></i> You can reference the <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em> whenever you make an Intelligence check to recall information about some aspect of evil, such as lore about demons. When you do so, double your proficiency bonus on that check.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Dark Speech.</b></i> While you carry the <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em> and are attuned to it, you can use an action to recite word from its pages in a foul language known as Dark Speech. Each time you do so, you take 1d12 psychic damage, and each non-evil creature within 15 feet of you takes 3d6 psychic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Destroying the Book.</b></i> The <em>Book of Vile Darkness</em> allows pages to be torn from it, but any evil lore contained on those pages finds its way back into the book eventually, usually when a new author adds pages to the tome.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a solar tears the book in two, the book is destroyed for 1d100 years, after which it reforms in some dark corner of the multiverse.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature attuned to the book for one hundred years can unearth a phrase hidden in the original text that, when translated to Celestial and spoken aloud, destroys both the speaker and the book in a blinding flash of radiance. However, as long as evil exists in the multiverse, the book reforms 1d10 × 100 years later.</p>
			<p class="indent">If all evil in the multiverse is wiped out, the book turns to dust and is forever destroyed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_DEATH" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">vecna, evil, circle of death, immunity, charmed, frightened, ability score, dominate monster, check, charisma, persuasion, intimidation, intelligence</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Book of Vile Darkness)" supports="Book of Vile Darkness Ability Score Increase" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Decrease (Book of Vile Darkness)" supports="Book of Vile Darkness Ability Score Decrease" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
</elements>
