<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Arcanum Worlds Presents: Chains of Asmodeus</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/457996/Chains-of-Asmodeus">Chains of Asmodeus</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="chains-of-asmodeus.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/collaborations/misc/chains-of-asmodeus.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Chains of Asmodeus" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_CHAINS_OF_ASMODEUS">
		<description>
			<h5 style="margin-top:-1em">Arcanum Worlds Presents: Chains of Asmodeus</h5>
			<p>Chains of Asmodeus is a 286-page source book and adventure for the Nine Hells written by legendary game designer James Ohlen (<i>Baldur's Gate, Baldur's Gate II, Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic, Dragon Age: Origins</i>) and award-winning author Adrian Tchaikovsky (<i>Children of Time, The Tiger and the Wolf, The Doors of Eden</i>). This book is beautifully illustrated with haunting art from Sergei Sarichev, Sergey Musin, Julian Calle, Sebastion Kowoll, Paul Adams, Luis Lasahido, and the Aaron Sims Company.</p>
			<p>Travel through the <b>Nine Hells</b> to save your soul in this tome that includes:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>50+ High Challenge Monsters</li>
				<li>Stat Blocks for Asmodeus, Lord of the Nine, and all major Archdevils</li>
				<li>20+ Infernal Magic Items</li>
				<li>New Item Corruption Mechanic</li>
				<li>Details on all Layers of the Nine Hells, with Beautifully Illustrated Maps created by John Stevenson</li>
				<li>A Fiendish Adventure for Levels 11-20</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">COA</set>
			<set name="url">https://www.dmsguild.com/product/457996/Chains-of-Asmodeus</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/collaborations/misc/CoA.jpg</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Arcanum Worlds, Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20231030</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--Magic Items-->

	<element name="Amulet of Appearance" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_APPEARANCE">
		<description>
			<p>Your armor, weapons, and other equipment always shine as if just polished. Even if you're wounded, your wounds do not appear to others. You're immune to the frightened and poisoned conditions, as these would otherwise ruin your elegant appearance. However, whenever you would otherwise have been affected by one of these conditions, a random non-evil Humanoid on the Material Plane whom you have previously met gets the condition instead. You know this.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">immunity, frightened, poisoned</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Amulet of Betrayal" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_BETRAYAL">
		<description>
			<p>You can use a bonus action to move one of the following conditions from yourself to an ally within 60 feet of you: blinded, deafened, frightened, poisoned, stunned, exhaustion. When transferring exhaustion, move all your exhaustion levels. If the chosen ally is immune to a transferred condition, the transfer fails.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Amulet of Duplicity" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_DUPLICITY">
		<description>
			<p>When you die, you're transported to an extradimensional space where you're stabilized at 0 hit points and kept in that state. The amulet creates a perfect copy of your corpse and places it where you were just before you died, but without any of your worn or carried items. After 24 hours, you regain 1 hit point and are returned to the location of your near-death. Everything about you is the same, except that your facial features are entirely different from before. Only a <em>wish</em> spell can restore your true identity.</p>
			<p class="indent">Until then, you have disadvantage on any Charisma (Persuasion) checks to attempt to reveal who you really are.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> An <em>identify</em> spell or similar reveals only that the amulet can prevent death. Once you attune to the amulet, you can't describe its ability to any other creature, and if unattuned, you immediately forget what the amulet does. A <em>remove curse</em> spell reveals the details of the curse but does not remove it from the amulet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Bracers of Asmodeus" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_BRACERS_OF_ASMODEUS">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +2 bonus to AC while wearing these bracers, if you do not wear armor or use a shield at the same time.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> While attuned to the bracers, you become obsessed with plotting, scheming, and manipulation. You always barter for better deals, often using secrets or leveraging other offers in the process. If you ever decline an opportunity to better yourself financially at another's expense, you immediately take 3d10 necrotic damage. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to end attunement to this item.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">armor, necrotic</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">arms</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="2" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Canian Fork" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_CANIAN_FORK">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, you can make one additional attack with it as a bonus action on each of your turns.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> You're unwilling to part with this weapon while attuned to it. You're also vulnerable to radiant damage and each time you receive magical healing, you must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw.</p>
			<p class="indent">On a failed save, the healing has no effect. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to end attunement to this item.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">trident, saving throw</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="trident">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Trident</set>
			<set name="name-format">Canian Fork</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Condensed Order" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_CONDENSED_ORDER">
		<description>
			<p><em>Condensed Order</em> is a silvery powder that can be extracted from those of a lawful persuasion. Devils bound for the warfronts of Avernus take flasks and snuff boxes of the stuff to fortify themselves against exposure to the raw chaos of demons. Taking the substance requires an action and makes you immune to the flesh warping feature of demonic ichor. It also gives you advantage on saving throws against any effect from a demonic source. These benefits last for 8 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">advantage</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Demonbone Polearm" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_DEMONBONE_POLEARM">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, when you're damaged by a creature in reach, you may use your reaction to make one melee attack against it with this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> You're unwilling to part with this weapon while attuned to it. While attuned, you have disadvantage on attack rolls with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever a hostile creature damages you, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or go berserk. While berserk, you must use your action on each of your turns to attack the creature nearest to you with the weapon. If you can make extra attacks as part of the Attack action, you use those extra attacks, moving to attack the next nearest creature after you fell your current target. If you have multiple possible targets, you attack one at random.</p>
			<p class="indent">You're berserk until you start your turn with no creatures within 60 feet of you that you can see or hear. Alternatively, an ally can use an action to make a DC 15 Charisma (Persuasion) check and if successful, you're no longer berserk. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to end attunement to this item.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">polearm, reaction</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="polearm">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_POLEARMS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Demonbone {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Gauntlets of Rage" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_GAUNTLETS_OF_RAGE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain the power of never-ending fury. After you make a melee weapon attack, you automatically enter a special fury for 1 minute. While furious, you can't cast spells, can't verbally communicate, and are immune to the charmed and frightened conditions. Each time you deal damage, you regain 2d8 hit points and may immediately remove a condition you currently suffer from or end this fury. Additionally, while in this fury, you may spend a spell slot before you make a melee attack. Doing so causes the attack to deal an extra 3 (1d6) necrotic damage per level of spell slot expended, if the attack hits. Once used you may not use this fury again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">necrotic, damage</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a bard, sorcerer, warlock, or wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Infernal Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_INFERNAL_AMULET">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this amulet, you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your spells, and it grants a +2 bonus to your spell save DC and spell attack bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> You're unwilling to part with this amulet while attuned to it and you wear it always. While wearing the amulet you have disadvantage on Strength saving throws and Strength checks. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to remove the item and end attunement.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spellcasting focus</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="2" />
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Infernal Plate Armor" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_INFERNAL_PLATE_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this armor, you gain a +2 bonus to AC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> Once you wear this armor, and are attuned to it, you can't remove it. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to end the attunement and finally doff it. While wearing the armor, you're vulnerable to the following damage types: force, lightning, psychic, radiant, and thunder.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">plate, vulnerability</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="armor">Plate</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_VULNERABILITY_FORCE" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_VULNERABILITY_LIGHTNING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_VULNERABILITY_PSYCHIC" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_VULNERABILITY_RADIANT" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_VULNERABILITY_THUNDER" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Knife of Stolen Resistance" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_KNIFE_OF_STOLEN_RESISTANCE">
		<description>
			<p>Using an action, you carve a single infernal rune into the flesh of an unconscious Beast, Celestial, Dragon, Fey, or Giant with this knife. Over the next 10 minutes the creature dies an agonizing death that can't be prevented short of the <em>Wish</em> spell. If the creature has any resistances or immunities, you gain those resistances and immunities until the creature dies or a <em>Wish</em> spell is used to save the creature. The knife's power can't be used again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dagger</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ring of Collecting" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_COLLECTING">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this ring you can use it to cast the <em>Leomund's Tiny Hut</em> spell as an action. Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn. Additionally, as a bonus action, you can use the ring to disintegrate any nonmagical piece of art (drawing, painting, or sculpture) within 60 feet that is no larger than Medium-sized. That art now appears inside the tiny hut, for you to appreciate whenever you desire. If you try to remove this art from the tiny hut, it vanishes forever. You can steadily improve this space, but only be denying such beauty to the rest of the world. For every 1,000 gp of art acquired, the tiny hut increases in size by adding another foot to its radius and lasts one additional hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ring of the Copycat" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_THE_COPYCAT">
		<description>
			<p>You gain the ability to channel energy from allies to cast spells, even if you normally can't. When an ally within 60 feet of you casts a spell that you normally can't cast and that requires 10 gp or fewer in material components, you may use a reaction to cast that spell. When cast in this way, the spell is cast using your ally's spellcasting ability, spell save DC, and spell attack bonus, as needed. You decide this cloned spell's target, as specified in the spell's description, and the spell originates from you. After you use this ability, your ally can't cast this spell again until they finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ring of Treachery" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_TREACHERY">
		<description>
			<p>This ring has 3 charges. While wearing this ring, when you're damaged, you may use a reaction to expend a charge and transfer that damage to a random creature (which could include an ally) within 60 feet. All charges are restored when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">damage</set>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Sage's Mirror" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_SAGES_MIRROR">
		<description>
			<p>This item has 3 charges and regains all charges at dusk. You can use an action and expend 1 of the mirror's charges to cast one of the following spells:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><em>Find the Path</em></li>
				<li><em>Legend Lore</em></li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">With each use, it is apparent that the information gleaned from the mirror comes from a chamber in the Nine Hells where sages and scholars are tortured for the answers to each question.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Skull of Selfish Knowledge" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_SKULL_OF_SELFISH_KNOWLEDGE">
		<description>
			<p>You may use an action to make the magical skull devour a nonmagical book, map, or scroll. Once devoured the learning is forever available to you, but you can never write the information down or communicate it to others. It is for you alone.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Soul Coin" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_SOUL_COIN">
		<description>
			<p><em>Soul Coins</em> are about 5 inches across and about an inch thick, minted from infernal iron. Each coin weighs one-third of a pound and is inscribed with Infernal writing and a spell that magically binds a single soul to the coin. Because each Soul Coin has a unique soul trapped within it, each has a story. A creature might have been imprisoned as a result of defaulting on a deal, while another might be the victim of a night hag's curse.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Carrying Soul Coins.</em></strong> To hold a <em>Soul Coin</em> is to feel the soul bound within it—overcome with rage or fraught with despair.</p>
			<p class="indent">An evil creature can carry as many <em>Soul Coins</em> as it wishes (up to its maximum weight allowance). A non-evil creature can carry a number of <em>Soul Coins</em> equal to or less than its Constitution modifier without penalty. A non-evil creature carrying a number of <em>Soul Coins</em> greater than its Constitution modifier has disadvantage on its attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Using a Soul Coin.</em></strong> A <em>Soul Coin</em> has 3 charges. A creature carrying the coin can use its action to expend 1 charge from a Soul Coin and use it to do one of the following:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Drain Life.</em></strong> You siphon away some of the soul's essence and gain 1d10 temporary hit points.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Query.</em></strong> You telepathically ask the soul a question and receive a brief telepathic response, which you can understand. The soul knows only what it knew in life, but it must answer you truthfully and to the best of its ability. The answer is no more than a sentence or two and might be cryptic.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Freeing a Soul.</em></strong> Casting a spell that removes a curse on a <em>Soul Coin</em> frees the soul trapped within it, as does expending all of the coin's charges. The coin itself rusts from within and is destroyed once the soul is released. A freed soul travels to the realm of the god it served, or the outer plane most closely tied to its alignment (DM's choice). The souls of lawful evil creatures released from <em>Soul Coins</em> typically emerge from the River Styx as lemure devils.</p>
			<p class="indent">A soul can also be freed by destroying the coin that contains it. A <em>Soul Coin</em> has AC 19, 1 hit point for each charge it has remaining, and immunity to all damage except that which is dealt by an infernal warship's furnace.</p>
			<p class="indent">Freeing a soul from a <em>Soul Coin</em> is considered a good act, even if the soul belongs to an evil creature.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hellish Currency.</em></strong> <em>Soul Coins</em> are a currency of the Nine Hells and are highly valued by devils. The coins are used among the infernal hierarchy to barter for favors, bribe the unwilling, and reward the faithful for services rendered.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Soul Coins</em> are created by Mammon and his greater devils on Minauros, the third layer of the Nine Hells, in a vast chamber where the captured souls of evil mortals are bound into the coins. These coins are then distributed throughout the Nine Hells to be used for goods and services, infernal deals, dark bargains, and bribes.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Stygian Spear" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_STYGIAN_SPEAR">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you throw it, it deals one extra die of damage on a hit. After you throw it and it hits or misses, it flies back to your hand immediately.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> You're unwilling to part with this weapon while attuned to it. In addition, you have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you roll a 1 on an attack roll using this weapon, your target changes to your closest ally.</p>
			<p class="indent">If there are multiple allies, randomly determine which is the target. Make a new attack roll with advantage against your ally. If the attack hits, in addition to the standard damage you deal an extra 2d6 poison damage. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to end attunement to this item.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear, javelin</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear or javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear||Javelin</set>
			<set name="name-format">Stygian Spear</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Sword of Retribution" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_RETRIBUTION">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this sword. Hit points lost to this weapon's damage can be regained only through a short or long rest, rather than by regeneration, magic, or any other means.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> You're unwilling to part with this weapon while attuned to it. While attuned to this weapon, you also have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">The vengeful spirit possessing the sword shares its history and lust for vengeance with the wielder. After each successful long rest, you experience nightmares of the spirit's past, culminating in its death. When you wake, you must make a DC 11 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, you only gain the benefits of a short rest. Only the <em>Remove Curse</em> spell allows you to end attunement to this item.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Corrupting.</em></strong> This item corrupts. See the "Infernal Item Corruption" section.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Retribution</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Vial of Greed" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_VIAL_OF_GREED">
		<description>
			<p>This small glass vial can stockpile resources for use in the future. Once stored, resources last for 1 century before vanishing. As an action you make the vial store any number of the following resources, which are magically consumed and converted into a violet-colored liquid:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Up to 31 days of food and/or drink. The flavors are lost, instead becoming tasteless.</li>
				<li>Up to 7 days of alcohol. The flavors are lost, instead becoming tasteless.</li>
				<li>Up to 5 magic scrolls that affect a single creature. The target of the spell is you, and if the spell requires concentration, you can concentrate.</li>
				<li>Up to 5 magic potions. No more than 2 duplicate potions can be stored at a time.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">You may have more than one kind of resource in the vial, up to the limits expressed above. You can use a bonus action to consume one day of food (or alcohol) or activate one scroll or magic potion. If activating a magic scroll, the effects of that scroll must end before you can activate another scroll from the <em>Vial of Greed</em>.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Weapon of Agonizing Paralysis" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_OF_AGONIZING_PARALYSIS">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When this weapon reduces a creature to 0 hit points, the creature doesn't die. Instead, infernal runes appear as if carved into their flesh and they're healed to 1 hit point. They now have the paralyzed condition until the condition is removed by a <em>Lesser Restoration</em> spell or similar magic. When the condition is removed, the runes disappear. At the start of each of their turns while they're paralyzed, the creature suffers immense pain and gains a level of exhaustion.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any melee">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Agonizing Paralysis</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--Infernal Artifacts-->

	<element name="Accounting and Valuation of All Things" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_ACCOUNTING_AND_VALUATION_OF_ALL_THINGS">
		<description>
			<p>The <em>Accounting and Valuation of All Things</em> is bound in gold leaf, with pages of silver and text of blood.</p>
			<p class="indent">This is a magic tome that functions as a spellbook and arcane focus. You have a +3 bonus to your spell attack and spell save DC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>Accounting and Valuation of All Things</em> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Soul Trade.</em></strong> One section of the book is dedicated to negotiating and valuing mortal souls. When the book is opened within 10 feet of a creature with a soul, that creature must make a DC 22 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the tome analyzes their greatest desires and calculates exactly what they would need to give up their soul. That information is then displayed within the tome, such that the user can offer a trade to acquire a soul. Creatures that succeed on the saving throw simply show up as a question mark in the book's pages and are immune to further valuations.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mammon's Tax.</em></strong> When the <em>Accounting and Valuation of All Things</em> is used as a spellbook, it maintains a unique ability to forcibly acquire souls. Any creature killed by a spell transcribed within the book has their soul ripped from their body and sent to Minauros. This process renders the subject immune to all forms of resurrection aside from <em>True Resurrection</em>. In payment for their soul, Mammon drops gold equal to (20 × CR) or (2 × Level) on their corpse.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Negotiation Tactics.</em></strong> The tome is capable of providing some assistance to all negotiations, not just those made for souls. You gain a passive +5 to Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to barter. Additionally, as an action, you can surrender your consciousness to the tome, allowing it to take over. For 1 minute, the <em>Accounting and Valuation of All Things</em> speaks for you, using a +12 Charisma (Persuasion) skill and gaining advantage on your rolls. Using the book in this manner has a corrupting influence, and each use compels you to become increasingly greedy, vain, and evil—much like its original owner, Mammon. When the duration ends, if your alignment is non-evil, you suffer 6d6 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Transcribed Spells.</em></strong> The spellbook section of the <em>Accounting and Valuation of All Things</em> comes with some spells already recorded. For each spell level, roll (1d4 - 1). The DM will determine the necessary spells of each level that already exist within the tome. If you copy spells from the tome to your own spellbook, the cost in gold is doubled. On the opposite end, copying spells from your spellbook to the tome only costs half the gold it normally would.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Tome.</em></strong> Destroying the <em>Accounting and Valuation of All Things</em> can be done in two ways. The first option is a simple bribe to Mammon to have him destroy the tome. An offering of 99,999 gp must be made, at midnight, by opening the book and placing the gold inside. If Mammon accepts the offering, the gold melts around the book, then both vanish.</p>
			<p class="indent">The second route, in case Mammon is unavailable or unwilling, is to incinerate the book. To accomplish this task, a pot of platinum (valued at no less than 99,999 gp) must be melted, enough to fully submerge the book. Once the platinum is prepared, dropping the tome into the molten solution melts the tome. The process completely destroys the tome, as well as the platinum.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spellbook, spellcasting focus</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="3" />
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Amulet of the Inferno" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_THE_INFERNO">
		<description>
			<p>When Fierna was born, petitioners and devils from all over came to celebrate her birth. Many brought gifts and treasures, including a powerful infernal warlock. Recognizing the strength and inner fire of Fierna, the warlock gifted her with the <em>Amulet of the Inferno</em>, and it has been around her neck ever since.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Amulet of the Inferno</em> is a magic necklace that grants a +3 bonus to spell save DC and spell attack bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>Amulet of the Inferno</em> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>3 major beneficial properties</li>
				<li>2 major detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Infernal Fire.</em></strong> While worn, the amulet augments any magical flames created by you, transforming normal fire into Hellfire. Hellfire ignores resistances and immunities to fire damage and deals double damage to creatures vulnerable to either fire or necrotic damage. It is also capable of melting stone, as well as igniting flammable objects.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Raging Inferno.</em></strong> While attuned to the <em>Amulet of the Inferno</em>, you may use a bonus action to cast <em>Fire Bolt</em> or <em>Produce Flame</em>. The cantrips scale based on your total character level and use Intelligence as a spellcasting modifier if you're normally incapable of casting spells.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Everburning.</em></strong> The <em>Amulet of the Inferno</em> grants resistance to cold damage and the ability to breathe underwater. Any magical flames you conjure are similarly augmented: they can be used underwater, can't be extinguished through any means, and can exude any temperature. While the casting of a fire spell can still be interrupted with <em>Counterspell</em>, once the spell has been cast, any lingering flames can't be removed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Amulet.</em></strong> The only creature capable of destroying the amulet is the warlock that created it. Nobody living knows the warlock's identity, making destroying the amulet almost impossible.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="3" />
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Ranseur of Torture" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_RANSEUR_OF_TORTURE">
		<description>
			<p>Forged of infernal iron and Hellfire through the help of Dispater, the <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> has been Belial's weapon of choice since he first became an archdevil.</p>
			<p class="indent">It is so directly tied to him that one of his worshipped symbols is a two-pronged fork. The weapon never leaves his side, and he is a master at wielding it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> is a magic pike. You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, and it does 2d10 piercing damage instead of its regular damage. When you hit a good aligned creature with it, that creature takes an extra 1d10 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Wounding.</em></strong> Damage dealt by the <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> is particularly dangerous, as it can only be restored through magical means. Resting, food, and medicine won't restore hit points removed by the pike. If the damage goes untreated for 7 days, the missing hit points are permanently removed, and can be recovered only through casting a <em>Regenerate</em> or <em>Wish</em> spell on the victim.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Excution.</em></strong> If a creature with less than its full hit points is hit by this pike, the <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> deals 1d10 additional piercing damage. If a creature is killed by the pike, their soul is sent to Phlegethos and can be restored only through casting a <em>Wish</em> spell on the victim.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Staggered.</em></strong> Each time a creature takes damage from the <em>Ranseur of Torture</em>, they must make a Constitution save, with a DC equaling the damage they took. On a failed save, their movement speed is reduced by 5 feet until the end of their next turn. This penalty stacks, though movement speed can't be reduced below 0.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Interrupting.</em></strong> Spellcasters damaged by the <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> have disadvantage on Constitution checks made to maintain concentration until the damage is healed. If a creature is concentrating on a spell when damaged by the ranseur, their concentration is immediately ended.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Ranseur.</em></strong> Only through the written consent of both Dispater and Belial can the <em>Ranseur of Torture</em> be destroyed. If either or both of the archdevils are dead, then the new archdevil to take their mantle must give permission in their stead. The two writs must be wrapped around each of the prongs of the weapon, then the weapon must be tossed into the Pit of Flame. If performed successfully, the Hellfire briefly burns a different hue.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire, necrotic, saving throw</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="pike">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Pike</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ruby Rod of Asmodeus" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_RUBY_ROD_OF_ASMODEUS">
		<description>
			<p>Asmodeus's Ruby Rod is said to have been constructed from a shard of pure evil, a ruby soaked in the blood of the innocents, the drool from a draconic deity, and the tears of 777 angels. It is a magic rod that functions as a morningstar and you have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. All damage dealt with it is converted to necrotic, and when you hit a good aligned creature, that creature takes an extra 2d12 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Ruby Rod of Asmodeus</em> has 66 charges and regains 6d6 charges each nightfall. Asmodeus is always capable of perceiving through the rod and knows the exact location of any creature attuned to it. If a creature uses the special abilities of the rod without Asmodeus's permission, they take 2d12 necrotic damage each use, doubled if they're good aligned. This damage ignores resistances and immunities, and if it kills the user, Asmodeus permanently claims their soul.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>Ruby Rod of Asmodeus</em> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">Asmodeus is immune to the detrimental properties of the weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bow to the King.</em></strong> You may use an action to expend 33 charges to use the rod to force all creatures within a 150-foot-radius to bow to you. A creature must succeed on a DC 21 Charisma saving throw or be forced to kneel for up to 1 hour. Creatures immune to the charmed condition have advantage on their save. Each time a kneeling creature takes damage, they may repeat the save, ending the effect on a success. The effect also ends early for kneeling creatures if they're touched by the Ruby Rod.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Acid, Cold, and Lightning.</em></strong> At a cost of 9 charges each use, you may use an action to trigger one of the following effects:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You project acid in a 60-foot line that is 5 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d8 acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</li>
				<li>You project an icy blast in a 60-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 19 Constitution saving throw, taking 12d8 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</li>
				<li>You shoot lightning in a 90-foot line that is 5 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 19 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d10 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Reactions.</em></strong> As a reaction to suffering a detrimental effect, you may cast Lesser Restoration (expending 3 charges) or Greater Restoration (expending 12 charges.)</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, if you're the sole target of a spell, you may use a reaction to attempt to use the rod to absorb the spell and cancel its effect. You roll 1d20 + 2, and if the result is higher than the spell level + 10, the spell is absorbed into the rod. The rod regains charges equal to the spell level it absorbed. If the absorbed charges go over the maximum of 66 charges, it overloads, dealing 1d6 necrotic damage per charge to you and expending all charges.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Rod.</em></strong> While Asmodeus lives, the <em>Ruby Rod of Asmodeus</em> can't be destroyed, and if attempted it simply returns to Asmodeus. If he were defeated, the rod could be destroyed by bringing it to the Abyss from whence it was created, then performing a ritual known only to Asmodeus.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">acid, cold, lightning, necrotic, saving throw, damage, spell, reaction</set>
			<set name="category">Rods</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Rod</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="weapon">Morningstar</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="charges">66</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Scourge of Shadow" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_SCOURGE_OF_SHADOW">
		<description>
			<p>Said to be a gift to Glasya from Asmodeus, the <em>Scourge of Shadow</em> is a multi-headed whip constructed from infernal iron. The scourge is nigh-in- destructible, and Glasya carries it with her wherever she goes. When she wields the whip in battle, it shrouds her in an aura of shadow.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Scourge of Shadow</em> is a magic whip. You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, and it does 3d4 slashing damage instead of its regular damage. When you hit a good aligned creature with it, that creatures takes an extra 4d4 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever an unattuned creature attacks with the weapon, it deals 2d4 necrotic damage, ignoring resistances and immunities, to them, but otherwise functions normally.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>Scourge of Shadow</em> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Keen.</em></strong> The whip scores a critical on a roll of 18, 19, or 20. When it scores a critical, its damage dice are upgraded to 3d6 instead of 3d4 for the duration of the attack. If attacking a good aligned creature, or attacking with the weapon unattuned, the necrotic damage dice are also increased to a d6 instead of a d4.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fast Reflexes.</em></strong> While attuned to the <em>Scourge of Shadow</em>, you gain advantage on initiative rolls, and you add your Charisma and Dexterity modifiers to the roll. You may use either your Strength, Dexterity, or Charisma modifier for the attack and damage rolls (the same modifier must be used for both attack and damage).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Veil of Shadow.</em></strong> You're protected by a field of shadow that makes you resistant to radiant and necrotic damage. While in dim light or darkness you gain blindsight out to 60 feet and Dexterity (Stealth) checks are made with advantage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Scourge.</em></strong> Though the process is known only to Glasya and Asmodeus, the <em>Scourge of Shadow</em> can be destroyed. It must be taken to the Pit of Fire in Phlegethos. The scourge, along with the body of an archdevil, must be thrown into the Hellfire together. As they hit the flames, a spell of <em>Darkness</em> must be cast at 9th level on the scourge. If each part of the ritual is performed correctly, the whip disintegrates within the Hellfire.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">necrotic, saving throw, resistance</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
			<stat name="initiative" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="True-Ice Shards" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_TRUE_ICE_SHARDS_RAPIER">
		<description>
			<p>Crafted from the very glacier in which he was imprisoned, the <em>True-Ice Shards</em> are a rapier and parrying dagger (main gauche) pair used by Levistus. They exemplify his time spent in the glacier, augmenting telepathy, divination, and defense. Due to his control over ice, Levistus can conjure the True-Ice Shards from anywhere, including if they were destroyed.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with the magical rapier and it does 1d8 cold damage instead of its regular damage. When using the magic dagger, you gain a +3 bonus to your AC, as long as it is used as your offhand weapon, and it does 1d6 cold damage instead of its regular damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Because Levistus conjures the True-Ice Shards at will, he often rewards a copy of the artifact to his most loyal followers. The copies are identical to the original with one exception: Levistus can destroy or retrieve a copy at any time.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>True-Ice Shards</em> have the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 major beneficial properties</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sub-Zero.</em></strong> Cold damage dealt with the shards ignores resistances and immunities. Creatures vulnerable to cold damage take triple damage from the <em>True-Ice Shards</em>, rather than double.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, the staff has 10 charges. When you make an attack, you may spend 1 or more charges. For each charge spent, you deal an additional 2 fire damage on a successful attack. Charges are still consumed if the attack misses. The staff regains all charges each day at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">After you damage a creature with the shards, you may use a bonus action to force the creature to make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature that took the damage becomes vulnerable to cold damage for 24 hours. Once you use this feature, you may not use it again until after you have finished a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Best Defense.</em></strong> As a reaction to being attacked, you use the rapier to increase your defense, adding +3 to your AC until the end of your next turn. If you attack with the rapier before the end of your next turn, you do not have its +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mental Command.</em></strong> While attuned to the <em>True-Ice Shards</em>, you can use an action to cast the <em>Detect Thoughts</em> spell (save DC 20), targeting any creature you have previously met. If the targeted creature is on a different plane of existence, the spell fails.</p>
			<p class="indent">As long as you maintain concentration, you can use a bonus action to send a telepathic message to the focused creature. It can reply—using a bonus action to do so—as long as the focus and concentration continue.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Omniscient.</em></strong> You can use the True-Ice Shards to cast a variety of divination spells. <em>Locate Animals or Plants</em>, <em>Locate Creature</em>, and <em>Locate Object</em> may be cast at will, and don't have a maximum range. Other limitations of the spells still apply, and they can't detect subjects on other planes of existence.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may cast <em>Scrying</em> (with a spell save DC of 20) and Find the Path. Once either spell is cast, you must finish a long rest before casting either of them again.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Shards.</em></strong> While Levistus still lives, destroying the <em>True-Ice Shards</em> serves little purpose, as he is capable of recreating them at will. That aside, the shards can be destroyed when subjected to a sufficient source of heat. A few such sources include the inside of an active volcano, a continuous source of Hellfire, or a powerful fire spell cast at 9th level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cold, saving throw, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rapier and dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Rapier</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="True-Ice Shards" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_TRUE_ICE_SHARDS_DAGGER">
		<description>
			<p>Crafted from the very glacier in which he was imprisoned, the <em>True-Ice Shards</em> are a rapier and parrying dagger (main gauche) pair used by Levistus. They exemplify his time spent in the glacier, augmenting telepathy, divination, and defense. Due to his control over ice, Levistus can conjure the True-Ice Shards from anywhere, including if they were destroyed.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with the magical rapier and it does 1d8 cold damage instead of its regular damage. When using the magic dagger, you gain a +3 bonus to your AC, as long as it is used as your offhand weapon, and it does 1d6 cold damage instead of its regular damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Because Levistus conjures the True-Ice Shards at will, he often rewards a copy of the artifact to his most loyal followers. The copies are identical to the original with one exception: Levistus can destroy or retrieve a copy at any time.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <em>True-Ice Shards</em> have the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 major beneficial properties</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sub-Zero.</em></strong> Cold damage dealt with the shards ignores resistances and immunities. Creatures vulnerable to cold damage take triple damage from the <em>True-Ice Shards</em>, rather than double.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, the staff has 10 charges. When you make an attack, you may spend 1 or more charges. For each charge spent, you deal an additional 2 fire damage on a successful attack. Charges are still consumed if the attack misses. The staff regains all charges each day at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">After you damage a creature with the shards, you may use a bonus action to force the creature to make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature that took the damage becomes vulnerable to cold damage for 24 hours. Once you use this feature, you may not use it again until after you have finished a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Best Defense.</em></strong> As a reaction to being attacked, you use the rapier to increase your defense, adding +3 to your AC until the end of your next turn. If you attack with the rapier before the end of your next turn, you do not have its +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mental Command.</em></strong> While attuned to the <em>True-Ice Shards</em>, you can use an action to cast the <em>Detect Thoughts</em> spell (save DC 20), targeting any creature you have previously met. If the targeted creature is on a different plane of existence, the spell fails.</p>
			<p class="indent">As long as you maintain concentration, you can use a bonus action to send a telepathic message to the focused creature. It can reply—using a bonus action to do so—as long as the focus and concentration continue.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Omniscient.</em></strong> You can use the True-Ice Shards to cast a variety of divination spells. <em>Locate Animals or Plants</em>, <em>Locate Creature</em>, and <em>Locate Object</em> may be cast at will, and don't have a maximum range. Other limitations of the spells still apply, and they can't detect subjects on other planes of existence.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may cast <em>Scrying</em> (with a spell save DC of 20) and Find the Path. Once either spell is cast, you must finish a long rest before casting either of them again.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Shards.</em></strong> While Levistus still lives, destroying the <em>True-Ice Shards</em> serves little purpose, as he is capable of recreating them at will. That aside, the shards can be destroyed when subjected to a sufficient source of heat. A few such sources include the inside of an active volcano, a continuous source of Hellfire, or a powerful fire spell cast at 9th level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cold, saving throw, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rapier and dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Wrought-Iron Tower" type="Magic Item" source="Chains of Asmodeus" id="ID_WOTC_COA_MAGIC_ITEM_WROUGHT_IRON_TOWER">
		<description>
			<p>Constructed from the same materials as his tower, Dispater's <em>Wrought-Iron Tower</em> is a powerful weapon that marks his rule over Dis. It embodies his ideals, representing defense, authority, and power. Its construction changes hourly, similar to the tower, appearing as either iron, steel, lead, or adamantine.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <em>Wrought-Iron Tower</em> is a magic staff that functions as a warhammer and you have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. If a creature is vulnerable to a certain type of damage, all damage dealt with the staff is converted to that damage type. When you hit a good aligned creature with it, that creature takes an extra 3d6 fire damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding the staff, you can control and navigate through the Iron Tower in Dis. While the staff is on the layer of Dis, Dispater knows the exact location of it, and is capable of teleporting to within 30 feet of it at will.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The Wrought-Iron Tower has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Best Offense.</em></strong> While attuned to the staff, you have a +2 bonus to AC and a +2 bonus to all saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, the staff has 10 charges. When you make an attack, you may spend 1 or more charges. For each charge spent, you deal an additional 2 fire damage on a successful attack. Charges are still consumed if the attack misses. The staff regains all charges each day at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing damage with the staff, you may use a bonus action and expend 1 charge to replace the damage dealt with your total AC instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Rulership.</em></strong> The <em>Wrought-Iron Tower</em> also functions as a <em>Rod of Rulership</em>, with an increased save DC of 18. This property costs 3 charges to use, though a creature that successfully saves against one of its uses is immune to future uses for 24 hours.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Slag.</em></strong> You can cast <em>Searing Smite</em> at 6th level on yourself, expending 1 charge. Instead of doing fire damage, you may have <em>Searing Smite</em> inflict acid damage. The spell requires no concentration and lasts for 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Staff.</em></strong> The <em>Wrought-Iron Tower</em> can only be destroyed inside the Iron Tower on Dis. Located somewhere within the tower is the forge that Dispater used to create the staff. An attuned creature must place the staff into the forge fires, then cast <em>Dispel Evil and Good</em> and touch the staff. They then take 20d10 fire damage, which ignores resistance and immunities. If the attuned creature survives the fire damage, the staff is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire, saving throw, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
			<set name="charges">10</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="2" />
			<stat name="strength:save:misc" value="2" />
			<stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="2" />
			<stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="2" />
			<stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="2" />
			<stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="2" />
			<stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>

</elements>
