<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>NERDS: Restoring Harmony</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://bombardgames.com/dungeons-dragons-nerds-unite/">NERDS: Restoring Harmony</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="nerds.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/collaborations/misc/nerds.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="NERDS: Restoring Harmony" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_NERDS_RESTORING_HARMONY">
		<description>
			<p>Wizards of the Coast and Nestle have conjured up a fantastic spell that have summoned NERDS into the D&amp;D universe.  Both of these cultural icons were born in the 1970s.  Now, 50 years later they are combining forces to take Dungeons &amp; Dragons players and NERDS lovers on a campaign using D&amp;D 5th edition rules.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">NRH</set>
			<set name="url">https://bombardgames.com/dungeons-dragons-nerds-unite/</set>
			<set name="image"></set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast, Bombard Games</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20210910</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--The Lost Tomb-->
	<element name="Amber Runestone" type="Magic Item" source="NERDS: Restoring Harmony" id="ID_WOTC_NRH_MAGIC_ITEM_AMBER_RUNESTONE">
		<description>
			<p>This piece of polished amber is engraved with many tiny runes. As a bonus action, you can mentally command the stone to shed bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. The light is sunlight. While the light persists, you can also use a bonus action to expand or reduce its radius of bright and dim light by 5 feet each, to a maximum of 30 feet each or a minimum of 10 feet each.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bright, dim, light, bonus action</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--Adventure Together-->
	<element name="Amulet of Harmony" type="Magic Item" source="NERDS: Restoring Harmony" id="ID_WOTC_NRH_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_HARMONY">
		<description>
			<p>The amulet is a golden disk about 4 inches across. There are symbols etched into its surface and there are six bezels that hold the Gems of Power.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <i>Amulet of Harmony</i> has the following properties:</p>
			<ul>
  				<li>While attuned to this amulet, you feel a pull in the direction of the Prismatic Well.</li>
				<li>If the Prismatic Well is dormant, you can restore its power by expending your own energy. You must be within 10-feet of the well to restore its power and you must say the words, "I invoke the power of the Prismatic Well and restore the colors of Harmony for all." If you do so, roll a d6. On a 2-6, the power of the well is restored. On a 1, the well is restored but you fall into a deep, magical slumber for 1 year and cannot be roused except by a <i>remove curse</i> spell or similar magic.</li>
				<li>You can turn off the power of the Prismatic Well, plunging all of Harmony into a polarized world where everything is horribly black and white. To do this, you must be within 10-feet of the well and you must say the words, "I revoke the power of the Prismatic Well and withhold the colors of Harmony to all." If you do so, roll a d6. On a 3-6, the well is turned off. On 1-2, the power of the well remains and you turn into a statue of black stone.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">Only a <i>wish</i> spell can undo this effect.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Prismatic Well" type="Magic Item" source="NERDS: Restoring Harmony" id="ID_WOTC_NRH_MAGIC_ITEM_PRISMATIC_WELL">
		<description>
			<p>This well enhances the colors of the city of Harmony and invigorates the population. When the well is at full power, all good-aligned creatures that see the colors experience feelings of happiness and have advantage on all Charisma checks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">good, alignment, advantage, charisma, checks</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
