<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items from Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/glory-of-the-giants/items-magic.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Adze of Annam" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_ADZE_OF_ANNAM">
		<description>
			<p>This massive adze is said to have been wielded by All-Father Annam, not as a weapon but as the tool he used to shape the various worlds of the Material Plane eons ago.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The adze has the following random properties, determined by rolling on the appropriate table in the Dungeon Master's Guide:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Magic Weapon.</em></strong> When a creature attunes to the adze, the artifact magically adjusts its size so that creature can wield it as a greataxe. The adze is a magic weapon that grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. On a hit, the adze deals an additional 3d12 force damage. It also deals double damage to objects and structures.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Divine Mattock.</em></strong> As an action, you can call upon the might of the All-Father and use the adze to cast <i>move earth</i> or <i>fabricate</i>. Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOVE_EARTH" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">random properties, attack, damage, force, damage, action, move earth, fabricate, spells</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greataxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greataxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Armor of Safeguarding" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_OF_SAFEGUARDING">
		<description>
			<p>Set in the center of this armor's chest is a citrine engraved with the shield rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this armor, your hit point maximum increases by an amount equal to 10 + your level.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the armor's rune to cast the <i>beacon of hope</i> spell with it; the spell has a duration of 1 minute and doesn't require concentration. Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">hit points, hp, maximum, beacon of hope, spell, action</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="hp" value="10" />
			<stat name="hp" value="level" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Bigby's Beneficent Bracelet" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_BIGBYS_BENEFICENT_BRACELET">
		<description>
			<p>This gorgeous jewelry piece, crafted by the wizard Bigby himself, consists of four gold rings attached via delicate chains to a wrist cuff studded with sapphires and diamonds.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The bracelet has the following random properties, determined by rolling on the appropriate table in the Dungeon Master's Guide:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Dexterous Fingers.</em></strong> While wearing the bracelet, you can cast <i>mage hand</i>.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Force Sculpture.</em></strong> By focusing and channeling the bracelet's magic for 1 minute, you can create a spectral copy of a Large or smaller nonmagical object. The copy appears in an unoccupied space within 10 feet of you, and it is made of tangible but translucent force that mimics the size, weight, and other properties of the object it's copying. The copy must appear on a surface or liquid that can support it. Creatures can touch and interact with the copy as if it were a nonmagical object.</p>
			<p class="indent">The copy is immune to all damage and can't be dispelled, but a disintegrate spell destroys it immediately. Otherwise, the copy disappears after 8 hours or when you dismiss it as an action.</p>
			<p class="indent">The bracelet can create up to three copies and regains all expended uses at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Helpful Hand.</em></strong> As an action, you can use the bracelet to cast <i>Bigby's hand</i> as a 9th-level spell (spell attack bonus +13). When you cast the spell this way, the spell doesn't require concentration. Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BIGBYS_HAND" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">random properties, mage hand, action, bigby's hand, spells</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Bloodshed Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_BLOODSHED_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>The hilt of this sword bears a carnelian engraved with the blood rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can add your Constitution modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage rolls of attacks made with this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> When you target a creature with an attack using this weapon, you can invoke the sword's rune, causing it to flare with crimson light and infusing your attack with bloodthirsty precision. You then spend and roll one of your unspent Hit Dice and add the number rolled to the attack roll. You can choose to invoke the rune after rolling the d20.</p>
			<p class="indent">If this attack hits, you can also spend and roll any number of your unspent Hit Dice and add the total rolled to the weapon's damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, constitution, damage, hit dice, hit die, attack</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Crown of the Wrath Bringer" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_CROWN_OF_THE_WRATH_BRINGER">
		<description>
			<p>This jagged iron circlet bears ornaments in the shape of the enemy rune. When worn, the crown glows with pale light as it draws upon the wearer's fury to strike opponents with vicious terror.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you make an attack roll against a creature and hit it while wearing this crown, you can spend and roll one of your unspent Hit Dice. The creature takes extra psychic damage equal to the number rolled.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the crown's rune to cast the <i>fear</i> spell (save DC 15) with it; the spell has a duration of 1 minute and doesn't require concentration. Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, hit die, hit dice, psychic, damage, action, fear, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Delver's Claws" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_DELVERS_CLAWS">
		<description>
			<p>The back of this weatherworn leather glove is adorned with three large metal hooks shaped like a mole's claws. Stitched into the glove's palm is the mountain rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">The glove is considered a simple melee weapon with the finesse and light properties, and it deals 1d4 slashing damage on a hit. While attuned to the glove, you gain a burrowing speed equal to your walking speed and blindsight to 15 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the glove's rune to bolster yourself with the sturdiness of the earth. Spend and roll a number of your unspent Hit Dice up to a maximum equal to your proficiency bonus. You then regain a number of hit points equal to the total roll plus your Constitution modifier.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, weapon, finesse, light, slashing, damage, burrowing, speed, blindsight, hit dice, hit die, healing, hit points, hp, constitution</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:burrow" value="speed" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT" />
			<stat name="blindsight:range" value="15" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Elven Thrower" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_ELVEN_THROWER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the thrown property with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with a ranged attack using this weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 damage or, if the target is a Giant, 2d8 damage. Immediately after the attack, the weapon flies back to your hand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">attack, damage</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Glowrune Pigment" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_GLOWRUNE_PIGMENT">
		<description>
			<p>This set of 1d4 + 2 small paint pots contains pigments mixed from crushed luminescent gemstones. This magical paint bestows temporary magical gifts on creatures with runes drawn on their skin with this paint.</p>
			<p class="indent">One paint pot contains enough pigment to paint one rune. A creature can spend 10 minutes to paint one of the following runes onto itself or another creature:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Journey Rune.</em></strong> Difficult terrain doesn't cost the painted creature extra movement.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Life Rune.</em></strong> The painted creature gains 10 temporary hit points and has advantage on death saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Light Rune.</em></strong> The painted creature gains darkvision to a range of 30 feet. If the painted creature already has darkvision from another source, the range of its darkvision increases by 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mountain Rune.</em></strong> The painted creature is immune to being knocked prone and has advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shield Rune.</em></strong> The painted creature has advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects that deal damage.</p>
			<p>A creature can benefit from only one painted rune at a time, so a new rune painted on a creature has no effect unless the old one is removed first. The rune's benefits last for 8 hours or until the painted creature uses its action to wipe away the rune.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">runes, temporary, hit points, temp, hp, death, saving throws, darkvision, prone, condition, dexterity</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Harp of Gilded Plenty" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_HARP_OF_GILDED_PLENTY">
		<description>
			<p>This golden harp is sculpted in the image of the god Iallanis, depicted as a young cloud giant woman. When a creature comes within 5 feet of the harp, the instrument animates and is capable of speaking, singing, and playing by itself.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you attempt to attune to the harp, you must first make either a DC 15 Charisma (Performance) check or a DC 20 Charisma (Persuasion) check to convince the harp that you are worthy, attuning to the harp on a success. If you fail, you can't attempt to attune to the harp again until the next dawn. Once you have successfully attuned to the harp, the harp resizes to suit you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Stalwart Song.</em></strong> Whenever you make a Charisma check while attuned to the harp, you can treat a roll of 9 or lower on the die as a 10.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Feast of Plenty.</em></strong> If you spend 10 minutes playing the harp, you can cast the <i>heroes' feast</i> spell from it. Once this property is used, it can't be used again until 1d10 + 10 days have passed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Soothing Melody.</em></strong> As an action, you can use the harp to cast the <i>calm emotions</i> spell (save DC 19). When the spell is cast using the harp, its duration increases to 1 hour, provided you maintain concentration on the spell. This property can be used five times, and it regains all uses at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> The harp is a sentient, chaotic good object with an Intelligence of 13, a Wisdom of 15, and a Charisma of 20. It has hearing and darkvision to a range of 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The harp can speak, read, and understand Common and Giant. It can also communicate telepathically with the creature attuned to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The harp has a dramatic and pompous personality, taking extreme pride in the quality of music produced from its strings. If the harp is shorter than 6 feet tall, it bemoans its height.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROES_FEAST" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">charisma, performance, persuasion, check, heroes' feast, calm emotions, spells, sentient, sentience</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Helm of Perfect Potential" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_HELM_OF_PERFECT_POTENTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>This copper-hued helm contains a shard of the Elemental Chaos embedded in its forehead, surrounded by a motif of a rising sun. Legend says Annam fashioned this helm for his daughter Diancastra to hold the fragment of chaos she used to prove her worth to her father.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The helm has the following random properties, determined by rolling on the appropriate table in the Dungeon Master's Guide:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Master of Guile.</em></strong> While wearing the helm, you have advantage on Charisma (Deception) and Wisdom (Insight) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Arrow of Elemental Havoc.</em></strong> As a bonus action while wearing the helm, you can launch a bolt of searing elemental energy toward a creature you can see within 90 feet of yourself. The target must make a DC 20 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 4d6 acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage (your choice). On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spellcasting.</em></strong> The helm has 6 charges and regains 1d6 charges each dawn. As an action while wearing the helm, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells (save DC 20): <i>elemental weapon</i> (1 charge), <i>call lightning</i> (2 charges), <i>wall of fire</i> (3 charges), <i>conjure elemental</i> (4 charges), <i>tsunami</i> (5 charges).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_TSUNAMI" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">random properties, advantage, charisma, deception, wisdom, insight, checks, bonus action, dexterity, saving throw, acid, cold, fire, lighting, thunder, damage, elemental weapon, call lightning, wall of fire, conjure elemental, tsunami, spells</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Horizon Puzzle Cube" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_HORIZON_PUZZLE_CUBE">
		<description>
			<p>A <i>Horizon puzzle cube</i> is an 8-inch magical cube made of gold, iron, crystal, and copper, and it is worth 5,000 gp to a sage or collector. A functioning puzzle cube can be solved with 30 minutes of work and a successful DC 25 Intelligence (Investigation) check. When the cube is solved, a 30-foot-diameter portal appears before the creature who solved the cube, leading to the northeastern platform of Horizon's Edge. The portal is two-way and remains open for 10 minutes or until a creature uses an action to change the puzzle's configuration. Puzzle cubes don't function while on Horizon's Edge, but a device somewhere in the demiplane allows a cube to function in reverse while the cube is fitted into it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">intelligence, investigation, check, portal, demiplane, plane</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Lash of Immolation" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_LASH_OF_IMMOLATION">
		<description>
			<p>The handle of this dark leather whip bears the fire rune, and embers dance around the whip's tail.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, and on a hit, the whip deals an extra 1d6 fire damage. When you score a critical hit with an attack using this whip, the target also has the restrained condition until the start of your next turn, as fiery bands lash around the target.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> When you make an attack with the whip and hit, you can use your reaction to invoke the whip's rune. Doing so increases the extra fire damage dealt by the whip to 2d6.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, attack, damage, restrained, condition, critical hit, crit, fire, reaction</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Longbow of the Healing Hearth" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_LONGBOW_OF_THE_HEALING_HEARTH">
		<description>
			<p>This ivory longbow is inscribed with a prayer to the god Hiatea, the runes of which are entwined with gilded engravings of wheat stalks and deer antlers.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon. If you load no ammunition in the weapon, it produces its own, automatically creating one magic arrow when you pull back the string. The arrow created by the bow vanishes the instant after it hits or misses a target.</p>
			<p class="indent">The bow has 8 charges for the following properties, which you can use while wielding the bow. The bow regains 1d4 + 1 charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curative Arrow.</em></strong> When you take the Attack action using the bow, you can expend 1 charge to replace one of your attacks with a blazing arrow of curative magic, which automatically hits one creature you can see within 150 feet of you. The target can then immediately spend and roll one of its unspent Hit Dice and regain a number of hit points equal to the roll plus your Wisdom modifier (minimum of +1)</p>
			<p class="indent">If the target has no unspent Hit Dice remaining, nothing happens. You can use a curative arrow only once per turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spellcasting.</em></strong> While holding the bow, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it (save DC 18): <i>create food and water</i> (1 charge), <i>warding bond</i> (2 charges), <i>guardian of faith</i> (3 charges).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_FOOD_AND_WATER" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">attack, damage, charges, healing, hit dice, create food and water, warding bond, guardian of faith, spells</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Lucent Destroyer" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_LUCENT_DESTROYER">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon is a triple-barreled bronze musket. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. It requires no ammunition, its damage is radiant instead of piercing, and it doesn't have the loading property. The base of the weapon is emblazoned with the light rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, while attuned to the weapon, you can cast <i>dancing lights</i> from the musket at will.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the weapon's rune to cast the <i>sunbeam</i> spell (save DC 17) with it. Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">It's up to you to decide whether a character has proficiency with a firearm. Characters in most D&amp;D worlds wouldn't have such proficiency. During their downtime, characters can use the training rules in the Player's Handbook to acquire proficiency, assuming that they have enough ammunition to keep the weapons working while mastering their use.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, attack, damage, loading, dancing lights, spell, at will, sunbeam</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="musket">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Musket</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mistral Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_MISTRAL_MANTLE">
		<description>
			<p>This thick, fur-lined cloak has the frost rune stitched on the hem in silvery blue thread. Frigid wind swirls around the cloak, regardless of the weather.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this cloak, you have resistance to cold damage. Additionally, when you move within 5 feet of a creature, you can cause the cloak's cold wind to buffet the creature. The creature must succeed on a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 cold damage and have the prone condition. A creature can be affected by the mantle only once during a turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the mantle's rune to cast the <i>sleet storm</i> spell (save DC 14) with it. When you use the mantle to cast the spell, the area of the spell isn't difficult terrain for you, and you can see through the storm, ignoring the normal penalties of a heavily obscured area.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, resistance, cold, damage, dexterity, saving throw, action, sleet storm, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Nimbus Coronet" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_NIMBUS_CORONET">
		<description>
			<p>The design of this bronze circlet resembles swirling clouds. At its center is set a deep-blue stone, upon which is inscribed the cloud rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this circlet, you take no damage from falling. Additionally, as a bonus action, you and everything you are wearing or carrying can teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 15 feet of yourself, reappearing in a puff of shimmering clouds.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the circlet's rune to assume a cloudlike form. The form lasts for 1 minute, until you are incapacitated, or until you dismiss it (no action required).</p>
			<p class="indent">While in cloud form, you have a flying speed of 60 feet and resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, falling, damage, bonus action, teleportation, action, flying, resistance, bludgeoning, piercing, slashing</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Orb of Skoraeus" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SKORAEUS">
		<description>
			<p>Said to be infused with the wisdom and power of the god Skoraeus, this polished stone orb is veined with iridescent crystal that seems to glow from within. The orb is 8 inches in diameter and weighs 8 pounds, making it a palm-sized trinket for a stone giant but a more unwieldy item for a Medium creature to use.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding this orb, you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your spells. You also gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Abundant Components.</em></strong> The orb has 3 charges and regains all expended charges at dawn. When you cast a spell while holding this orb, you can expend up to 3 charges to ignore the spell's material components with a gold piece cost, up to 300 gp per charge expended.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Astute Mind.</em></strong> You gain a +2 bonus to any Constitution saving throw you make to maintain your concentration on a spell.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Divine Sight.</em></strong> You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spellcasting, focus, charges, material, components, concentration, vision</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Prehistoric Figurine of Wondrous Power (Carnelian Triceratops)" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_PREHISTORIC_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_CARNELIAN_TRICERATOPS">
		<description>
			<p>Larger and more roughly hewn than typical figurines of wondrous power, these statuettes depict dinosaurs and related creatures from the earliest days of the world.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can throw a <i>prehistoric figurine of wondrous power</i> to a point on the ground within 60 feet of yourself while speaking a command word, whereupon the figurine magically transforms into a triceratops. If the space where the triceratops would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the triceratops, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">The triceratops is friendly to you and your companions, and can be ridden. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the triceratops defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
			<p class="indent">The triceratops exists for up to 6 hours. At the end of the duration, the triceratops reverts to its statuette form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the triceratops becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until 10 days have passed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_MM_INFORMATION_TRICERATOPS" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">transformation, conjuration, summoning, dinosaurs, companions, mount</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Prehistoric Figurine of Wondrous Power (Jasper Tyrannosaurus Rex)" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_PREHISTORIC_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_JASPER_TYRANNOSAURUS_REX">
		<description>
			<p>Larger and more roughly hewn than typical figurines of wondrous power, these statuettes depict dinosaurs and related creatures from the earliest days of the world.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can throw a <i>prehistoric figurine of wondrous power</i>, crafted from rare green jasper, to a point on the ground within 60 feet of yourself while speaking a command word, whereupon the figurine magically transforms into a tyrannosaurus rex. If the space where the tyrannosaurus rex would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the tyrannosaurus rex, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">The tyrannosaurus rex is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the tyrannosaurus rex defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you command the figurine while it's in tyrannosaurus rex form (including commanding it to revert to figurine form), you must roll a d20. On a 1, you lose control of the figurine, and it becomes hostile to you and your companions until it is reduced to 0 hit points, at which point it reverts to figurine form.</p>
			<p class="indent">The tyrannosaurus rex exists for up to 1 hour. At the end of the duration, the tyrannosaurus rex reverts to its statuette form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the tyrannosaurus rex becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until 14 days have passed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_MM_INFORMATION_TYRANNOSAURUS_REX" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">transformation, conjuration, summoning, dinosaurs, companions</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Prehistoric Figurine of Wondrous Power (Kyanite Pteranodon)" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_PREHISTORIC_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_KYANITE_PTERANODON">
		<description>
			<p>Larger and more roughly hewn than typical figurines of wondrous power, these statuettes depict dinosaurs and related creatures from the earliest days of the world.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can throw a <i>prehistoric figurine of wondrous power</i> to a point on the ground within 60 feet of yourself while speaking a command word, whereupon the figurine magically transforms into a pteranodon. If the space where the pteranodon would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the pteranodon, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">The pteranodon is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the pteranodon defends itself but takes no other actions. If your size is Medium or smaller, you can ride the pteranodon as a mount.</p>
			<p class="indent">The pteranodon exists for up to 8 hours. At the end of the duration, the pteranodon reverts to its statuette form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the pteranodon becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until 7 days have passed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_MM_INFORMATION_PTERANODON" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">transformation, conjuration, summoning, dinosaurs, companions, mount</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Prehistoric Figurine of Wondrous Power (Pyrite Plesiosaurus)" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_PREHISTORIC_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_PYRITE_PLESIOSAURUS">
		<description>
			<p>Larger and more roughly hewn than typical figurines of wondrous power, these statuettes depict dinosaurs and related creatures from the earliest days of the world.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can throw a <i>prehistoric figurine of wondrous power</i> to a point on the ground within 60 feet of yourself while speaking a command word, whereupon the figurine magically transforms into a plesiosaurus. If the space where the plesiosaurus would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the plesiosaurus, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">The plesiosaurus is friendly to you and your companions, and can be ridden as a mount. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the plesiosaurus defends itself but takes no other actions. While you are riding the plesiosaurus, you can use it to cast <i>water breathing</i> at will.</p>
			<p class="indent">The plesiosaurus exists for up to 12 hours. At the end of the duration, the plesiosaurus reverts to its statuette form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the plesiosaurus becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until 4 days have passed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_MM_INFORMATION_PLESIOSAURUS" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">transformation, conjuration, summoning, dinosaurs, companions, water breathing, spell, at will, mount</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Reaper's Scream" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_REAPERS_SCREAM">
		<description>
			<p>The spikes of this iron morningstar glow with sickly, pale light. The death rune is inscribed on its shaft and inlaid with pearl.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, and attacks with this weapon deal necrotic damage instead of piercing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you attack a creature with this weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, you gain 10 temporary hit points. Any creature that hits you with a melee attack while you have 1 or more of these temporary hit points takes 10 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can invoke the weapon's rune, unleashing the screams of every creature slain by the weapon in one cacophonous burst. Each creature of your choice within 60 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or have the stunned condition until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, attack, damage, necrotic, temporary, temp, hp, hit points, bonus action, stunned, condition, wisdom, saving throw</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="morningstar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Morningstar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ring of Amity" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_AMITY">
		<description>
			<p>This ring is carved from hematite and bears an engraving of the friend rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you first attune to this ring, you can touch one willing creature and form a magical bond between the two of you. While this bond lasts, whenever you are subjected to a spell or magical effect that restores hit points, the bonded creature also receives the benefits of the spell or effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can bond with a different creature whenever you finish a long rest, provided that you can touch the creature and the creature is willing.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature can benefit from only one ring of amity's bond at a time. The bond ends if either you or the creature travels to a different plane of existence, if you bond with a different creature at the end of a long rest, or if you sever the bond as a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> When the bonded creature hits a target with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to invoke the ring's rune if you are within 60 feet of the bonded creature. The bonded creature's attack is then turned into a critical hit.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bond, rune, reaction, critical hit, crits</set>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Shield of the Blazing Dreadnought" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELD_OF_THE_BLAZING_DREADNOUGHT">
		<description>
			<p>Modeled after the formidable spiked tower shields wielded by some fire giants, this iron shield emanates a constant warmth.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use a bonus action to activate the shield, causing glowing lava to flow through the shield's grooves for 1 minute. While the shield is active, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Blazing Soul.</em></strong> You have immunity to fire damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Cleansing Fire.</em></strong> As an action, you can cause the shield to flare with the cleansing fire of the god Surtur. Choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself (you can choose yourself). One disease or condition of your choice affecting this creature ends immediately; the condition can be blinded, charmed, deafened, or poisoned.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shield Bash.</em></strong> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a shield bash, targeting one creature you can see within 5 feet of yourself. The target must make a Strength saving throw (DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier). On a failed save, the target takes 3d6 bludgeoning damage plus 3d6 fire damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage only. You can use Shield Bash only once per turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the shield has been activated, it can't be activated again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, fire, damage, immunity, action, condition, blinded, charmed, deafened, poisoned, attack, strength, saving throw, bludgeoning, prone</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Staff of the Rooted Hills" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OF_THE_ROOTED_HILLS">
		<description>
			<p>The hill rune is carved into this gnarled wooden staff. The staff magically resizes to match the height of any creature that attunes to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. The first time you hit any creature with the staff on your turn, the creature must succeed on a DC 12 Strength saving throw or be restrained by spectral vines until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the staff's rune to cast either <i>hold person</i> (save DC 12) or <i>speak with plants</i> with the staff. When you cast <i>hold person</i> using the staff, the target is wreathed in spectral vines.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked to cast either spell, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, attack, damage, strength, saving throw, restrained, condition, action, hold person, speak with plants, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="staff">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Stonebreaker's Breastplate" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_STONEBREAKERS_BREASTPLATE">
		<description>
			<p>This breastplate is made from marbled granite, though it feels no heavier than a typical metal breastplate. Its chest is emblazoned with the stone rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this breastplate, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage and are immune to being knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the breastplate's rune to cast the <i>wall of stone</i> spell (save DC 14) with it. When you cast the spell in this way, you have advantage on saving throws made to maintain concentration on the spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">This armor consists of a fitted metal chest piece worn with supple leather. Although it leaves the legs and arms relatively unprotected, this armor provides good protection for the wearer's vital organs while leaving the wearer relatively unencumbered.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rune, resistance, bludgeoning, piercing, slashing, damage, prone, condition, action, wall of stone, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="breastplate">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armor">Breastplate</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Thunderbuss" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_THUNDERBUSS">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ranged weapon is a flared pistol with the storm rune engraved along the barrel. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. It requires no ammunition, its damage is thunder instead of piercing, and it doesn't have the loading property.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can invoke the weapon's rune to launch a ball of energy to a point you can see within 30 feet of yourself. The energy then detonates into a 10-foot-radius sphere of turbulent wind and thunder centered on that point, and each creature in that sphere must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d6 thunder damage, and it can't take reactions until the end of your next turn. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage only.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">It's up to you to decide whether a character has proficiency with a firearm. Characters in most D&amp;D worlds wouldn't have such proficiency. During their downtime, characters can use the training rules in the Player's Handbook to acquire proficiency, assuming that they have enough ammunition to keep the weapons working while mastering their use.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">attack, damage, loading, bonus action, rune, thunder, reactions</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="pistol">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Pistol</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="War Horn of Valor" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_WAR_HORN_OF_VALOR">
		<description>
			<p>This brass war horn is engraved with the war rune, which glows purple when the horn is blown.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can blow the horn as a bonus action. When you do, if you have the frightened condition, you immediately end that condition on yourself. You also have advantage on saving throws against being frightened until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> When you blow the horn, you can also invoke the rune, imbuing the horn's deep call with protective magic that affects creatures of your choice within 30 feet of yourself. You and all affected creatures gain a +1 bonus to AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bonus action, frightened, condition, advantage, saving throws, rune, AC, armor class</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Wayfarer's Boots" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_WAYFARERS_BOOTS">
		<description>
			<p>This pair of boots is made of durable cloth, with the journey rune stitched in golden thread above each heel. While you are wearing this item, your walking speed increases by 10 feet, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can invoke the boots' runes to cast the <i>expeditious retreat</i> spell with them. Once the runes have been invoked, they can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">speed, advantage, wisdom, survival, checks, bonus action, rune, expeditious retreat, spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed" value="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Wyrmreaver Gauntlets" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_WYRMREAVER_GAUNTLETS">
		<description>
			<p>Originally crafted for ground-bound giant brawlers to fight against dragons and other enormous predators of the sky, these studded gauntlets are engraved with the dragon rune.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you are wearing these gauntlets, your unarmed strike deals an additional 1d6 force damage on a hit. Additionally, whenever you finish a long rest, choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. You have resistance to the chosen damage type until you finish another long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can invoke the gauntlets' runes and summon two enormous spectral fists that envelop the gauntlets and mimic your hand motions. The fists can also launch themselves to strike distant opponents, returning immediately to your space after they hit or miss.</p>
			<p class="indent">The fists last for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated. While the spectral fists are active, unarmed strikes you make on your turn have a reach of 30 feet, and when you hit a creature with an opportunity attack made with your unarmed strike, the creature must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or have the prone condition.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the runes have been invoked, they can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">force, damage, acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, resistance, bonus action, rune, reach, range, unarmed strike, opportunity attack, prone, condition</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Zephyr Armor" type="Magic Item" source="Bigby Presents: Glory of the Giants" id="ID_WOTC_GOTG_MAGIC_ITEM_ZEPHYR_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>This fine set of white-and-silver armor bears the wind rune upon its chest.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you have advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks and Dexterity saving throws as your movements are bolstered by gentle currents of wind.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Invoking the Rune.</em></strong> As an action, you can invoke the armor's rune to cast the <i>wind wall</i> spell (save DC 15) with it. Once the rune has been invoked, it can't be invoked again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">wind wall, spell, rune, advantage, dexterity, acrobatics, saving throws, saves</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
