<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Bastion Charms</name>
		<description>Bastion Charms from Eberron: Forge of the Artificer</description>
		<author url="https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/category/5147000?pid=DB5147000/">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items-charms.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer/items/items-charms.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Manifest Charm" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. The effects of the Charm depend on the facility’s linked plane:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><b>Daanvi, the Perfect Order.</b> You can expend the Charm (no action required) to end the Blinded, Deafened, Paralyzed, or Poisoned condition on yourself.</li>
				<li><b>Dolurrh, the Realm of the Dead.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell from the Necromancy school, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</li>
				<li><b>Fernia, the Sea of Fire.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that deals Fire damage, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</li>
				<li><b>Irian, the Eternal Dawn.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that restores Hit Points or deals Radiant damage, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</li>
				<li><b>Lamannia, the Twilight Forest.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that conjures or summons a Beast, an Elemental, or a Fey (including <i>Conjure Animals, Conjure Elemental, Conjure Fey, Conjure Minor Elementals, Conjure Woodland Beings, Find Steed, Summon Beast, Summon Elemental,</i> or <i>Summon Fey</i>), you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</li>
				<li><b>Mabar, the Endless Night.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that animates or summons an Undead (including <i>Animate Dead, Create Undead,</i> or <i>Summon Undead</i>), you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</li>
				<li><b>Risia, the Plain of Ice.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that deals Cold damage, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</li>
				<li><b>Shavarath, the Battleground.</b> When you score a Critical Hit, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to deal an extra 10 damage of one of the types dealt by the attack.</li>
				<li><b>Syrania, the Azure Sky.</b> You can expend the Charm as a Bonus Action to gain a Fly Speed equal to your Speed for 1 minute.</li>
				<li><b>Thelanis, the Faerie Court.</b> When you cast a spell from the Enchantment or Illusion school, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to give one target of the spell Disadvantage on its saving throw against the spell.</li>
				<li><b>Xoriat, the Realm of Delirium.</b> When you use a spell slot to cast a spell, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to roll on the Wild Magic Surge table in the Player’s Handbook.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Daanvi)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_DAANVI">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Daanvi, the Perfect Order.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can expend the Charm (no action required) to end the Blinded, Deafened, Paralyzed, or Poisoned condition on yourself.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Dolurrh)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_DOLURRH">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Dolurrh, the Realm of the Dead.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use a spell slot to cast a spell from the Necromancy school, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Fernia)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_FERNIA">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Fernia, the Sea of Fire.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that deals Fire damage, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Irian)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_IRIAN">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Irian, the Eternal Dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that restores Hit Points or deals Radiant damage, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Lamannia)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_LAMANNIA">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Lamannia, the Twilight Forest.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that conjures or summons a Beast, an Elemental, or a Fey (including <i>Conjure Animals, Conjure Elemental, Conjure Fey, Conjure Minor Elementals, Conjure Woodland Beings, Find Steed, Summon Beast, Summon Elemental,</i> or <i>Summon Fey</i>), you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Mabar)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_MABAR">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Mabar, the Endless Night.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use a spell slot to cast a spell that animates or summons an Undead (including <i>Animate Dead, Create Undead,</i> or <i>Summon Undead</i>), you can expend the Charm (no action required) to treat the spell as if it were cast using a spell slot 1 level above the slot expended.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Shavarath)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_SHAVARATH">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Shavarath, the Battleground.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you score a Critical Hit, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to deal an extra 10 damage of one of the types dealt by the attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Syrania)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_SYRANIA">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Syrania, the Azure Sky.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can expend the Charm as a Bonus Action to gain a Fly Speed equal to your Speed for 1 minute.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Thelanis)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_THELANIS">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Thelanis, the Faerie Court.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you cast a spell from the Enchantment or Illusion school, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to give one target of the spell Disadvantage on its saving throw against the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Manifest Charm (Xoriat)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANIFEST_CHARM_XORIAT">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue the Empower order of a Manifest Zone Bastion Facility, the facility’s hireling conducts magical rites for the next 7 days. At the end of that period, you gain a special Charm  called a Manifest Charm, which lasts until you use it. This charm is linked with the plane of Xoriat, the Realm of Delirium.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use a spell slot to cast a spell, you can expend the Charm (no action required) to roll on the Wild Magic Surge table in the Player’s Handbook.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_INFORMATION_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_SORCERY_WILD_MAGIC_SURGE_TABLE" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Museum Charm" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MUSEUM_CHARM">
		<description>
			<p>Within your Museum Bastion Facility is one treasure that gives you a magical Charm when you spend 7 days studying it and then finish a Long Rest in your Bastion. The Charm lasts for 7 days or until you use it. You can’t gain another Charm from this facility while you still have one. The effect of the Charm depends on the origin of the treasure in your Museum. You can choose one of the following options (your DM might make more options available or limit the existing options based on your past expeditions):</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><b>Charm of Argonnessen.</b> While you have this Charm, you know Draconic. You can expend the Charm to cast <i>Dragon’s Breath</i> (level 4 version), targeting yourself only.</li>
				<li><b>Charm of Ashtakala.</b> While you have this Charm, you know Abyssal and Infernal. You can expend the Charm to cast <i>Ray of Sickness</i> (level 4 version).</li>
				<li><b>Charm of Dhakaan.</b> While you have this Charm, you know the Goblin language. You can expend the Charm to cast <i>Staggering Smite</i>.</li>
				<li><b>Charm of Khyber.</b> While you have this Charm, you have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet. You can expend the Charm to gain Truesight with a range of 60 feet for 1 minute.</li>
				<li><b>Charm of Xen'drik.</b> While you have this Charm, you know the Giant language. As a Bonus Action, you can expend the Charm to change your Strength score to 25 for 1 hour.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Museum Charm (Argonnessen)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MUSEUM_CHARM_ARGONNESSEN">
		<description>
			<p>Within your Museum Bastion Facility is one treasure that gives you a magical Charm when you spend 7 days studying it and then finish a Long Rest in your Bastion. The Charm lasts for 7 days or until you use it. You can’t gain another Charm from this facility while you still have one. This particular charm is from an Argonnessen treasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you have this Charm, you know Draconic. You can expend the Charm to cast <i>Dragon’s Breath</i> (level 4 version), targeting yourself only.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Museum Charm (Ashtakala)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MUSEUM_CHARM_ASHTAKALA">
		<description>
			<p>Within your Museum Bastion Facility is one treasure that gives you a magical Charm when you spend 7 days studying it and then finish a Long Rest in your Bastion. The Charm lasts for 7 days or until you use it. You can’t gain another Charm from this facility while you still have one. This particular charm is from an Ashtakala treasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you have this Charm, you know Abyssal and Infernal. You can expend the Charm to cast <i>Ray of Sickness</i> (level 4 version).</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Museum Charm (Dhakaan)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MUSEUM_CHARM_DHAKAAN">
		<description>
			<p>Within your Museum Bastion Facility is one treasure that gives you a magical Charm when you spend 7 days studying it and then finish a Long Rest in your Bastion. The Charm lasts for 7 days or until you use it. You can’t gain another Charm from this facility while you still have one. This particular charm is from a Dhakaan treasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you have this Charm, you know the Goblin language. You can expend the Charm to cast <i>Staggering Smite</i>.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_STAGGERING_SMITE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_GOBLIN" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Museum Charm (Khyber)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MUSEUM_CHARM_KHYBER">
		<description>
			<p>Within your Museum Bastion Facility is one treasure that gives you a magical Charm when you spend 7 days studying it and then finish a Long Rest in your Bastion. The Charm lasts for 7 days or until you use it. You can’t gain another Charm from this facility while you still have one. This particular charm is from a Khyber treasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you have this Charm, you have Darkvision with a range of 120 feet. You can expend the Charm to gain Truesight with a range of 60 feet for 1 minute.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="120" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Museum Charm (Xen'drik)" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" id="ID_WOTC_EFOTA_MAGIC_ITEM_MUSEUM_CHARM_XENDRIK">
		<description>
			<p>Within your Museum Bastion Facility is one treasure that gives you a magical Charm when you spend 7 days studying it and then finish a Long Rest in your Bastion. The Charm lasts for 7 days or until you use it. You can’t gain another Charm from this facility while you still have one. This particular charm is from a Xen'drik treasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you have this Charm, you know the Giant language. As a Bonus Action, you can expend the Charm to change your Strength score to 25 for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_GIANT" />
		</rules>
	</element>

</elements>