<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/phandelver-and-below-the-shattered-obelisk/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Phandelver and Below: The Shattered Obelisk" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_PBSO_SOURCE_PHANDELVER_AND_BELOW_THE_SHATTERED_OBELISK">
		<description>
			<p><strong>Uncover a new threat to Phandalin in this timeless dungeoneering adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.
</strong></p>
			<p><i>Phandelver and Below: The Shattered Obelisk</i> is a high-fantasy adventure that begins in the beloved town of Phandalin as it faces unimaginable danger. Whether the heroes are newcomers to Phandalin or are returning after the acclaimed Dungeons &amp; Dragons adventure <i>Lost Mine of Phandelver</i>, they discover hints of a threat lurking below the town. The heroes soon learn that the cult of a malevolent entity has set its sights on transforming Phandalin into the capital of its evil empire. To save the town from oblivion, the heroes must uncover a nefarious plot and confront the otherworldly cultists directly.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Offers new Dungeon Masters and players the opportunity to dive into their first full-fledged Dungeons &amp; Dragons adventure</li>
				<li>Retains the beloved Lost Mine of Phandelver quests that unfold into a brand-new adventure with classic D&amp;D themes and a tinge of horror</li>
				<li>Presents a bestiary with approximately two-dozen new creatures that showcase psionic magic, body horror, and more.</li>
				<li>Provides a magic appendix that includes new consumable metamagic items, Netherese amulets, and duergar magic</li>
				<li>Includes a double-sided poster map with the Phandalin region on one side and the town of Phandalin plus key encounters in the adventure on the other</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">PBSO</set>
			<set name="url">https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/en/product/820931/phandelver-and-below-the-shattered-obelisk-digital-plus-physical-bundle</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/phandelver-and-below-the-shattered-obelisk/PBSO.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20230919</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
</elements>
