<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/journeys-through-the-radiant-citadel/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Biza's Breath" type="Item" source="Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel" id="ID_WOTC_JTRC_POISON_BIZAS_BREATH">
		<description>
			<p>A creature subjected to this poison must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or become poisoned for 1 minute. The poisoned creature must use its action to make a melee attack against a randomly determined creature within its reach. If there is no other creature within its reach, the poisoned creature does nothing on its turn. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_POISON_INHALED" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">poison,inhale</set>
			<set name="category">Poison</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet alt="Biza's Breath (Inhaled)" />
	</element>

	<element name="Black Ghost Orchid Seed" type="Item" source="Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel" id="ID_WOTC_JTRC_ITEM_BLACK_GHOST_ORCHID_SEED">
		<description>
			<p>Every few years, a ghost orchid colony grows a black pod as thick as a human fist that holds three soft, black seeds. A creature that consumes one of these black seeds is affected by the spell <i>feign death</i>. If the creature is unaware of the pod's effects or does not wish to be affected, it can resist the effect by succeeding on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw. Otherwise, it is considered to be a willing recipient of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="White Ghost Orchid Seed" type="Item" source="Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel" id="ID_WOTC_JTRC_ITEM_WHITE_GHOST_ORCHID_SEED">
		<description>
			<p>More rarely, the orchids produce a smaller pod holding a single white seed. Among its various magical properties, if a white seed is ground and scattered over a dead body, the body is affected by the <i>resurrection</i> spell. A white ghost orchid seed has no effect if consumed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Hammock of Worlds" type="Magic Item" source="Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel" id="ID_WOTC_JTRC_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMMOCK_OF_WORLDS">
		<description>
			<p>The Hammock of Worlds is a colorful hammock woven with traditional Ataguan designs. It can be used only by a member of the order known as the Green Doctors.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action to unfold and place the Hammock of Worlds on a solid surface, whereupon it creates a two-way portal to the Ghost Orchid Tepui in the Feywild or to the Drought Elder in the Far Realm (the user's choice). You can use an action to close an open portal by taking hold of the edges of the cloth and folding it up. Once Hammock of Worlds has opened a portal, it can't do so again for 1d8 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Lesser Hammock of Worlds" type="Magic Item" source="Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel" id="ID_WOTC_JTRC_MAGIC_ITEM_LESSER_HAMMOCK_OF_WORLDS">
		<description>
			<p>The Hammock of Worlds is a colorful hammock woven with traditional Ataguan designs.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action to unfold and place the lesser version of the Hammock of Worlds on a solid surface, whereupon it creates a two-way portal to the Ghost Orchid Tepui in the Feywild. You can use an action to close an open portal by taking hold of the edges of the cloth and folding it up. Once the lesser version of the Hammock of Worlds has opened a portal, it can't do so again for 1d8 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Way of the Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel" id="ID_WOTC_JTRC_MAGIC_ITEM_WAY_OF_THE_DRAGON">
		<description>
			<p>You are as elusive and free as the Dragon of Heavenly Blessings. This charm has 6 charges. As an action, you can expend 1 charge and gain one of the following benefits.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Difficult terrain doesn't cost you extra movement unit the end of your next long rest.</li>
				<li>The next time you end your turn paralyzed or restrained, that condition ends on you. This benefit then ends.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>After you expend a charge, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest. Once all its charges have been expended, the charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
