<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--Magic Items-->
	<element name="Daoud's Wondrous Lanthorn" type="Magic Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_MAGIC_ITEM_DAOUDS_WONDROUS_LANTHORN">
		<description>
			<p>This artifact destroys wealth to provide light and protection. Wrought from the finest yellow gold, the lantern has four faces, and an unwavering amber flame burns within it. The faces of the lantern are fitted with faceted gemstone lenses.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lantern is a symbol of the teachings of Daoud, who was once a priest of Istus, a god of fate. When Daoud was stripped of his possessions, he developed a radical new philosophy in his quest to understand fate. He urged followers of his ideology to eschew wealth and seek out all fortunes, good and ill, to unravel the cloth of destiny.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The lantern has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Precious Fuel.</em></strong> The lantern burns only one source of fuel: powdered gemstones placed in the lantern's base. The lantern can hold a maximum of 10,000 gp worth of powdered gems, and it contains 9,000 gp of fuel when found. Thereafter it attempts to burn 100 gp of fuel after each year passes, keeping the lantern burning for another year. If no fuel is available, the lantern's flame goes out. You can add more fuel to the lantern as part of a short or long rest. Once added, fuel can't be removed from the lantern's base.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lantern's flame can't be extinguished by any means other than running out of fuel. If the lantern's flame goes out, the creature attuned to it immediately dies. One exception to this rule exists (see the "Destroying the Lantern" section).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Revealing Light.</em></strong> The lantern sheds bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light for an additional 60 feet. Invisible creatures and objects are visible while in the lantern's bright light.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attuned to the lantern, you can use a bonus action to dim the lantern, reducing the light to dim light in a 5-foot radius, or brighten the lantern back to its normal bright light radius.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Lenses.</em></strong> When found, the lantern's faces display the following gem lenses: diamond, emerald, ruby, and sapphire. As part of a short or long rest, you can magically change any of these gem lenses to a different type of gem shown in the Lenses table. The gem lenses can't be removed from the lantern.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action while holding the lantern, you can burn some of the lantern's fuel to cast a spell (save DC 20) through one or more of its current gem lenses, as noted in the Lenses table. The spell's target or point of origin must be in the lantern's area of bright light. If there isn't enough fuel left to cast the spell, the last of the remaining fuel is expended, and the flame goes out.</p>
			<h5>Lenses</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Lens Color</td><td>Spell</td><td>Fuel Cost</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Amethyst</td><td><i>Reverse Gravity</i></td><td>3,000 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Diamond</td><td><i>Disintegrate</i></td><td>2,000 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Emerald</td><td><i>Haste</i></td><td>500 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Jacinth</td><td><i>Flame Strike</i></td><td>1,000 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Ruby</td><td><i>Hold Monster</i></td><td>1,000 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Sapphire</td><td><i>Fear</i></td><td>500 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Topaz</td><td><i>Slow</i></td><td>500 gp</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Any four colors</td><td><i>Prismatic Wall</i></td><td>5,000 gp</td></tr>
			</table>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Lantern.</em></strong> To destroy the lantern, the creature attuned to it must forsake all material possessions except for the lantern and common clothes. Then the creature must willingly snuff the lantern's flame with the intention to destroy the artifact. When its flame is snuffed in this way, the lantern's gold corrodes, the lenses and remaining gemstone fuel turn to worthless sand, and the creature attuned to it is spared.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">random properties, minor beneficial, major beneficial, minor detrimental, action, reverse gravity, disintegrate, haste, flame strike, hold monster, fear, slow, prismatic wall, spells</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Heretic" type="Magic Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_MAGIC_ITEM_HERETIC">
		<description>
			<p>The blasphemous weapon Heretic was created by a cult to steal power from good-aligned gods. The blade hungers to strike down servants of the Upper Planes and weaken the forces of good.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. <em>Heretic</em> has 6 charges for the following properties; the sword regains 1d4 + 1 charges daily at dawn:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroy Devotion.</em></strong> Once per turn when you hit a creature with this weapon, you can expend 1 of its charges to attempt to render the target powerless. The target must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or have the paralyzed condition until the start of your next turn. Celestials have disadvantage on the save.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Faith Hunter.</em></strong> While holding the sword, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it: <i>Detect Evil and Good</i> (1 charge), <i>Fly</i> (2 charges), or <i>True Seeing</i> (3 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><em><strong>Sentience.</strong> Heretic</em> is a sentient, chaotic evil weapon with an Intelligence of 17, a Wisdom of 17, and a Charisma of 15. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon can speak, read, and understand Common and Giant, and it can communicate with its wielder telepathically. Its voice is soft and deep but rises in a wild furor when it's aware Celestials or worshipers of good-aligned deities are present. While you are attuned to it, <em>Heretic</em> also understands every language you know.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em><strong>Personality.</strong> Heretic</em> craves the destruction of good-aligned gods and their supporters. The blade is condescending and snobby, especially in the company of priests and other pious folk, at whom it often directs sneering comments. When <em>Heretic</em> identifies its quarry, it erupts in a frenzied need for violence.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">attack, damage, evil, neutral, constitution, saving throw, paralyzed, disadvantage, detect evil and good, fly, true seeing, spells, sentient, sentience, charges</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a non-good creature">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Staff of Ruling" type="Magic Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OF_RULING">
		<description>
			<p>An ornate carving of a serpent adorned with a coursing river spirals down the length of this redand-gold staff. While you're holding it, you can use an action to produce one of the following effects. Once the staff has produced an effect, it can't produce that effect again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Orb of Lightning.</em></strong> You create a Small orb of lightning in an unoccupied space you can see within 60 feet of yourself. You concentrate on this orb as if concentrating on a spell. As a bonus action, you can move the orb up to 20 feet in any direction.</p>
			<p class="indent">When your concentration ends, or when a creature enters the orb's space or starts its turn there, the orb detonates in a 20-foot-radius sphere. Each creature in that area must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking lightning damage equal to the total accumulated damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one; the orb's base damage is 6d6, and if at the end of your turn the orb hasn't detonated, its damage increases by 2d6, to a maximum of 10d6.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Staff to Snake.</em></strong> You throw the staff to an unoccupied space within 10 feet of you, and the staff becomes a giant poisonous snake. The snake is under your control and shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours.</p>
			<p class="indent">On your turn, you can mentally command the snake if it is within 60 feet of you and you don't have the incapacitated condition. You decide what action the snake takes and where it moves during its turn, or you can issue it a general command, such as to attack your enemies or guard a location.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you use a bonus action to speak the command word again, or if the snake is reduced to 0 hit points, the snake reverts to staff form in its current space.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Thunderclap.</em></strong> You point the staff skyward, producing a fearsome thunderclap. Each creature of your choice in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or have the deafened and frightened conditions until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">focus, arcane, action, dexterity, constitution, saving throw, area of effect, aoe, lightning, damage, companion, bonus action, concentration, deafened, frightened, condition</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--Technology-->
	<element name="Antigravity Belt" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_ANTIGRAVITY_BELT">
		<description>
			<p>Metal tubes ring the lower edge of this wide belt. It is powered by an energy cell stored in a metal case near the buckle. Placing a full energy cell in the belt gives the belt 10 charges.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Activating the Belt.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can expend any number of the belt's charges to activate it; the belt remains active for 1 minute per charge expended. You can use a bonus action to deactivate the belt early, but doing so doesn't recover any expended charges.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you activate the belt, and as a bonus action while it remains active, you can rise or descend vertically up to 20 feet. You remain floating in place while the property is active, and you can move yourself horizontally by being pushed or towed or by scooting yourself along a surface, such as a wall or ceiling, at half your walking speed. If you are still levitating when the belt deactivates, you fall.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Replacing the Energy Cell.</em></strong> While the belt has charges remaining, its energy cell can't be removed. Once the belt has 0 charges, you can replace the energy cell with a new cell by using an action or a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, bonus action, charges</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">waist</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Grenade, Concussion" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_GRENADE_CONCUSSION">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, a character can throw a grenade at a point up to 60 feet away. With a grenade launcher, the character can propel the grenade up to 120 feet away.</p>
			<p class="indent">This grenade explodes in a concussive blast that fills a 20-foot-radius sphere. Each creature in that area must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking (6d6) force damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, action, area of effect, aoe, dexterity, saving throw, force, damage</set>
			<set name="category">Explosives</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Grenade, Sleep" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_GRENADE_SLEEP">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, a character can throw a grenade at a point up to 60 feet away. With a grenade launcher, the character can propel the grenade up to 120 feet away.</p>
			<p class="indent">This grenade releases a cloud of soporific mist that fills a 20-foot-radius sphere, then dissipates. Each creature in that area must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or have the unconscious condition for 1 hour. The condition ends on a creature early if the creature takes damage or if another creature uses an action to shake it awake.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, action, area of effect, aoe, constitution, saving throw, unconscious, condition</set>
			<set name="category">Explosives</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Needler Pistol" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_NEEDLER_PISTOL">
		<description>
			<p>This strange pistol resembles a flask with a honeycomb of tubes sticking out its front. The weapon is powered by an energy cell stored at the base of the flask. Placing a full energy cell in the pistol gives the pistol 10 charges.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action while holding this pistol, you can expend 1 of its charges to fire a burst of glowing, needlelike darts from the pistol in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 8d4 piercing damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Replacing the Energy Cell.</em></strong> While the pistol has charges remaining, its energy cell can't be removed. Once the pistol has 0 charges, you can replace the energy cell with a new cell by using an action or a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, action, area of effect, aoe, dexterity, saving throw, piercing, damage, charges</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Paralysis Pistol" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_PARALYSIS_PISTOL">
		<description>
			<p>This curious-looking pistol is shaped like a large, glass bulb with a handle on the bottom and brass prongs protruding from its front. The weapon is powered by an energy cell stored in its grip. Placing a full energy cell in the pistol gives the pistol 6 charges.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action while holding this pistol, you can expend 1 of its charges to fire a ray of crackling energy at a creature you can see within 60 feet of yourself. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or have the paralyzed condition for 1 minute. At the end of each of the target's turns, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Replacing the Energy Cell.</em></strong> While the pistol has charges remaining, its energy cell can't be removed. Once the pistol has 0 charges, you can replace the energy cell with a new cell by using an action or a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, action, constitution, saving throw, paralyzed, condition, charges</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Powered Armor" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_POWERED_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>This suit of technologically advanced plate armor includes an under-suit that can fully seal, a helmet with a full face mask and crystal lenses in the eyeholes, and a set of gauntlets. The armor is powered by an energy cell stored in a compartment on the thigh plate.</p>
			<p class="indent">Placing a full energy cell in the armor gives the armor 24 charges. A suit of powered armor functions as a suit of normal plate armor, even when it has 0 charges remaining.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Activating the Armor.</em></strong> As an action, you can expend any number of the armor's charges to activate it; the armor remains active for 1 hour per charge expended. You can use a bonus action to deactivate the armor early, but doing so doesn't recover any expended charges.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the armor is active, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Augmented Physicality.</em></strong> You have advantage on Strength checks, and your carrying capacity is doubled.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Environmental Adaptation.</em></strong> The armor seals airtight and provides its own atmosphere. You can breathe normally in any environment and withstand extreme temperatures, and you're unaffected by harmful gases, as well as contact and inhaled poisons.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Force Field.</em></strong> When you would take damage, you can use your reaction to expend 1 of the armor's charges to deploy a defensive force field. Roll 3d10 and reduce the damage taken by the total rolled.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Propulsion.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can expend 1 of the armor's charges to gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed for 1 minute. If you're airborne when this duration ends, you fall.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Replacing the Energy Cell.</em></strong> While the armor has charges remaining, its energy cell can't be removed. Once the armor has 0 charges, you can replace the energy cell with a new cell by using an action or a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, action, advantage, strength, checks, reaction, force, carry capacity, carrying capacity, bonus action, fly speed, flying speed, charges</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Robot Controller" type="Item" source="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" id="ID_WOTC_QIS_ITEM_ROBOT_CONTROLLER">
		<description>
			<p>This small handheld device features a glass pane with a glowing display that responds to your touch.</p>
			<p class="indent">The controller is powered by an energy cell stored in the device. Placing a full energy cell in the device gives the device 3 charges.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action while holding this device, you can expend 1 of its charges to cause one of the following effects:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Control.</em></strong> One Construct of your choice within 60 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or have the charmed condition for 1 minute. While charmed in this way, the Construct obeys your verbal commands, and you and the Construct can communicate remotely with each other through the device. Whenever the charmed Construct takes damage, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Disrupt.</em></strong> Constructs of your choice within 30 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or have the incapacitated condition for 1 minute. An incapacitated Construct can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Replacing the Energy Cell.</em></strong> While the device has charges remaining, its energy cell can't be removed. Once the device has 0 charges, you can replace the energy cell with a new cell by using an action or a bonus action..</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">technology, action, wisdom, saving throw, charm, incapacitated, condition</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
