<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Quests from the Infinite Staircase" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_QUESTS_FROM_THE_INFINITE_STAIRCASE">
		<description>
			<h5 style="margin-top:-1em">ADVENTURE AWAITS BEHIND EVERY DOOR!</h5>
			<p><strong>Enter the Infinite Staircase – a dreamlike expanse with doors leading to fantastical worlds and planes of existence.</strong></p>
			<p><i>Quests from the Infinite Staircase</i> embraces the magic of the most beloved <i>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</i> adventures of all time. Your journey begins in the Infinite Staircase, a dreamlike expanse with doors leading to fantastical worlds, where you'll meet Nafas, a noble genie who fulfills wishes with the help of valiant heroes - like you! As you explore what lies beyond each door, embark on timeless adventures and make memorable moments with your party.</p>
			<p>This handpicked collection contains 6 remastered first edition adventures, complete with striking settings and a lovable cast of characters. These unforgettable quests can be run individually or as a delightful campaign that takes characters from level 1 to 13.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>REDISCOVER BELOVED FIRST EDITION ADVENTURES.</b> Uncover the ruins of an ancient kingdom, dig through the wreckage of a futuristic spaceship, and explore an enchanting fairytale garden; these treasured tales have been carefully chosen and lovingly remastered for fifth edition.</li>
				<li><b>PLAY INDIVIDUALLY OR AS A CAMPAIGN.</b> Designed for maximum flexibility, all 6 can be played as standalone adventures, dropped into an ongoing game, or run together as a cohesive campaign that takes characters from level 1 to 13.</li>
				<li><b>MAGIC ITEMS &amp; MARVELOUS MACHINERY.</b> Let your imagination soar with 3 new magic items and 6 futuristic technological devices; take inspiration from this marvelous machinery as you infuse your campaign and characters with some classic D&amp;D flair.</li>
				<li><b>MEET OVER 30 MEMORABLE MONSTERS &amp; CHARACTERS.</b> From sentient androids to cosmic frog monsters, you’re sure to emerge with a newfound favorite or two as you journey through roleplaying history.</li>
				<li><b>6 TIMELESS D&amp;D ADVENTURES.</b> This book contains the following <i>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</i> adventures: The Lost City, When a Star Falls, Beyond the Crystal Cave, Pharaoh, The Lost Caverns of Tsojcanth, and Expeditions to the Barrier Peaks.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">QIS</set>
			<set name="url">https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/en/product/928653/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase-digital-plus-physical-bundle</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/quests-from-the-infinite-staircase/QIS.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20240716</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
</elements>
