<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Battle Master</name>
		<description>The Battle Master subclass from the Player’s Handbook 2024.</description>
		<author url="https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/en/product/1001494/2024-player-s-handbook-digital-plus-physical-bundle">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="fighter-battle-master.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/players-handbook-2024/archetypes/fighter-battle-master.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Battle Master" type="Archetype" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER">
		<supports>Fighter Subclass</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Master Sophisticated Battle Maneuvers</p>
			<p>Battle Masters are students of the art of battle, learning martial techniques passed down through generations. The most accomplished Battle Masters are well-rounded figures who combine their carefully honed combat skills with academic study in the fields of history, theory, and the arts.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY"/>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_STUDENT_OF_WAR"/>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_KNOW_YOUR_ENEMY"/>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY"/>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_RELENTLESS"/>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_ULTIMATE_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY"/>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_INFORMATION_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_MANEUVER_OPTIONS"/>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_STUDENT_OF_WAR" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_KNOW_YOUR_ENEMY" level="7"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_RELENTLESS" level="15"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_ULTIMATE_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" level="18"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 3: Combat Superiority" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your experience on the battlefield has refined your fighting techniques. You learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called Superiority Dice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Maneuvers.</em></strong> You learn three maneuvers of your choice from the "Maneuvers Options" section later in this subclass's description. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack.</p>
			<p class="indent">You learn two additional maneuvers of your choice when you reach Fighter levels 7, 10, and 15. Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority Dice.</em></strong> You have four Superiority Dice, which are d8s. A Superiority Die is expended when you use it. You regain all expended Superiority Dice when you finish a Short or Long Rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain an additional Superiority Die when you reach Fighter levels 7 (five dice total) and 15 (six dice total).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Saving Throws.</em></strong> If a maneuver requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 plus your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice) and Proficiency Bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Combat Superiority" usage="{{combat superiority:dice amount}}d{{combat superiority:dice size}}/Short Rest">
			<description>You can use only one maneuver per attack. You can replace one maneuver you know with a different one when you reach levels 7, 10, and 15.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="combat superiority:dice amount" value="4" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="combat superiority:dice amount" value="5" bonus="base" level="7" />
			<stat name="combat superiority:dice amount" value="6" bonus="base" level="15" />
			<stat name="combat superiority:dice size" value="8" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="combat superiority:dc:ability" value="strength:modifier" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="combat superiority:dc:ability" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="combat superiority:dc" value="8" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="combat superiority:dc" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency"/>
			<stat name="combat superiority:dc" value="combat superiority:dc:ability" bonus="ability"/>

			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Maneuver (Combat Superiority 3)" supports="Maneuver, Battle Master" number="3" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Maneuver (Combat Superiority 7)" supports="Maneuver, Battle Master" number="2" level="7" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Maneuver (Combat Superiority 10)" supports="Maneuver, Battle Master" number="2" level="10" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Maneuver (Combat Superiority 15)" supports="Maneuver, Battle Master" number="2" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 3: Student of War" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_STUDENT_OF_WAR">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_STUDENT_OF_WAR</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with one type of Artisan's Tools of your choice, and you gain proficiency in one skill of your choice from the skills available to Fighters at level 1.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Student of War)" supports="Artisan tools" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Student of War)" supports="Skill,Fighter" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 7: Know Your Enemy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_KNOW_YOUR_ENEMY">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_KNOW_YOUR_ENEMY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>As a Bonus Action, you can discern certain strengths and weaknesses of a creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself; you know whether that creature has any Immunities, Resistances, or Vulnerabilities, and if the creature has any, you know what they are.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest. You can also restore a use of the feature by expending one Superiority Die (no action required).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Know Your Enemy" action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>Choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of yourself. You learn what Immunities, Resistances, and Vulnerabilities that creature has. &#13;
			You can restore a use of the feature by expending one Superiority Die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 10: Improved Combat Superiority" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Superiority Die becomes a d10.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="combat superiority:dice size" value="10" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 15: Relentless" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_RELENTLESS">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_RELENTLESS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Once per turn, when you use a maneuver, you can roll 1d8 and use the number rolled instead of expending a Superiority Die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Relentless" usage="1/Turn">
			<description>When you use a maneuver, you can roll 1d8 and use the number rolled instead of expending a Superiority Die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 18: Ultimate Combat Superiority" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_ULTIMATE_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_ULTIMATE_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your Superiority Die becomes a d12.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="combat superiority:dice size" value="12" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Maneuver Options" type="Information" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_INFORMATION_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_MANEUVER_OPTIONS">
		<description>
			<p>The maneuvers are presented here in alphabetical order.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Ambush.</b></i> When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or an Initiative roll, you can expend one Superiority Die and add the die to the roll, unless you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Bait and Switch.</b></i> When you’re within 5 feet of a creature on your turn, you can expend one Superiority Die and switch places with that creature, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement and the creature is willing and doesn’t have the Incapacitated condition. This movement doesn’t provoke Opportunity Attacks.</p>
			<p class="indent">Roll the Superiority Die. Until the start of your next turn, you or the other creature (your choice) gains a bonus to AC equal to the number rolled.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Commander’s Strike.</b></i> When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a willing creature who can see or hear you and expend one Superiority Die. That creature can immediately use its Reaction to make one attack with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, adding the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage roll on a hit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Commanding Presence.</b></i> When you make a Charisma (Intimidation, Performance, or Persuasion) check, you can expend one Superiority Die and add that die to the roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Disarming Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to disarm the target. Add the Superiority Die roll to the attack’s damage roll. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or drop one object of your choice that it’s holding, with the object landing in its space.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Distracting Strike.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to distract the target. Add the Superiority Die roll to the attack’s damage roll. The next attack roll against the target by an attacker other than you has Advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Evasive Footwork.</b></i> As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die and take the Disengage action. You also roll the die and add the number rolled to your AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Feinting Attack.</b></i> As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die to feint, choosing one creature within 5 feet of yourself as your target. You have Advantage on your next attack roll against that target this turn. If that attack hits, add the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Goading Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to goad the target into attacking you. Add the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage roll. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have Disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Lunging Attack.</b></i> As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die and take the Dash action. If you move at least 5 feet in a straight line immediately before hitting with a melee attack as part of the Attack action on this turn, you can add the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Maneuvering Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to maneuver one of your comrades into another position. Add the Superiority Die roll to the attack’s damage roll, and choose a willing creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its Reaction to move up to half its Speed without provoking an Opportunity Attack from the target of your attack.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Menacing Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to frighten the target. Add the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage roll. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Parry.</b></i> When another creature damages you with a melee attack roll, you can take a Reaction and expend one Superiority Die to reduce the damage by the number you roll on your Superiority Die plus your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Precision Attack.</b></i> When you miss with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die, roll that die, and add it to the attack roll, potentially causing the attack to hit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Pushing Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to drive the target back. Add the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed up to 15 feet directly away from you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Rally.</b></i> As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die to bolster the resolve of a companion. Choose an ally of yours within 30 feet of yourself who can see or hear you. That creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to the Superiority Die roll plus half your Fighter level (round down).</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Riposte.</b></i> When a creature misses you with a melee attack roll, you can take a Reaction and expend one Superiority Die to make a melee attack roll with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike against the creature. If you hit, add the Superiority Die to the attack’s damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Sweeping Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with a melee attack roll using a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to damage another creature. Choose another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to the number you roll on your Superiority Die. The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Tactical Assessment.</b></i> When you make an Intelligence (History or Investigation) check or a Wisdom (Insight) check, you can expend one Superiority Die and add that die to the ability check.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>Trip Attack.</b></i> When you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can expend one Superiority Die and add the die to the attack’s damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or have the Prone condition.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<!-- Combat Maneuvers -->
	<element name="Ambush" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_AMBUSH">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or an Initiative roll, you can expend one Superiority Die and add the die to the roll, unless you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or an Initiative roll and aren't Incapacitated, you can roll the die and add it to the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Bait and Switch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_BAIT_AND_SWITCH">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you're within 5 feet of a creature on your turn, you can expend one Superiority Die and switch places with that creature, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement and the creature is willing and doesn't have the Incapacitated condition. This movement doesn't provoke Opportunity Attacks.</p>
			<p class="indent">Roll the Superiority Die. Until the start of your next turn, you or the other creature (your choice) gains a bonus to AC equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When you're within 5 feet of a willing creature without the Incapacitated condition on your turn, you can switch places with that creature, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement. This movement doesn't provoke Opportunity Attacks. &#13;
			Until the start of your next turn, you or the other creature (your choice) gains a bonus to AC equal to a roll of Superiority Die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Commander’s Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_COMMANDERS_STRIKE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a willing creature who can see or hear you and expend one Superiority Die. That creature can immediately use its Reaction to make one attack with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, adding the Superiority Die to the attack's damage roll on a hit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>You can replace one of your attacks to direct one of your companions to strike. Choose a willing creature who can see or hear you. That creature can immediately use its Reaction to make one attack with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, adding the die to the attack's damage roll on a hit.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Commanding Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_COMMANDING_PRESENCE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make a Charisma (Intimidation, Performance, or Persuasion) check, you can expend one Superiority Die and add that die to the roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When you make a Charisma (Intimidation, Performance, or Persuasion) check, you can roll the die and add it to the check.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Disarming Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_DISARMING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to disarm the target. Add the Superiority Die roll to the attack's damage roll. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or drop one object of your choice that it's holding, with the object landing in its space.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can attempt to disarm the target. Add the die to the attack's damage roll. The target must succeed on a DC{{combat superiority:dc}} Strength saving throw or drop one object of your choice that it's holding, with the object landing in its space.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Distracting Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_DISTRACTING_STRIKE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to distract the target. Add the Superiority Die roll to the attack's damage roll. The next attack roll against the target by an attacker other than you has Advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On hit, you can distract the target. Add the die to the attack's damage roll. The next attack roll against the target by an attacker other than you has Advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Evasive Footwork" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_EVASIVE_FOOTWORK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die and take the Disengage action. You also roll the die and add the number rolled to your AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>Take the Disengage action. You also roll the die and add the number rolled to your AC until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Feinting Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_FEINTING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die to feint, choosing one creature within 5 feet of yourself as your target. You have Advantage on your next attack roll against that target this turn. If that attack hits, add the Superiority Die to the attack's damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>Choose one creature within 5 feet of yourself as your target. You have Advantage on your next attack roll against that target this turn. If that attack hits, add the die to the attack's damage roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Goading Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_GOADING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to goad the target into attacking you. Add the Superiority Die to the attack's damage roll. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have Disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On hit, add the die to the attack's damage roll. The target must then succeed on a DC{{combat superiority:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or have Disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Lunging Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_LUNGING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die and take the Dash action. If you move at least 5 feet in a straight line immediately before hitting with a melee attack as part of the Attack action on this turn, you can add the Superiority Die to the attack's damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>Take the Dash action. If you move at least 5 feet in a straight line immediately before hitting with a melee attack as part of the Attack action on this turn, you can add the die to the attack's damage roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Maneuvering Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_MANEUVERING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to maneuver one of your comrades into another position. Add the Superiority Die roll to the attack's damage roll, and choose a willing creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its Reaction to move up to half its Speed without provoking an Opportunity Attacks from the target of your attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On hit, you add the die to the attack's damage roll, and choose a willing creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its Reaction to move up to half its Speed without provoking an Opportunity Attacks from the target of your attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Menacing Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_MENACING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to frighten the target. Add the Superiority Die to the attack's damage roll. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On hit, you add the die to the attack's damage roll. The target must then succeed on a DC{{combat superiority:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Parry" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_PARRY">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When another creature damages you with a melee attack roll, you can take a Reaction and expend one Superiority Die to reduce the damage by the number you roll on your Superiority Die plus your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When another creature damages you with a melee attack roll, you can reduce the damage by 1d{{combat superiority:dice size}} (Superiority Die) + {{combat superiority:dc:ability}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Precision Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_PRECISION_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you miss with an attack roll, you can expend one Superiority Die, roll that die, and add it to the attack roll, potentially causing the attack to hit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When you miss with an attack roll, you can add the Superiority Die to the attack roll, potentially causing the attack to hit.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Pushing Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_PUSHING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to drive the target back. Add the Superiority Die to the attack's damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed up to 15 feet directly away from you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On hit with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you add the die to the attack's damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a DC{{combat superiority:dc}} Strength saving throw or be pushed up to 15 feet directly away from you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Rally" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_RALLY">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a Bonus Action, you can expend one Superiority Die to bolster the resolve of a companion. Choose an ally of yours within 30 feet of yourself who can see or hear you. That creature gains Temporary Hit Points equal to the Superiority Die roll plus half your Fighter level (round down).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>Choose an ally within 30 feet of yourself who can see or hear you. That creature gains 1d{{combat superiority:dice size}} (Superiority Die) + {{level:fighter:half}} Temporary Hit Points.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Riposte" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_RIPOSTE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When a creature misses you with a melee attack roll, you can take a Reaction and expend one Superiority Die to make a melee attack roll with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike against the creature. If you hit, add the Superiority Die to the attack's damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When a creature misses you with a melee attack, you can make a melee attack roll with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike against the creature. If you hit, add the die to the attack's damage roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sweeping Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_SWEEPING_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with a melee attack roll using a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can expend one Superiority Die to attempt to damage another creature. Choose another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to the number you roll on your Superiority Die. The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On a melee hit with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can attempt to damage another creature of your choice within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes the weapon's damage equal to the number you rolled on your Superiority Die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Tactical Assessment" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_TACTICAL_ASSESSMENT">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make an Intelligence (History or Investigation) check or a Wisdom (Insight) check, you can expend one Superiority Die and add that die to the ability check.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>When you make an Intelligence (History or Investigation) check or a Wisdom (Insight) check, you can add the die to the ability check.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Trip Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_TRIP_ATTACK">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you can expend one Superiority Die and add the die to the attack's damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or have the Prone condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Superiority Die">
			<description>On hit with a weapon or an Unarmed Strike, you add the die to the attack's damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a DC{{combat superiority:dc}} Strength saving throw or have the Prone condition.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!--Feature Replacement Grants-->
	<element name="Combat Superiority Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" />
	<element name="Student of War Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_STUDENT_OF_WAR" />
	<element name="Know Your Enemy Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_KNOW_YOUR_ENEMY" />
	<element name="Improved Combat Superiority Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" />
	<element name="Relentless Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_RELENTLESS" />
	<element name="Ultimate Combat Superiority Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_PHB24_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_FIGHTER_BATTLE_MASTER_ULTIMATE_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" />
</elements>
