<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Paladin</name>
		<description>The Paladin class from the Player’s Handbook.</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.3.3">
			<file name="class-paladin.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/players-handbook/classes/class-paladin.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Paladin" type="Class" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_PALADIN">
		<description>
			<p>Clad in plate armor that gleams in the sunlight despite the dust and grime of long travel, a human lays down her sword and shield and places her hands on a mortally wounded man. Divine radiance shines from her hands, the man’s wounds knit closed, and his eyes open wide with amazement.</p>
			<p class="indent">A dwarf crouches behind an outcrop, his black cloak making him nearly invisible in the night, and watches an orc war band celebrating its recent victory. Silently, he stalks into their midst and whispers an oath, and two orcs are dead before they even realize he is there.</p>
			<p class="indent">Silver hair shining in a shaft of light that seems to illuminate only him, an elf laughs with exultation. His spear flashes like his eyes as he jabs again and again at a twisted giant, until at last his light overcomes its hideous darkness.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whatever their origin and their mission, paladins are united by their oaths to stand against the forces of evil. Whether sworn before a god’s altar and the witness of a priest, in a sacred glade before nature spirits and fey beings, or in a moment of desperation and grief with the dead as the only witness, a paladin’s oath is a powerful bond. It is a source of power that turns a devout warrior into a blessed champion.</p>
			<h4>THE CAUSE OF RIGHTEOUSNESS</h4>
			<p>A paladin swears to uphold justice and righteousness, to stand with the good things of the world against the encroaching darkness, and to hunt the forces of evil wherever they lurk. Different paladins focus on various aspects of the cause of righteousness, but all are bound by the oaths that grant them power to do their sacred work. Although many paladins are devoted to gods of good, a paladin’s power comes as much from a commitment to justice itself as it does from a god. Paladins train for years to learn the skills of combat, mastering a variety of weapons and armor. Even so, their martial skills are secondary to the magical power they wield: power to heal the sick and injured, to smite the wicked and the undead, and to protect the innocent and those who join them in the fight for justice.</p>
			<h4>BEYOND THE MUNDANE LIFE</h4>
			<p>Almost by definition, the life of a paladin is an adventuring life. Unless a lasting injury has taken him or her away from adventuring for a time, every paladin lives on the front lines of the cosmic struggle against evil. Fighters are rare enough among the ranks of the militias and armies of the world, but even fewer people can claim the true calling of a paladin. When they do receive the call, these warriors turn from their former occupations and take up arms to fight evil. Sometimes their oaths lead them into the service of the crown as leaders of elite groups of knights, but even then their loyalty is first to the cause of righteousness, not to crown and country.</p>
			<p class="indent">Adventuring paladins take their work seriously. A delve into an ancient ruin or dusty crypt can be a quest driven by a higher purpose than the acquisition of treasure. Evil lurks in dungeons and primeval forests, and even the smallest victory against it can tilt the cosmic balance away from oblivion.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A PALADIN</h4>
			<p>The most important aspect of a paladin character is the nature of his or her holy quest. Although the class features related to your oath don't appear until you reach 3rd level, plan ahead for that choice by reading the oath descriptions at the end of the class. Are you a devoted servant of good, loyal to the gods of justice and honor, a holy knight in shining armor venturing forth to smite evil? A re you a glorious champion of the light, cherishing everything beautiful that stands against the shadow, a knight whose oath descends from traditions older than many of the gods? Or are you an embittered loner sworn to take vengeance on those who have done great evil, sent as an angel of death by the gods or driven by your need for revenge? Appendix B lists many deities worshiped by paladins throughout the multiverse, such as Torm, Tyr, Heironeous, Paladine, Kiri-Jolith, Dol Arrah, the Silver Flame, Bahamut, Athena, Re-Horakhty, and Heimdall.</p>
			<p class="indent">How did you experience your call to serve as a paladin? Did you hear a whisper from an unseen god or angel while you were at prayer? Did another paladin sense the potential within you and decide to train you as a squire? Or did some terrible event—the destruction of your home, perhaps— drive you to your quests? Perhaps you stumbled into a sacred grove or a hidden elven enclave and found yourself called to protect all such refuges of goodness and beauty. Or you might have known from your earliest memories that the paladin’s life was your calling, almost as if you had been sent into the world with that purpose stamped on your soul.</p>
			<p class="indent">As guardians against the forces of wickedness, paladins are rarely of any evil alignment. Most of them walk the paths of charity and justice. Consider how your alignment colors the way you pursue your holy quest and the manner in which you conduct yourself before gods and mortals. Your oath and alignment might be in harmony, or your oath might represent standards of behavior that you have not yet attained.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a paladin quickly by following these suggestions. First, Strength should be your highest ability score, followed by Charisma. Second, choose the noble background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a paladin, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per paladin level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per paladin level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two skills from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</li>
            </ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><i>(a)</i> a martial weapon and a shield or <i>(b)</i> two martial weapons</li>
				<li><i>(a)</i> five javelins or <i>(b)</i> any simple melee weapon</li>
				<li><i>(a)</i> a priest’s pack or <i>(b)</i> an explorer’s pack</li>
				<li>Chain mail and a holy symbol</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE PALADIN</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 1st</td><td class="left">Divine Sense, Lay on Hands</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 2nd</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Spellcasting, Divine Smite</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 3rd</td><td class="left">Divine Health, Sacred Oath</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td class="left">Aura of Protection</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td class="left">Sacred Oath feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td class="left">Aura of Courage</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td class="left">Improved Divine Smite</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td class="left">Cleansing Touch</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td class="left">Sacred Oath feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td class="left">Aura improvements</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td class="left">Sacred Oath feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_SENSE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_LAY_ON_HANDS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SPELLCASTING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_SMITE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_HEALTH" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SACRED_OATH" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_ASI" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_AURA_OF_PROTECTION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_AURA_OF_COURAGE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_IMPROVED_DIVINE_SMITE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_CLEANSING_TOUCH" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A holy warrior bound to a sacred oath.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A holy warrior bound to a sacred oath.</set>
			<set name="hd">d10</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Paladin)" supports="Skill,Paladin" number="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_SENSE" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_LAY_ON_HANDS" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_SMITE" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_HEALTH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SACRED_OATH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_ASI" level="4" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_AURA_OF_PROTECTION" level="6" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_AURA_OF_COURAGE" level="10" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_IMPROVED_DIVINE_SMITE" level="11" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_CLEANSING_TOUCH" level="14" />
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_PALADIN">
			<prerequisite>Strength 13 and Charisma 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>([str:13],[cha:13])</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="Divine Sense" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_SENSE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_DIVINE_SENSE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance). Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the <i>hallow</i> spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{divine sense:count}}/Long Rest" action="Action">
			<description>You can open your awareness to detect presence of strong evil. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity. Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="divine sense:count" value="1" />
			<stat name="divine sense:count" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Lay on Hands" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_LAY_ON_HANDS">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_LAY_ON_HANDS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x 5.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately for each one.</p>
			<p class="indent">This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="{{lay on hands:hp pool}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hp to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool. 
			You can expend 5 hp from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it.
			This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="lay on hands:hp pool" value="level:paladin" />
			<stat name="lay on hands:hp pool" value="level:paladin" />
			<stat name="lay on hands:hp pool" value="level:paladin" />
			<stat name="lay on hands:hp pool" value="level:paladin" />
			<stat name="lay on hands:hp pool" value="level:paladin" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_FIGHTING_STYLE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_FIGHTING_STYLE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">DEFENSE</h5>
			<p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">DUELING</h5>
			<p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
			<p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">PROTECTION</h5>
			<p>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style,Paladin" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SPELLCASTING">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_SPELLCASTING</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list.</p>
			<h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
			<p>The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your paladin spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
			<p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
			<p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
			</center>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
			<p>You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Paladin" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
			<list known="true">Paladin</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:prepare" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="paladin:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:paladin:half" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Divine Smite" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_SMITE">
		<requirements>!ID_KBP_DMBD_CLASS_FEATURE_ANTIPALADIN_UNHOLY_SMITE, !ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_DIVINE_SMITE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon’s damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend, to a maximum of 6d8.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon’s damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend, to a maximum of 6d8.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Divine Health" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_DIVINE_HEALTH">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_DIVINE_HEALTH</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sacred Oath" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SACRED_OATH">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_SACRED_OATH</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 3rd level, you swear the oath that binds you as a paladin forever. Up to this time you have been in a preparatory stage, committed to the path but not yet sworn to it. Now you choose the Oath of Devotion, the Oath of the Ancients, or the Oath of Vengeance, all detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 15th, and 20th level. Those features include oath spells and the Channel Divinity feature.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">OATH SPELLS</h5>
			<p>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you gain an oath spell that doesn’t appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">CHANNEL DIVINITY</h5>
			<p>Your oath allows you to channel divine energy to fuel magical effects. Each Channel Divinity option provided by your oath explains how to use it.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which option to use. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</p>
			<p class="indent">Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your paladin spell save DC.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your oath allows you to channel divine energy to fuel magical effects.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Sacred Oath" supports="Sacred Oath" />
			<stat name="channel divinity:count" value="1" level="1" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_ASI">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Paladin 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Paladin,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Paladin 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Paladin,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Paladin 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Paladin,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Paladin 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Paladin,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Paladin 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Paladin,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_EXTRA_ATTACK</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aura of Protection" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_AURA_OF_PROTECTION">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_AURA_OF_PROTECTION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you or a friendly creature within {{aura of protection:range}} feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a +{{aura of protection:save bonus}} bonus to the saving throw. You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="aura of protection:range" value="10" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="aura of protection:range" value="30" level="18" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="aura of protection:save bonus" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="aura of protection:save bonus" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aura of Courage" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_AURA_OF_COURAGE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_AURA_OF_COURAGE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can’t be frightened while you are conscious.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You and friendly creatures within {{aura of courage:range}} feet of you can’t be frightened while you are conscious.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="aura of courage:range" value="10" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="aura of courage:range" value="30" level="18" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Improved Divine Smite" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_IMPROVED_DIVINE_SMITE">
		<requirements>!ID_KBP_DMBD_CLASS_FEATURE_ANTIPALADIN_IMPROVED_UNHOLY_SMITE, !ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_IMPROVED_DIVINE_SMITE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry divine power with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Cleansing Touch" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_CLEANSING_TOUCH">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_CLEANSING_TOUCH</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action to end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="{{cleansing touch:count}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="cleansing touch:count" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="cleansing touch:count" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Feature Replacement Grants-->
	<element name="Divine Sense Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_DIVINE_SENSE" />
	<element name="Lay on Hands Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_LAY_ON_HANDS" />
	<element name="Fighting Style Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
	<element name="Spellcasting Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_SPELLCASTING" />
	<element name="Divine Smite Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_DIVINE_SMITE" />
	<element name="Divine Health Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_DIVINE_HEALTH" />
	<element name="Sacred Oath Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_SACRED_OATH" />
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
	<element name="Extra Attack Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
	<element name="Aura of Protection Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_AURA_OF_PROTECTION" />
	<element name="Aura of Courage Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_AURA_OF_COURAGE" />
	<element name="Improved Divine Smite Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_IMPROVED_DIVINE_SMITE" />
	<element name="Cleansing Touch Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_PALADIN_CLEANSING_TOUCH" />
</elements>
