<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Changeling from Monsters of the Multiverse</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-changeling.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/monsters-of-the-multiverse/race-changeling.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Changeling" type="Race" source="Monsters of the Multiverse" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACE_Changeling">
		<description>
			<p>With ever-changing appearances, changelings reside in many societies undetected. Each changeling can supernaturally adopt any face they like. For some changelings, a new face is only a disguise. For other changelings, a new face may reveal an aspect of their soul.</p>
			<p class="indent">The first changelings in the multiverse appeared in the Feywild, and the wondrous, mutable essence of that plane lingers in changelings today-even in those changelings who have never set foot in the fey realm. Each changeling decides how to use their shape-shifting ability, channeling either the peril or the joy of the Feywild. Sometimes they adopt new forms for the sake of mischief or malice, and other times they don a new identity to right wrongs or delight the downtrodden.</p>
			<p class="indent">In their true form, changelings appear faded, their features almost devoid of detail. It is rare to see a changeling in that form, for a typical changeling changes their shape the way others might change clothes. A casual shape—one created on the spur of the moment, with no depth or history—is called a mask. A mask can be used to express a mood or to serve a specific purpose and then might never be used again. However, many changelings develop identities that have more depth, crafting whole personas complete with histories and beliefs. A changeling adventurer might have personas for many situations, including negotiation, investigation, and combat.</p>
			<p class="indent">Personas can be shared by multiple changelings; a community might be home to three healer changelings, with whoever is on duty adopting the persona of Andrea, the gentle physician. Personas can even be passed down through a family, allowing a younger changeling to take advantage of contacts established by the persona's previous users.</p>
			<h4>CHANGELING TRAITS</h4>
			<p>As a changeling, you have the following racial traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creature Type.</em></strong> You are a Fey.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> You are Medium or Small. You choose the size when you select this race.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Changeling Instincts.</em></strong> Thanks to your connection to the fey realm, you gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Performance, or Persuasion.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shapechanger.</em></strong> As an action, you can change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height and weight and can change your size between Medium and Small. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of an individual you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait.</p>
			<p class="indent">You stay in the new form until you use an action to revert to your true form or until you die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Option (Changeling)" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size (Changeling)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_SMALL|ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_MEDIUM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_FEY" />

			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language (Changeling)" supports="Custom Race Language"  requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Changeling)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHANGELING_CHANGELING_INSTINCTS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHANGELING_SHAPECHANGER" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Changeling Instincts" type="Racial Trait" source="Monsters of the Multiverse" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHANGELING_CHANGELING_INSTINCTS">
		<description>
			<p>Thanks to your connection to the fey realm, you gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Performance, or Persuasion.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Changeling Instincts" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" number="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Customized Skill Proficiency (Changeling Instincts)" supports="Skill" number="2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shapechanger" type="Racial Trait" source="Monsters of the Multiverse" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHANGELING_SHAPECHANGER">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height and weight and can change your size between Medium and Small. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of an individual you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait.</p>
			<p class="indent">You stay in the new form until you use an action to revert to your true form or until you die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can change your appearance and your voice. You determine the specifics of the changes, including your coloration, hair length, and sex. You can also adjust your height and weight and can change your size between Medium and Small. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You can't duplicate the appearance of an individual you've never seen, and you must adopt a form that has the same basic arrangement of limbs that you have. Your clothing and equipment aren't changed by this trait.&#13;
			You stay in the new form until you use an action to revert to your true form or until you die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
