<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/monsters-of-the-multiverse/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- If WOTC continue referring to the book as "Mordenkainen Presents: Monsters of the Multiverse" we would change the source name to represent an actual title, for now, we decided to go with shorter version, same goes for folder and index names -->
	<element name="Monsters of the Multiverse" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_SOURCE_MONSTERS_OF_THE_MULTIVERSE">
		<description>
			<h5 style="margin-top:-1em">A bestiary of wondrous friends and foes for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</h5>
			<p>Sparkling with the musings of the wizard Mordenkainen, this tome features a host of creatures for use in the Dungeons &amp; Dragons roleplaying game. Hailing from every corner of the multiverse, these creatures represent some of the most benevolent and malevolent forces that D&amp;D heroes might face.</p>
			<p>The book also gathers together fantastical peoples from many different worlds. Each of these peoples represents a race option when you create your D&amp;D character, expanding on the choices in the <i>Player’s Handbook</i>.</p>
			<p>Compiling and updating monsters that originally appeared in <i>Volo’s Guide to Monsters</i> and <i>Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes</i>, this book presents friends and foes for any D&amp;D campaign, many of them accompanied by the comments of Mordenkainen. The wizard has faced many of these monsters and peoples on numerous wondrous adventures. Now it’s time for you to venture forth and face these creatures yourself!</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Includes over 250 monsters. Updates to the monsters include making spellcasters easier for Dungeon Masters to run; giving many monsters more damage and resilience; and improving the organization of the stat blocks themselves.</li>
				<li>Includes over 30 playable races. Brings all the game’s setting-agnostic races into one book, complementing the races in the <i>Player’s Handbook</i>.</li>
				<li>A multiverse of lore. Includes updates to monster lore that refocuses the stories on the D&amp;D multiverse, rather than on any particular world.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">MOTM</set>
			<set name="url">https://dnd.wizards.com/products/monsters-of-the-multiverse</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/monsters-of-the-multiverse/MOTM.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20220517</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
