<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wondrous Items</name>
		<description>Wondrous Items from Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn.</description>
		<author url="https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/en/product/1246491/adventures-in-faerun">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/forgotten-realms-adventures-in-faerun/items/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Calimemnon Crystal" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_CALIMEMNON_CRYSTAL">
		<description>
			<p>This immaculately cut sixty-sided diamond fits in one hand, yet it contains an entire genie empire. The <i>Calimemnon Crystal</i> was made by high elf magic to imprison the notorious genie lords Calim and Memnon, who once ruled and warred over what is now Calimshan.</p>
			<p class="indent">When viewed by a creature with <i>Truesight</i>, the normally beautiful diamond is a grotesque sight: trapped within the gemstone are more than a hundred genies, including the physical forms of Calim and Memnon. The genies scream and strain in agonized fury, pressing their belligerent faces against the walls of their crystal line prison.</p>
			<h5>PROPERTIES OF THE CRYSTAL</h5>
			<p>While attuned to the crystal, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Arcane Focus.</i></b> You can use the Calimemnon Crystal as an Arcane Focus.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight.</i></b> You have a Fly Speed of 30 feet and can hover.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells.</i></b> You can cast these spells with the crystal (spell save DC 18): <i>Create or Destroy Water</i>, <i>Enlarge/Reduce</i>, <i>Invisibility</i> (targeting yourself only), and <i>Major Image</i>.</p>
			<h5>AURA OF COLD</h5>
			<p>The temperature drops precipitously in a 20-foot Emanation originating from the crystal. Whenever the Emanation enters a creature's space and whenever a creature enters the Emanation or ends its turn there, the creature takes (2d6) Cold damage. A creature takes this damage only once per turn. While attuned to the crystal, you are unaffected by the aura, and you can take a Magic action to disable or enable the aura.</p>
			<h5>HEALING/DAMAGE RAYS</h5>
			<p>While holding the crystal, you can take a Magic action to fire six rays of volatile energy from the crystal at one or more creatures within 60 feet. You can aim the rays at one target or at several. For each ray, choose one of the following effects:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Damage Ray.</i></b> The target makes a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw, taking (6d6 + 6) Radiant damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Healing Ray.</i></b> The target regains 2d6 + 2 Hit Points.</p>
			<p class="indent">This property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<h5>RANDOM PROPERTIES</h5>
			<p>The Artifact has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>DESTROYING THE CRYSTAL</h5>
			<p>The <i>Calimemnon Crystal</i> is destroyed if the creature attuned to it casts the Wish spell and wishes the crystal destroyed. Nothing else can harm it. When the crystal is destroyed, all the genies in the crystal are released.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG24_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">—</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="30" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Crown of Horns" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_CROWN_OF_HORNS">
		<description>
			<p>The Crown of Horns contains the essence and intelligence of Myrkul, one of the Dead Three. This ghastly crown is a pale silver circlet with four curved bones set around its rim. On the crown's brow is set a black diamond whose depths swirl with weird, malignant energy.</p>
			<p class="indent">Myrkul created the <i>Crown of Horns</i> at the height of his power. When Myrkul was slain by Mystra, he imbued the crown with his dying essence. Myrkul has since returned to become one of the Dead Three, and the <i>Crown of Horns</i> continues to further his gruesome will by seeking out mortal agents and gradually transforming them into powerful Undead scions. Should a wearer prove unworthy of this honor, the crown teleports away to find a new mortal to corrupt for its master.</p>
			<h5>CURSED</h5>
			<p>The crown is cursed. Attuning to the crown extends the curse to you. Only a Wish spell or the will of Myrkul can remove this curse. As long as you remain cursed, the following properties apply to you:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Bound.</i></b> You are unwilling to part with the crown, wearing it at all times, and you can't voluntarily end your Attunement to the crown.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Cruel.</i></b> Your alignment becomes Neutral Evil.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Doomed.</i></b> You slowly transform into a monstrous servant of Myrkul over the course of 365 days. During that time, the transformation is purely cosmetic; these cosmetic changes slowly fade if you end Attunement to the crown before completing the transformation. When the transformation is complete, you become a Lich under the DM's control. Each time you use this Artifact's Cone of Undeath or Myrkul's Hand benefit, there is a 10 percent cumulative chance that you instantly complete this transformation.</p>
			<h5>CONE OF UNDEATH</h5>
			<p>You can take a Magic action to unleash a wave of unholy light in a 60-foot Cone. Each creature in the Cone makes a DC 18 Constitution saving throw, taking (4d8) Necrotic damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. A Humanoid killed by Cone of Undeath rises at the start of your next turn as a Specter that follows your verbal orders.</p>
			<h5>DAMAGE IMMUNITY</h5>
			<p>You have Immunity to Necrotic damage.</p>
			<h5>FEAR AURA</h5>
			<p>While wearing the crown, you emit an aura of terrifying energy in a 60-foot Emanation. A creature that enters this area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition. A Frightened target must use its movement on its turns to get as far away as possible from you, moving by the safest route.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you damage a Frightened target or if a Frightened target ends its turn more than 120 feet away from you, the target can repeat the Wisdom save, ending the condition on itself on a success. A creature that succeeds on the save against this effect is immune to it for 1 minute, after which it can be affected again.</p>
			<p class="indent">The aura is inactive while you have the Incapacitated condition. You can activate or deactivate the aura as a Bonus Action.</p>
			<h5>MYRKUL'S HAND</h5>
			<p>While wearing the crown, you can cast the <i>Power Word Kill</i> spell (save DC 18) from it. A Humanoid killed by this spell rises at the start of your next turn as a Wraith that follows your verbal orders. Once you use the crown to cast this spell, you can't cast it again from the crown until the next dawn.</p>
			<h5>TELEPORTATION</h5>
			<p>While wearing the crown, you can cast the <i>Teleport</i> spell. The crown can also cast this spell of its own free will. Once the spell has been cast using the crown, it can't be cast again until 7 days have passed.</p>
			<h5>RANDOM PROPERTIES</h5>
			<p>The Artifact has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>SENTIENCE</h5>
			<p>The <i>Crown of Horns</i> is a sentient Neutral Evil Artifact with an Intelligence of 10, a Wisdom of 16, and a Charisma of 19. It has hearing and Darkvision out to 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The crown communicates telepathically with its wearer and knows Common.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Personality.</i></b> The crown contains the essence of Myrkul and exists to spread that god's will, which is to slay the living, raise the dead, and sow fear across the Material Plane. The crown urges its wearer to spread dread and destruction wherever possible.</p>
			<h5>DESTROYING THE CROWN</h5>
			<p>The crown is destroyed if it is worn by Myrkul's successor, Kelemvor, while he sits on the throne of Myrkul's former realm, the Bone Castle.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_TELEPORT" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG24_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">—</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Alignment" id="ID_ALIGNMENT_NEUTRAL_EVIL" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_NECROTIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Harper Pin" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_HARPER_PIN">
		<description>
			<p>When you attune to this pin, choose a Harper persona, including an alignment and a creature type. While wearing this pin, you register as that persona when targeted by magic to determine your creature type, alignment, or location. The type of pin determines its rarity and effects.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Silver Harper Pin.</i></b> When you attune to this pin, you can devise a general line of thought of 25 words or fewer. While you wear this pin, a creature that reads your thoughts detects your preprogrammed line of thought instead. A creature that takes the Study action while reading your thoughts makes a DC 13 Intelligence (Investigation) check. On a successful check, it becomes aware that the detected thoughts are preprogrammed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Golden Harper Pin.</i></b> While wearing this pin, you can cast the <i>Nondetection</i> spell on yourself. The duration of this spell is permanent until you disable the effect (no action required), you remove the pin, or you are no longer attuned to the pin.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_NONDETECTION" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mechanical Wonder" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_MECHANICAL_WONDER">
		<description>
			<p>A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a semi-autonomous object imbued with magical power. <i>Mechanical Wonders</i> vary greatly in size and form depending on their function.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a dormant object until activated. To activate a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>, you must wind the wonder with a handheld key unique to that wonder. It takes 1 minute to wind a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>. While you wind it, you must take the Utilize action each turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once wound, a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> remains activated for the duration specified in the wonder’s description.</p>
			<h5>MECHANICAL WONDER OPTIONS</h5>
			<table class="indent">
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Type</td><td>Rarity</td><td>Cost</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<tr><td>Domestic Wonder</td><td>Uncommon</td><td>400gp</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Flying Wonder</td><td>Common</td><td>100gp</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Gyrocopter Wonder</td><td>Rare</td><td>4000gp</td></tr>
					<tr><td>Mobility Wonder</td><td>Common</td><td>100gp</td></tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">Varies</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">Varies</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity" />
		</setters>
	</element> 
	<element name="Mechanical Wonder (Flying)" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_FLYING_WONDER">
		<description>
			<p>A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a semi-autonomous object imbued with magical power. <i>Mechanical Wonders</i> vary greatly in size and form depending on their function.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a dormant object until activated. To activate a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>, you must wind the wonder with a handheld key unique to that wonder. It takes 1 minute to wind a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>. While you wind it, you must take the Utilize action each turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once wound, a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> remains activated for the duration specified in the wonder’s description.</p>
			<h5>FLYING WONDER</h5>
			<p>An activated flying wonder uses the <i>Flying Wonder</i> stat block. The wonder is an ally to you and your allies. In combat, the wonder shares your Initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its movement to avoid danger. The flying wonder is destroyed if it drops to 0 Hit Points.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_INFORMATION_FLYING_WONDER_STATBLOCK" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">—</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 
	<element name="Mechanical Wonder (Mobility)" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_MOBILITY_WONDER">
		<description>
			<p>A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a semi-autonomous object imbued with magical power. <i>Mechanical Wonders</i> vary greatly in size and form depending on their function.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a dormant object until activated. To activate a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>, you must wind the wonder with a handheld key unique to that wonder. It takes 1 minute to wind a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>. While you wind it, you must take the Utilize action each turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once wound, a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> remains activated for the duration specified in the wonder’s description.</p>
			<h5>MOBILITY WONDER</h5>
			<p>While inactive, the mobility wonder resembles a metal turtle shell with straps. It is designed to be worn on your back or flank, depending on your anatomy. Once wound, the mobility wonder transforms into a personal transport device and remains active for 24 hours. While active, the mobility wonder increases your Speed to 30 feet. Other creatures can’t remove your mobility wonder from you unless you allow it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">—</set>
			<set name="slot">back</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

	<element name="Orb of Damara" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_DAMARA">
		<description>
			<p>A wizard named Damara created this orb while devising a way to become a dragon. Aided by a mysterious magician (actually an aspect of Tiamat in disguise), Damara eventually created an Artifact that would enable him to achieve his dream. Yet the potential power of his creation terrified Damara so much that he dared not use the orb. Instead, the wizard entombed himself with the Artifact to seal it away.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <i>Orb of Damara</i> is about 6 inches in diameter and is made of a glassy, iridescent material that's like obsidian but incredibly hard. If held to one's own lips with the intention of consuming it, the orb shrinks to the size of a grape.</p>
			<h5>PROPERTIES OF THE ORB</h5>
			<p>While attuned to the orb, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Dragon's Breath.</i></b> You can take a Magic action to exhale a 15-foot Cone. When you do, choose Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Poison. Each creature in the Cone makes a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw, taking 6d6 damage of the chosen type on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fear Aura.</i></b> You exude a terrifying aura in a 20-foot Emanation while you don't have the Incapacitated condition. You can take a Magic action to disable or enable this aura. Any enemy that starts its turn in the aura must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition until the start of its next turn. A creature that succeeds on this save is immune to the aura's effects for 24 hours.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight.</i></b> You have a Fly Speed of 60 feet and can hover.</p>
			<h5>RANDOM PROPERTIES</h5>
			<p>The Artifact has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING</h5>
			<p>The orb has 6 charges and regains 1d4 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While attuned to the orb, you can cast one of the spells on the following table from it (+10 spell attack modifier, spell save DC 18). The table indicates how many charges you must expend to cast the spell.</p>
			<table class="indent">
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Spell</td><td>Charge Cost</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<tr><td><i>Disguise Self</i></td><td>0</td></tr>
					<tr><td><i>Fire Shield</i></td><td>2</td></tr>
					<tr><td><i>Hold Person</i></td><td>1</td></tr>
					<tr><td><i>See Invisibility</i></td><td>1</td></tr>
					<tr><td><i>Summon Dragon</i> (level 9 version)</td><td>4</td></tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			<h5>DRAGON TRANSFORMATION</h5>
			<p>If you swallow the orb, you transform into an adult chromatic dragon under the DM's control. The type of chromatic dragon depends on your alignment and personality and is left to the DM to decide. The transformation is permanent, but if the dragon is slain, its body reverts to its original form and the orb reappears outside its body.</p>
			<h5>DESTROYING THE ORB</h5>
			<p>If an Ancient Gold Dragon willingly swallows the orb, the orb and the dragon are both destroyed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_SUMMON_DRAGON" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG24_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">—</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="60" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tome of the Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_MAGIC_ITEM_TOMB_OF_THE_DRAGON">
		<description>
			<p>This heavy tome is bound in dragonhide and reinforced with thick bands of cold iron. The original copies were made by wyrmspeakers of the Cult of the Dragon and bear that cult's symbol on their cover. The <i>Tome of the Dragon</i> contains the secret ritual to transform a dragon or a dead dragon's body into a dracolich.</p>
			<p class="indent">To decipher and use the <i>Tome of the Dragon</i>, you must be either a spellcaster with at least two level 5 spell slots or a Dragon. A single assistant (or more, at the DM's discretion) can help you conduct the ritual, so long as that assistant also meets the requirements to use the tome.</p>
			<p class="indent">To create a dracolich using a <i>Tome of the Dragon</i>, you must have continuous access to the body of an adult or ancient dragon (either living or dead), as well as 80,000 GP worth of supplies (which includes a gem that will serve as the anchor for the dracolich's spirit). While you have the necessary materials, you must conduct a ritual that lasts 180 days divided by the number of creatures conducting the ritual. During the ritual, you and any assistants must work without interruption, resting no more than 8 hours per day. If you are a Dragon, the cost of supplies and the ritual's duration are halved.</p>
			<p class="indent">When the ritual is complete, the tome explodes with violet light, dealing (12d6) Necrotic damage to you and each assistant. If this damage reduces a creature to 0 Hit Points, the creature is killed and immediately reanimates as a Zombie under the DM's control.</p>
			<p class="indent">At the end of the ritual, the target transforms into a Dracolich. If the ritual's target was a living dragon, that dragon dies instantly, and its spirit is transferred to the gem supplied for the ritual. If the target was a dead dragon's body, the body reanimates, and the gem is inhabited by an evil dragon spirit from the Outer Planes. The dracolich is under no obligation toward its creators and acts according to its nature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">20000</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Flying Wonder Information Statblock -->
	<element name="Flying Wonder" type="Information" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_INFORMATION_FLYING_WONDER_STATBLOCK">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p><i>Tiny Construct, Unaligned</i></p>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
			<li><b>AC</b> 12</li>
			<li><b>HP</b> 2 (1d4)</li>
			<li><b>Speed</b> 5 ft., Fly 30 ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center">
				<thead><tr><td> </td><td> </td><td>MOD</td><td>SAVE</td><td> </td><td> </td><td>MOD</td><td>SAVE</td><td> </td><td> </td><td>MOD</td><td>SAVE</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>STR</td><td>2</td><td>-4</td><td>-4</td><td>DEX</td><td>15</td><td>+2</td><td>+2</td><td>CON</td><td>10</td><td>+0</td><td>+0</td></tr>
				<tr><td>INT</td><td>2</td><td>-4</td><td>-4</td><td>WIS</td><td>10</td><td>+0</td><td>+0</td><td>CHA</td><td>1</td><td>-5</td><td>-5</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><b>Immunities</b> Poison, Exhaustion, Poisoned</li>
				<li><b>Senses</b> Blindsight 60 ft., Passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><b>Languages</b> Understands Common but can’t speak</li>
				<li><b>CR</b> 0 (XP 10; PB +2)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 class="caption">TRAITS</h4>
			<p><b><i>Increased Carrying Capacity. </i></b> The wonder can carry up to 100 pounds.</p>
			<p><b><i>Wind-Up Operation. </i></b> The wonder has the Unconscious condition until another creature winds it with the wonder's unique key for 1 minute. Once wound, the wonder operates for 24 hours or until a creature touches the wonder with its key as a Utilize action to deactivate it, after which the wonder has the Unconscious condition until it is wound again.</p>
			<h4 class="caption">BONUS ACTIONS</h4>
			<p><b><i>Chime. </i></b> The wonder chirps a merry, metronomic tune. The wonder chooses one ally that it can see within 60 feet. Until the start of the wonder's next turn, the target has Advantage on the next ability check it makes with a Musical Instrument or Tinker's Tools.</p>
			<p><b><i>Sprint. </i></b> The wonder takes the Dash action.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

<!-- Flying Wonder Companion -->
	<element name="Flying Wonder" type="Companion" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_DOMESTIC_WONDER">
		<description>
			<p>A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a semi-autonomous object imbued with magical power. <i>Mechanical Wonders</i> vary greatly in size and form depending on their function.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> is a dormant object until activated. To activate a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>, you must wind the wonder with a handheld key unique to that wonder. It takes 1 minute to wind a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i>. While you wind it, you must take the Utilize action each turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once wound, a <i>Mechanical Wonder</i> remains activated for the duration specified in the wonder’s description.</p>
			<h5>FLYING WONDER</h5>
			<p>An activated flying wonder uses the Flying Wonder stat block. The wonder is an ally to you and your allies. In combat, the wonder shares your Initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its movement to avoid danger. The flying wonder is destroyed if it drops to 0 Hit Points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="strength">2</set>
			<set name="dexterity">15</set>
			<set name="constitution">10</set>
			<set name="intelligence">3</set>
			<set name="wisdom">10</set>
			<set name="charisma">1</set>
			<set name="ac">12</set>
			<set name="hp">2 (1d4)</set>
			<set name="speed">5 ft., Fly 30 ft.</set>
			<set name="skills" />
			<set name="immunities">Poison, Exhaustion, Poisoned</set>
			<set name="senses">Blindsight 60 ft., Passive Perception 10</set>
			<set name="languages">Understands Common but can’t speak</set>
			<set name="type">Construct</set>
			<set name="size">Tiny</set>
			<set name="alignment">unaligned</set>
			<set name="challenge">0</set>
			<set name="proficiency">2</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_TRAIT_FLYING_WONDER_INCREASED_CARRYING_CAPACITY,ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_TRAIT_FLYING_WONDER_WINDUP_OPERATION</set>
			<set name="bonusActions">ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_BONUS_ACTION_FLYING_WONDER_CHIME,ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_BONUS_ACTION_FLYING_WONDER_SPRINT</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="2" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="5" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:speed:fly" value="30" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Increased Carrying Capacity" type="Companion Trait" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_TRAIT_FLYING_WONDER_INCREASED_CARRYING_CAPACITY">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The wonder can carry up to 100 pounds.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The wonder can carry up to 100 pounds.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Wind-Up Operation" type="Companion Trait" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_TRAIT_FLYING_WONDER_WINDUP_OPERATION">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The wonder has the Unconscious condition until another creature winds it with the wonder's unique key for 1 minute. Once wound, the wonder operates for 24 hours or until a creature touches the wonder with its key as a Utilize action to deactivate it, after which the wonder has the Unconscious condition until it is wound again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The wonder has the Unconscious condition until another creature winds it with the wonder's unique key for 1 minute. Once wound, the wonder operates for 24 hours or until a creature touches the wonder with its key as a Utilize action to deactivate it, after which the wonder has the Unconscious condition until it is wound again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Chime" type="Companion Bonus Action" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_BONUS_ACTION_FLYING_WONDER_CHIME">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The wonder chirps a merry, metronomic tune. The wonder chooses one ally that it can see within 60 feet. Until the start of the wonder's next turn, the target has Advantage on the next ability check it makes with a Musical Instrument or Tinker's Tools.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The wonder chirps a merry, metronomic tune. The wonder chooses one ally that it can see within 60 feet. Until the start of the wonder's next turn, the target has Advantage on the next ability check it makes with a Musical Instrument or Tinker's Tools.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sprint" type="Companion Bonus Action" source="Forgotten Realms: Adventures in Faerûn" id="ID_WOTC_FRAIF_COMPANION_BONUS_ACTION_FLYING_WONDER_SPRINT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The wonder takes the Dash action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The wonder takes the Dash action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
