<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Items</name>
		<description>The Items from Candlekeep Mysteries</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/candlekeep-mysteries">Candlekeep Mysteries</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/candlekeep-mysteries/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Alchemy Jug (Blue)" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_ALCHEMY_JUG_BLUE"> <!--pg 144-->
		<description>
			<p>This ceramic jug appears to be able to hold a gallon of liquid and weighs 12 pounds whether full or empty. Sloshing sounds can be heard from within the jug when it is shaken, even if the jug is empty.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action and name one liquid from the table below to cause the jug to produce the chosen liquid. Afterward, you can uncork the jug as an action and pour that liquid out, up to 2 gallons per minute. The maximum amount of liquid the jug can produce depends on the liquid you named.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the jug starts producing a liquid, it can't produce a different one, or more of one that has reached its maximum, until the next dawn.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Liquid</td><td>Max Amount</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Beer</td><td>4 gallons</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Boiling Hot Tea</td><td>1 quart</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Honey</td><td>1 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Mayonnaise</td><td>2 gallons</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Oil</td><td>1 quart</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Vinegar</td><td>2 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Water, fresh</td><td>8 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Water, salt</td><td>12 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Wine</td><td>1 gallon</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">liquid</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="12">12 lb.</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Alchemy Jug (Orange)" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_ALCHEMY_JUG_ORANGE"> <!--pg 144-->
		<description>
			<p>This ceramic jug appears to be able to hold a gallon of liquid and weighs 12 pounds whether full or empty. Sloshing sounds can be heard from within the jug when it is shaken, even if the jug is empty.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action and name one liquid from the table below to cause the jug to produce the chosen liquid. Afterward, you can uncork the jug as an action and pour that liquid out, up to 2 gallons per minute. The maximum amount of liquid the jug can produce depends on the liquid you named.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the jug starts producing a liquid, it can't produce a different one, or more of one that has reached its maximum, until the next dawn.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Liquid</td><td>Max Amount</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Beer</td><td>4 gallons</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Honey</td><td>1 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Mayonnaise</td><td>2 gallons</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Oil</td><td>1 quart</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Soy Sauce</td><td>1 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Vinegar</td><td>2 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Water, fresh</td><td>8 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Water, salt</td><td>12 gallon</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Wine</td><td>1 gallon</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">liquid</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="12">12 lb.</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Cracked Driftglobe" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_CRACKED_DRIFTGLOBE"> <!--pg 110-->
		<description>
			<p>This small sphere of thick glass weighs 1 pound. If you are within 60 feet of it, you can speak its command word and cause it to emanate the light spell.</p>
			<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Gloves of Soul Catching" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_GLOVES_OF_SOUL_CATCHING"> <!--pg 169-->
		<description>
			<p>Your Constitution score is 20 while you wear these gloves. This property of the gloves has no effect on you if your Constitution is already 20 or higher.</p>
			<p class="indent">After making a successful unarmed strike while wearing these gloves, you can use the gloves to deal an extra 2d10 force damage to the target, and you regain a number of hit points equal to the force damage dealt. Alternatively, instead of regaining hit points in this way, you can choose to gain advantage on one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make before the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution:score:set" value="20" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
 
	<element name="Nether Scroll of Azumar" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_NETHER_SCROLL_OF_AZUMAR"> <!--pg 210-->
		<description>
			<p>Unlike most scrolls, a Nether Scroll of Azumar is not a consumable magic item. It takes 30 days of concentrated study—at least 8 hours per day—to attempt to understand this scroll. After completing this study, you must make a DC 25 Intelligence (Arcana) check. If this check fails, you take 16d10 psychic damage, and you can attempt the check again after another 30 days of concentrated study.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you succeed on the check, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your Intelligence score increases by 2, to a maximum of 22. Once you gain this benefit, you can't use this scroll to increase your Intelligence again.</li>
				<li>You gain advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">When you gain the scroll's benefits, a stone golem magically appears in an unoccupied space within 60 feet of you and acts as your ally. If you die, the golem turns to dust.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_CM_INFORMATION_STONE_GOLEM_STATBLOCK" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">intelligence</set>
			<set name="category">Scrolls</set>
			<set name="type">Scroll</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<!-- consumable items that apply rules not implemented, equip this item as alternative to activate it -->
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence" value="2" />
			<stat name="intelligence:max" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Stone Golem" type="Information" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_INFORMATION_STONE_GOLEM_STATBLOCK">
		<description>
			<p><em>Large Construct</em></p>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 17 (natural armor)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 178 (17d10 + 85)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30 ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>22 (+6)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>3 (-4)</td><td>11 (+0)</td><td>1 (-5)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison, psychic, bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks that aren't adamantine</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 120 ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> understands the languages of its creator but can't speak</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 10 </li>
			</ul>
			<p><strong><em>Immutable Form.</em></strong> The golem is immune to any spell or effect that would alter its form.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Magic Resistance.</em></strong> The golem has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Magic Weapons.</em></strong> The golem's weapon attacks are magical.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">ACTIONS</h5>
			<p><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The golem makes two slam attacks.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Slam.</em></strong> <em>Melee Weapon Attack:</em> +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (3d8 + 6) bludgeoning damage.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Slow (Recharge 5–6).</em></strong> The golem targets one or more creatures it can see within 10 feet of it. Each target must make a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw against this magic. On a failed save, a target can't use reactions, its speed is halved, and it can't make more than one attack on its turn. In addition, the target can take either an action or a bonus action on its turn, not both. These effects last for 1 minute. A target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Orcus Figurine" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_ORCUS_FIGURINE"> <!--pg 44-->
		<description>
			<p>Carved from an ogre's petrified heart, the gray figurine depicts the Demon Prince of Undeath in ghastly detail, clutching his skull-topped wand in one hand and three severed heads by the hair in the other. The figurine smells like decaying flesh, and this scent is detectable out to a range of 5 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The figurine is a Tiny object with AC 17, 3 hit points, and immunity to all types of damage except radiant damage. A detect evil and good spell or similar magic reveals that the figurine has been desecrated. As long as it has at least 1 hit point, the figurine has the following magical properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Undead within 30 feet of the figurine can't be turned.</li>
				<li>Dead creatures within 30 feet of the figurine can't be brought back to life.</li>
				<li>A creature that holds the figurine while praying to Orcus for at least 1 hour has a 10 percent chance of summoning a smoky avatar of the demon lord. Once this avatar is summoned, it can't be summoned again for 30 days. Orcus's avatar has the statistics of a wraith except that it's chaotic evil. It attacks all non-undead creatures it encounters, and it disappears after 1 hour or when reduced to 0 hit points.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Radiance" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_RADIANCE"> <!--pg 87-->
		<description>
			<p>While holding this wand, you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls. In addition, you ignore half cover when making a spell attack. Radiance is in the form of an exquisite golden hand mirror.</p>
			<p class="indent">While surrounded by darkness, it sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius. A creature that is attuned to Radiance can use a bonus action while holding the mirror to cast the enhance ability spell, choosing itself and no other creature as the spell's target. Once this property of the wand is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wands</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="type">Wand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Serpent Scale Armor" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_SERPENT_SCALE_ARMOR"> <!--pg 98-->
		<description>
			<p>This suit of magic armor is made from shimmering scales. While wearing it, you can apply your full Dexterity modifier (instead of a maximum of +2) when determining your Armor Class. In addition, this armor does not impose disadvantage on your Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scale mail">Armor</set>
			<set name="stealth">none</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="armor">Scale Mail</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:dexterity:cap" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Serpent's Fang" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_SERPENTS_FANG"> <!--pg 98-->
		<description>
			<p>This single-edged magic sword is made from the scrimshawed fang of a giant serpent. Its hilt changes shape to adjust to the grasp of any creature that picks it up. The weapon deals an extra 1d10 poison damage to any target it hits.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Staff of Fate" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OF_FATE"> <!--pg 183-->
		<description>
			<p>This transparent crystal staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Altered Outcome.</em></strong> The staff has 6 charges. As a bonus action, you can expend 1 of the staff's charges to give yourself or one other creature that you can see a d4. The recipient can roll this d4 and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, damage roll, or saving throw it makes before the start of your next turn. If this extra die is not used before then, it is lost.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you expend the staff's last charge, roll a d20. On a roll of 9 or lower, the staff becomes a nonmagical quarterstaff that breaks the first time it scores a hit and deals damage. On a roll of 10 or higher, the staff regains 1d6 of its expended charges.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Stonky's Ring" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_STONKYS_RING"> <!--pg 132-->
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this ring, you can cast the telekinesis spell at will, but you can target only objects that aren't being worn or carried.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any character who attunes to the ring gains control of Stonky's creations, though the skitterwidgets ignore commands spoken more than 30 feet away from them.</p>
			<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Watchful Helm" type="Magic Item" source="Candlekeep Mysteries" id="ID_WOTC_CM_MAGIC_ITEM_WATCHFUL_HELM"> <!--pg 183-->
		<description>
			<p>While you wear this helm, you gain a +1 bonus to AC and remain aware of your surroundings even while you're asleep, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can cast the see invisibility spell from the helm. Once this property of the helm is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
