<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Adventures in the Forgotten Realms</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="adventures-in-the-forgotten-realms.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/misc/adventures-in-the-forgotten-realms.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_ADVENTURES_IN_THE_FORGOTTEN_REALMS">
		<description>
			<p>Two Red Wizards of Thay have undertaken a secret mission into the High Moors east of the Sword Coast. They are searching for something or someone. Whatever their goal out there in the cold and windswept hills, if the Red Wizards want to keep it secret then it is probably best uncovered swiftly for the good of everyone else. Even the mercenaries who escorted them into the wilderness earlier agree: someone should stop them.</p>
			<p class="indent">Pursuing the Red Wizards leads the adventurers to a barrow mound in the wild grasses of the High Moors. At the barrow, they discover the remnants of a wizards' sanctum still being plundered. The fate of its lore and treasures is up to the characters. Without caution, things may get out of hand.</p>
			<p class="indent">This <i>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</i> adventure is written to suit four to six characters of 8th level. With this text and the core D&amp;D manuals, you have everything you need to play. You may also benefit from the <i>Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide</i> to learn more about the High Moors of Faerûn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">AITFR</set>
			<set name="url">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/scarlet-flames-2021-06-30</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/misc/AitFR.jpg</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20210630</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--The Hidden Page-->
	
	<element name="Planar Key" type="Magic Item" source="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" id="ID_WOTC_AITFR_MAGIC_ITEM_PLANAR_KEY">
		<description>
			<p>This key is etched with sigils.</p>
			<p class="indent">A planar key begins existence with 1d4 + 1 charges and cannot regain charges. When the key's last charge is expended, the key's sigils and magic fade away, but the key remains.</p>
			<p class="indent">While touching the key, you can use your action to expend 1 charge and have the key cast <i>plane shift</i> limited to the key's predefined destination only. Each planar key links to a single destination defined when the key is made.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">plane shift</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/hidden-page-2021-07-07</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--A Verdant Tomb-->

	<element name="Linked Glyphs" type="Spell" source="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" id="ID_WOTC_AITFR_SPELL_LINKED_GLYPHS">
		<supports>Artificer, Bard, Cleric, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you inscribe a detection glyph that later activates a magical effect at the site of a separate, linked glyph. You inscribe the detection glyph either on a surface (such as a table or a section of floor or wall) or within an object that can be closed (such as a book, a scroll, or a treasure chest) to conceal the glyph. The glyph can cover an area no larger than 10 feet in diameter. If the surface or object is moved more than 10 feet from where you cast this spell, the detection glyph is broken, and the spell ends without being triggered.</p>
			<p class="indent">Both glyphs are nearly invisible, and finding either requires a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC.</p>
			<p class="indent">You decide what triggers the detection glyph when you cast this spell. For glyphs inscribed on a surface, the most typical triggers include touching or standing on the glyph, removing another object covering the glyph, approaching within a certain distance of the glyph, or manipulating the object on which the glyph is inscribed. For glyphs inscribed within an object, the most common triggers include opening that object, approaching within a certain distance of the object, or seeing or reading the glyph. Once a glyph is triggered, this spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can further refine the trigger so the spell activates only under certain circumstances or according to physical characteristics (such as height or weight), creature kind (for example, the ward could be set to affect aberrations or drow), or alignment. You can also set conditions for creatures that don't trigger the glyph, such as those who say a certain password.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you inscribe the detection glyph, choose an alarm glyph or spell glyph to link to it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Alarm Glyph. </i></b>You create and magically link two glyphs: a detection glyph and an effect glyph. Each of these two glyphs must stay within 100 miles of the other or the spell effect ends. When the detection glyph is triggered, the effect glyph reacts like an alarm spell, creating a mental ping in your mind if you are within 1 mile of the effect glyph. This ping awakens you if you are sleeping.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spell Glyph. </i></b>You create and magically link two glyphs: a detection glyph and an effect glyph. These two glyphs must be within 100 feet of each other. You can store a prepared spell of 4th level or lower in the effect glyph by casting it as part of creating the glyphs. The spell must target a single creature or an area. The spell being stored has no immediate effect when cast in this way. When the detection glyph is triggered, the spell stored in the effect glyph is cast. If the spell has a target, it targets the creature that triggered the glyph. If the spell affects an area, the area is centered on the effect glyph. If the spell summons hostile creatures or creates harmful objects or traps, they appear as close as possible to the effect glyph. If the spell requires concentration, it lasts until the end of its full duration.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels. </i></b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher to create a spell glyph, you can store any spell of up to the same level as the slot you use.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 hour</set>
			<set name="duration">Until dispelled or triggered</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">incense and powdered diamond worth at least 300 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/verdant-tomb-2021-07-14</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Mighty Fortress" type="Spell" source="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" id="ID_WOTC_AITFR_SPELL_MIGHTY_FORTRESS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A fortress of stone erupts from a square area of ground of your choice that you can see within range. The area is 120 feet on each side, and it must not have any buildings or other structures on it. Any creatures in the area are harmlessly lifted up as the fortress rises.</p>
			<p class="indent">The fortress has four turrets with square bases, each one 20 feet on a side and 30 feet tall, with one turret on each corner. The turrets are connected to each other by stone walls that are each 80 feet long, creating an enclosed area. Each wall is 1 foot thick and is composed of panels that are 10 feet wide and 20 feet tall. Each panel is contiguous with two other panels or one other panel and a turret. You can place up to four stone doors in the fortress’s outer wall.</p>
			<p class="indent">A small keep stands inside the enclosed area. The keep has a square base that is 50 feet on each side, and it has three floors with 10-foot-high ceilings. Each of the floors can be divided into as many rooms as you like, provided each room is at least 5 feet on each side. The floors of the keep are connected by stone staircases, its walls are 6 inches thick, and interior rooms can have stone doors or open archways as you choose. The keep is furnished and decorated however you like, and it contains sufficient food to serve a nine-course banquet for up to 100 people each day. Furnishings, food, and other objects created by this spell crumble to dust if removed from the fortress.</p>
			<p class="indent">A staff of one hundred invisible servants obeys any command given to them by creatures you designate when you cast the spell. Each servant functions as if created by the unseen servant spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The walls, turrets, and keep are all made of stone that can be damaged. Each 10 foot by-10-foot section of stone has AC 15 and 30 hit points per inch of thickness. It is immune to poison and psychic damage. Reducing a section of stone to 0 hit points destroys it and might cause connected sections to buckle and collapse at the DM’s discretion.</p>
			<p class="indent">After 7 days or when you cast this spell somewhere else, the fortress harmlessly crumbles and sinks back into the ground, leaving any creatures that were inside it safely on the ground.</p>
			<p class="indent">Casting this spell on the same spot once every 7 days for a year makes the fortress permanent.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">1 mile</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a diamond worth at least 500 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/verdant-tomb-2021-07-14</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Stone of Creation" type="Magic Item" source="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" id="ID_WOTC_AITFR_MAGIC_ITEM_STONE_OF_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>Rare legends and lore that speak of the <i>Stone of Creation</i> claim it fell to the Material Plane like a meteor from some distant edge of the Outer Planes or the Far Realm. Similar legends across various worlds, all describing stones that grow buildings and islands from magic, like a house from a seed, suggest the <i>Stone of Creation</i> is not a unique artifact—or that all the various pieces of it are derived from a single source of stone even larger than sages imagine.</p>
			<p class="indent">The raw, black stone appears flaky like slate but is as hard as granite and marbled with veins of gold and platinum. The original, complete <i>Stone of Creation</i> took the form of a blocky slab like a standing stone, but it may be impossible to know the Stone's true size, or if the concept of a "whole" <i>Stone of Creation</i> even applies to the artifact. Perhaps other slabs and boulders made from the Stone have been scattered across the multiverse, being cut down and recombed through interplanar movements and the magic of the artifacts themselves.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> The <i>Stone of Creation</i> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Stone Smithing.</em></strong> While attuned to the <i>Stone of Creation</i>, you are proficient with mason's tools and can use them to cut pieces from the Stone's slab, thereby creating lesser artifacts.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Cut into Pieces.</em></strong> The Stone of Creation is a source for smaller artifacts that derive their power from it. These pieces allow you to shape and bestow a portion of the slab's power for yourself or others.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can cut pieces in two general sizes: a <i>chip of creation</i> or a <i>keystone of creation</i>. These lesser artifacts require their own attunement.</p>
			<p class="indent">Up to eleven chips of creation can be created from the existing slab, plus up to nine keystones. A chip resembles a flake of rock about the size of an adult human's hand. A keystone is at least five times that thickness.</p>
			<p class="indent">When all chips and keystones have been cut away, a portion of the Stone remains but proves impervious to additional attempts to cut or chisel pieces from it. This smallest version of the Stone is the same size as a Tiny creature.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Raze or Reshape Creations.</em></strong> Although the <i>Stone of Creation</i> cannot create structures or demiplanes of its own, while you are attuned to it you can revise or renovate any structure or demiplane created by a keystone or chip, provided you are within 1 mile of the Stone and you can see or otherwise perceive the structure or demiplane. For example, you may add doors, seal windows, change the arrangement of rooms, or even dispel a structure created by a keystone. To do so, you must concentrate for 1 minute, as if on a spell, while picturing the changes you wish to make in your mind; over the course of that minute, the changes slowly occur. These changes cannot deal damage or directly harm a creature. A dispelled structure gradually recedes and diminishes to nothing, leaving creatures unharmed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying the Stone.</em></strong> The <i>Stone of Creation</i> is a strange artifact that can be divided into smaller artifacts, yet the Stone is impervious to most damage. Only the smith attuned to the Stone can carve it. Destroying the Stone's lesser, derived artifacts (and their creations) does no damage to the Stone itself.</p>
			<p class="indent">The <i>Stone of Creation</i> is destroyed if it reaches the Elemental Chaos or is struck with a forked metal rod attuned to the Elemental Chaos (as per the <i>plane shift</i> spell). The Stone then shatters into harmless, inert shards of rock. Places created by the slab's chips and keystones crumble, decay, or fade away to nothing after the Stone of Creation is destroyed. Whether the Stone of Creation is itself a piece of a larger artifact remains unknown.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/verdant-tomb-2021-07-14</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Chip of Creation" type="Magic Item" source="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" id="ID_WOTC_AITFR_MAGIC_ITEM_CHIP_OF_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>This solid, hand-sized flake of rock is a minor piece of the <i>Stone of Creation</i> and contains a portion of its power.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Linked Room.</em></strong> Each chip of creation is inextricably linked to its own demiplanar room, as per the demiplane spell. This room exists as long as both this <i>chip</i> and the <i>Stone of Creation</i> do. A door to the room only exists when created using a demiplane spell, whether a <i>chip of creation</i> is used in the casting or not.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Demiplane.</em></strong> While attuned to a <i>chip of creation</i>, you can cast demiplane at will but only to reach the demiplanar room associated with that <i>chip of creation</i> or another demiplane that you know the nature and contents of, and only if the target demiplane was created by another piece of the <i>Stone of Creation</i>.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying a Chip.</em></strong> A <i>chip of creation</i> is an artifact in its own right and impervious to most damage, but a disintegrate spell is sufficient to destroy it. After it has been attuned once, a chip that has gone 1d4 + 1 days unattuned becomes an inert, powerless bit of rock.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the <i>Stone of Creation</i> is destroyed, all its chips break attunement, lose all magical properties, and linked demiplanar rooms cease to exist at once. Creatures or objects within the room are instantly expelled into the immediate vicinity of the destroyed chip.</p>
			<p class="indent">If it reaches the Elemental Chaos or is struck by a forked, metal rod attuned to the Elemental Chaos (as per the <i>plane shift</i> spell), a chip is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">demiplane</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/verdant-tomb-2021-07-14</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Keystone of Creation" type="Magic Item" source="Adventures in the Forgotten Realms" id="ID_WOTC_AITFR_MAGIC_ITEM_KEYSTONE_OF_CREATION">
		<description>
			<p>A <i>keystone of creation</i> is a piece of the <i>Stone of Creation</i>, usually between 6 to 10 inches on a side, and can be rough-hewn or cleanly cut and polished by a mason attuned to the <i>Stone of Creation</i>.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> A <i>keystone of creation</i> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 beneficial manifestation</li>
				<li>1 detrimental manifestation</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Extradimensional Places.</em></strong> You can use the keystone to conjure an extradimensional space such as <i>Mordenkainen's magnificent mansion</i>. The easiest way is to simply cast the spell using the artifact's power, which requires no spell slots or material components. Each time you cast a spell with the artifact, the subsequent casting replaces the prior one. For more detailed control of a conjured demiplane or extradimensional space, see "Construction Details."</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Raising Structures.</em></strong> You can use the keystone to conjure a physical structure on the Material Plane. The easiest way is to simply cast the <i>mighty fortress</i> spell using the artifact's power, which requires no spell slots or material components. Each time you cast a spell with the artifact, the subsequent casting replaces the prior one. For more detailed control of a conjured demiplane or extradimensional space, see "Construction Details." Locations conjured by keystones cannot become permanent through repeated spell castings.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Connected Spaces.</em></strong> You can use multiple keystones to create larger spaces, whether adjacent to each other or even interlinked. You can even combine structures on the Material Plane and extradimensional spaces this way. If you are attuned to one keystone when you attune to a second keystone, the keystones combine to become a single artifact (utilizing a single attunement slot), combining their features and their fates forevermore. You cannot attune to, and thus combine, more than three keystones at once.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Destroying a Keystone.</em></strong> A keystone is an artifact in its own right and impervious to most damage, but a <i>disintegrate</i> spell is sufficient to destroy an unattuned keystone.</p>
			<p class="indent">After it has been attuned at least once, a given keystone requires attunement to maintain its magical power. Otherwise, its creations on the Material Plane gradually rot and decay over 1d12 + 1 days, and a demiplane relying on the keystone collapses over 1d20 + 10 minutes. Additional destructive forces like fire may hasten the destruction. A demiplane created or upheld by a keystone ejects all creatures within it to their home planes when it collapses.</p>
			<p class="indent">When a keystone's creation is fully destroyed, the keystone becomes an inert, powerless rock. If the <i>Stone of Creation</i> is destroyed, all its keystones break attunement, lose all magical properties, and their creations decay or collapse to nothing.</p>
			<p class="indent">If it reaches the Elemental Chaos or is struck by a forked, metal rod attuned to the Elemental Chaos (as per the <i>plane shift</i> spell), a keystone is destroyed.</p>
			<h4>Construction Details</h4>
			<p>You can customize a keystone's creation with cosmetic details you can imagine. You can also rearrange the floorplans and structural details of your creations as follows.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Demiplane Design.</em></strong> With a single keystone, you can conjure an extradimensional space in the shape of a dome or pyramid, up to 1 mile on each side, with whatever terrain you wish. The edges of this space are solid and impassable but may be invisible, so that your space can appear to go on forever if you wish. With additional keystones, you can add an additional square mile to your creation, adding or combining terrain types.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each square mile can include a single structure up to the size of <i>Mordenkainen's magnificent mansion</i>, with all the attendant servants and feasts, or any number of smaller structures that together equal a magnificent mansion in total area.</p>
			<p class="indent">You cannot create flora or fauna that deal damage or otherwise harm creatures. If you create cliffs, waters, or other natural features, however, creatures in the space might fall, drown, or otherwise be harmed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Physical Structure Design.</em></strong> With a single keystone, you can create a structure akin to a mighty fortress with the added flexibility to customize that fortress not only for cosmetic details but for substantive effects. With a single keystone, you can rearrange the walls, open spaces, floors, doors, and other features of the mighty fortress provided you do not exceed 150 10-foot-wide cubes of interior space. Your fortress can reach across a creek, river, or other waters. It can take reckless or even dangerous shapes to include deep pits, flooded chambers, and so on. Your design, once conjured, is not guaranteed to be capable of supporting its own weight or surviving the stresses of attacks, weather, or time.</p>
			<p class="indent">You may post any number of your structure's servants as guards, if you wish. They have statistics identical to an unseen servant with the addition of a passive Perception score equal to your own, though you cannot perceive through their senses. The servants can ring bells or otherwise manipulate the environment to raise an alarm.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Manifestations.</em></strong> Each place or structure conjured by a <i>keystone of creation</i> has special, unforeseen manifestations that affect its makeup and appearance. Some manifestations are beneficial, some are detrimental. These manifestations change each time a keystone is used to conjure a structure or place. The DM may roll or choose from the following tables, or devise unique manifestations based on the specific creations being conjured.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/magic-story/verdant-tomb-2021-07-14</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	

</elements>
