<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic</name>
		<description>Taking a new look at the tiefling race, this article breaks down the Player’s Handbook tiefling into a modular variant, allowing players to create tiefling characters tied to either a diabolic or a demonic ancestry. Additionally, a new suite of conjuration spells allows casters to call forth demons to do their bidding.</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/old-black-magic">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="20151207.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2015/20151207.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20151207">
		<description>
			<p>Taking a new look at the tiefling race, this article breaks down the Player’s Handbook tiefling into a modular variant, allowing players to create tiefling characters tied to either a diabolic or a demonic ancestry. Additionally, a new suite of conjuration spells allows casters to call forth demons to do their bidding.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20151207</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/old-black-magic</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20151207</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Tiefling Variant -->
	<element name="Abyssal Tiefling" type="Sub Race" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_SUBRACE_TIEFLING_ABYSSAL">
		<supports>Tiefling</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As presented in the Player’s Handbook, all members of the tiefling race share some manner of diabolic origin. The following option allows you to instead create a tiefling with a demonic tie.</p>
			<p class="indent">All abyssal tieflings trace their bloodline to the demons of the Abyss. These tieflings have the following additional features.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase.</i></b> Your Constitution score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Abyssal Arcana.</i></b> Each time you finish a long rest, you gain the ability to cast cantrips and spells randomly determined from a short list. At 1st level, you can cast a cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can also cast a 1st-level spell. At 5th level, you can cast a 2nd-level spell</p>
			<p class="indent">You can cast a spell gained from this trait only once until you complete your next long rest. You can cast a cantrip gained from this trait at will, as normal. For 1st-level spells whose effect changes if cast using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you cast the spell as if using a 2nd-level slot. Spells of 2nd level are cast as if using a 2nd-level slot. </p>
			<p class="indent">At the end of each long rest, you lose the cantrips and spells previously granted by this feature, even if you did not cast them. You replace those cantrips and spells by rolling for new ones on the Abyssal Arcana Spells table. Roll separately for each cantrip and spell. If you roll the same spell or cantrip you gained at the end of your previous long rest, roll again until you get a different result.</p>
			<p class="caption">Abyssal Arcana Spells</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>1st Level</td><td>3rd Level</td><td>5th Level</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td><em>Dancing lights</em></td><td><em>Burning hands</em></td><td><em>Alter self</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td><em>True strike</em></td><td><em>Charm person</em></td><td><em>Darkness</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td><em>Light</em></td><td><em>Magic missle</em></td><td><em>Invisibility</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td><em>Message</em></td><td><em>Cure wounds</em></td><td><em>Levitate</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td><em>Spare the dying</em></td><td><em>Tasha's hideous laughter</em></td><td><em>Mirror image</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td><em>Prestidigitation</em></td><td><em>Thunderwave</em></td><td><em>Spider climb</em></td></tr>
			</table>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Abyssal Fortitude.</i></b> Your hit point maximum increases by half your level (minimum 1).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Languages.</i></b> You can speak, read, and write Abyssal.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_TIEFLING_SUBRACE" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_LANGUAGE_REPLACEMENT_TIEFLING_INFERNAL" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_REPLACEMENT_TIEFLING_HELLISH_RESISTANCE" />
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<stat name="constitution" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +2 (Abyssal Tiefling)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Abyssal Tiefling)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_RACIAL_TRAIT_ABYSSAL_ABYSSAL_ARCANA" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_RACIAL_TRAIT_ABYSSAL_ABYSSAL_FORTITUDE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Abyssal Arcana" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_RACIAL_TRAIT_ABYSSAL_ABYSSAL_ARCANA">
		<description>
			<p>Each time you finish a long rest, you gain the ability to cast cantrips and spells randomly determined from a short list. At 1st level, you can cast a cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can also cast a 1st-level spell. At 5th level, you can cast a 2nd-level spell</p>
			<p class="indent">You can cast a spell gained from this trait only once until you complete your next long rest. You can cast a cantrip gained from this trait at will, as normal. For 1st-level spells whose effect changes if cast using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you cast the spell as if using a 2nd-level slot. Spells of 2nd level are cast as if using a 2nd-level slot. </p>
			<p class="indent">At the end of each long rest, you lose the cantrips and spells previously granted by this feature, even if you did not cast them. You replace those cantrips and spells by rolling for new ones on the Abyssal Arcana Spells table. Roll separately for each cantrip and spell. If you roll the same spell or cantrip you gained at the end of your previous long rest, roll again until you get a different result.</p>
			<p class="caption">Abyssal Arcana Spells</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>1st Level</td><td>3rd Level</td><td>5th Level</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td><em>Dancing lights</em></td><td><em>Burning hands</em></td><td><em>Alter self</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td><em>True strike</em></td><td><em>Charm person</em></td><td><em>Darkness</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td><em>Light</em></td><td><em>Magic missle</em></td><td><em>Invisibility</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td><em>Message</em></td><td><em>Cure wounds</em></td><td><em>Levitate</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td><em>Spare the dying</em></td><td><em>Tasha's hideous laughter</em></td><td><em>Mirror image</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td><em>Prestidigitation</em></td><td><em>Thunderwave</em></td><td><em>Spider climb</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you finish a long rest, roll on the Abyssal Arcana Spells table to determine your random cantrip, this cantrip can be cast at will. You lose cantrip previously granted by this feature when you finish a long rest. If you roll the same cantrip you gained at the end of your previous long rest, roll again until you get a different result.</description>
			<description level="3">Whenever you finish a long rest, roll on the Abyssal Arcana Spells table to determine your random cantrip and 1st-level spell, rolling separately for each. You can cast cantrip at will. You can also cast a 1st-level spell once (if the rolled spell can be used with a higher level slots, you cast it at the 2nd-level). You lose cantrip and spell previously granted by this feature when you finish a long rest. If you roll the same cantrip or spell you gained at the end of your previous long rest, roll again until you get a different result.</description>
			<description level="5">Whenever you finish a long rest, roll on the Abyssal Arcana Spells table to determine your random cantrip, and spells of 1st and 2nd level, rolling separately for each. You can cast cantrip at will. You can also cast each spell once (if the rolled spell of 1st-level can be used with a higher level slots, you cast it at the 2nd-level). You lose cantrip and spells previously granted by this feature when you finish a long rest. If you roll the same cantrip or spell you gained at the end of your previous long rest, roll again until you get a different result.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Abyssal Fortitude" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_RACIAL_TRAIT_ABYSSAL_ABYSSAL_FORTITUDE">
		<description>
			<p>Your hit point maximum increases by half your level (minimum 1).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="abyssal fortitude:hp" value="level:half" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="abyssal fortitude:hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="hp" value="abyssal fortitude:hp" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Spells -->
	<element name="Conjure Barlgura" type="Spell" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_SPELL_CONJURE_BARLGURA">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a barlgura that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The barlgura disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">The barlgura is hostile to all non-­demons. Roll initiative for the barlgura, which has its own turns. At the start of its turn, it moves toward and attacks the nearest non-­demon it can perceive. If two or more creatures are equally near, it picks one at random. If it cannot see any potential enemies, the barlgura moves in a random direction in search of foes.</p>
			<p class="indent">As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned barlgura cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">summon, demon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Conjure Hezrou" type="Spell" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_SPELL_CONJURE_HEZROU">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a hezrou that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The hezrou disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">The hezrou’s attitude depends on the value of the food used as a material component for this spell. Roll initiative for the hezrou, which has its own turns. At the start of the hezrou’s turn, the DM makes a secret Charisma check on your behalf, with a bonus equal to the food’s value divided by 20. The check DC starts at 10 and increases by 2 each round. You can issue orders to the hezrou and have it obey you as long as you succeed on the Charisma check.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the check fails, the spell no longer requires concentration and the demon is no longer under your control. The hezrou then focuses on devouring any corpses it can see. If there are no such meals at hand, it attacks the nearest creatures and eats anything it kills. If its hit points are reduced to below half its hit point maximum, it returns to the Abyss.</p>
			<p class="indent">As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned hezrou cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">summon, demon</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">food worth at least 100 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Conjure Lesser Demon" type="Spell" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_SPELL_CONJURE_LESSER_DEMON">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon up to a total of eight manes or dretches that appear in unoccupied spaces you can see within range. A manes or dretch disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">The demons are hostile to all creatures. Roll initiative for the summoned demons as a group, which has its own turns. The demons attack the nearest non-demons to the best of their ability.</p>
			<p class="indent">As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground with the blood used as a material component. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned demons cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts. Using the material component in this manner consumes it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or 7th level, you summon sixteen demons. If you cast it using a spell slot of 8th or 9th level, you summon thirty-­two demons.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">summon, demon</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of blood from an intelligent humanoid killed within the past 24 hours</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Conjure Shadow Demon" type="Spell" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_SPELL_CONJURE_SHADOW_DEMON">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a shadow demon that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The shadow demon disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">Roll initiative for the shadow demon, which has its own turns. You can issue orders to the shadow demon, and it obeys you as long as it can attack a creature on each of its turns and does not start its turn in an area of bright light. If either of these conditions is not met, the shadow demon immediately makes a Charisma check contested by your Charisma check. If you fail the check, the spell no longer requires concentration and the demon is no longer under your control. The demon automatically succeeds on the check if it is more than 100 feet away from you.</p>
			<p class="indent">As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned shadow demon cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">summon, demon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of blood from an intelligent humanoid killed within the past 24 hours</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Conjure Vrock" type="Spell" source="Unearthed Arcana: That Old Black Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20151207_SPELL_CONJURE_VROCK">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a vrock that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The vrock disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">The vrock’s attitude depends on the value of the gem used as a material component for this spell. Roll initiative for the vrock, which has its own turns. At the start of the vrock’s turn, the DM makes a secret Charisma check on your behalf, with a bonus equal to the gem’s value divided by 20. The check DC starts at 10 and increases by 2 each round. You can issue orders to the vrock and have it obey you as long as you succeed on the Charisma check.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the check fails, the spell no longer requires concentration and the vrock is no longer under your control.The vrock takes no actions on its next turn and uses its telepathy to tell any creature it can see that it will fight in exchange for treasure. The creature that gives the vrock the most expensive gem can command it for the next 1d6 rounds. At the end of that time, it offers the bargain again. If no one offers the vrock treasure before its next turn begins, it attacks the nearest creatures for 1d6 rounds before returning to the Abyss.</p>
			<p class="indent">As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned vrock cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">summon, demon</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gem worth at least 100 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
