<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Weapons</name>
		<description>Magical Weapons from the Dungeon Master’s Guide 2024</description>
		<author url="https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/core-rules/3710000?pid=DB3710000">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/dungeon-masters-guide-2024/items/items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Weapon, +1" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_1">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} +{{enhancement}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon, +2" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_2">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} +{{enhancement}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon, +3" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_3">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} +{{enhancement}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Adamantine Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ADAMANTINE_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>This weapon is made of adamantine, one of the hardest substances in existence. Whenever this weapon or piece of ammunition hits an object, the hit is a Critical Hit.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Adamantine {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Axe of the Dwarvish Lords" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AXE_OF_THE_DWARVISH_LORDS">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A young dwarf prince set out to forge a weapon that would be regarded as a symbol of unity among his people. Venturing deep under the mountains, deeper than any dwarf had ever delved, the prince came to the blazing heart of a great volcano. With the aid of Moradin, a god of creation, he first crafted four mighty tools: the <i>Starmetal Pick</i>, the <i>Earthheart Forge</i>, the <i>Anvil of Songs</i>, and the <i>Shaping Hammer</i>. With these tools, he forged the <i>Axe of the Dwarvish Lords.</i></p>
			<p class="indent">Armed with the Artifact, the prince brought peace to the dwarf clans, ending grudges and answering slights. The clans became allies, and they threw back their enemies and enjoyed an era of prosperity. This young dwarf is remembered as the First King. When he became old, he passed the weapon, which had become his badge of office, to his heir. The rightful inheritors passed the axe on for many generations.</p>
			<p class="indent">Later, in an era marked by treachery and wickedness, the axe was lost in a bloody civil war fomented by greed for its power and the status it bestowed. Centuries later, the dwarves still search for the axe, and many adventurers have made careers of chasing after rumors and plundering old vaults to find it.</p>
			<p><b><i>Magic Weapon.</i></b> The <i>Axe of the Dwarvish Lords</i> is a magic weapon that grants a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with it.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you attack a creature with the axe and roll a 20 on the d20 for the attack roll, the axe deals an extra 20 Slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The axe has Thrown with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with a ranged attack using this weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 Force damage, or an extra 2d8 Force damage if the target is a creature of the Giant type. Immediately after hitting or missing, the weapon flies back to your hand.</p>
			<p><b><i>Blessings of Moradin.</i></b> While attuned to the axe, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Darkvision.</i></b> You gain Darkvision with a range of 60 feet. If you already have Darkvision, its range increases by 60 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fortitude of Stone.</i></b> Your Constitution increases by 2, to a maximum of 20.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Gifts of the Creator.</i></b> You have proficiency with Brewer's Supplies, Mason's Tools, and Smith's Tools.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>One with the Forge.</i></b> You have Immunity to Poison damage and Resistance to Fire damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sunder.</i></b> When you hit an object with the axe, the object takes the maximum amount of damage possible.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Conjure Earth Elemental.</i></b> While holding the axe, you can take a Magic action to summon an Earth Elemental. It appears in an unoccupied space you choose within 30 feet of yourself, understands your languages, obeys your commands, and takes its turn immediately after you on your Initiative count. The elemental disappears after 24 hours, when it dies, or when you dismiss it as a Bonus Action. You can't use this property again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> The axe has the following randomly determined properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Travel the Depths.</i></b> You can take a Magic action to touch the axe to a fixed piece of dwarven stonework and cast Teleport from the axe. If your intended destination is underground, there is no chance of a mishap or arriving somewhere unexpected. You can't use this property again until 3 days have passed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Axe.</i></b> The only way to destroy the axe is to melt it down in the <i>Earthheart Forge</i>, where it was created. It must remain in the burning forge for 50 years before it finally succumbs to the fire and is consumed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG24_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_TELEPORT" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="range">20/60</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="2" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="60" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_BREWERS_SUPPLIES" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_MASONS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Berserker Axe" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BERSERKER_AXE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, while you are attuned to this weapon, your Hit Point maximum increases by 1 for each level you have attained.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> This weapon is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the weapon, keeping it within reach at all times. You also have Disadvantage on attack rolls with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever another creature damages you while the weapon is in your possession, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or go berserk. This berserk state ends when you start your turn and there are no creatures within 60 feet of you that you can see or hear.</p>
			<p class="indent">While berserk, you regard the creature nearest to you that you can see or hear as your enemy. If there are multiple possible creatures, choose one at random. On each of your turns, you must move as close to the creature as possible and take the Attack action, targeting the creature. If you're unable to get close enough to the creature to attack it with the weapon, your turn ends after you've used up all your available movement. If the creature dies or can no longer be seen or heard by you, the next nearest creature that you can see or hear becomes your new target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any axe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe||Greataxe||Halberd</set>
			<set name="name-format">Berserker {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="hp" value="level" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blackrazor" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BLACKRAZOR">
		<description>
			<p>Hidden in the dungeon of White Plume Mountain, <i>Blackrazor</i> shines like a piece of night sky filled with stars. Its black scabbard is decorated with pieces of cut obsidian.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. If you hit an Undead with this weapon, you take 1d10 Necrotic damage, and the target regains 1d10 Hit Points. If this Necrotic damage reduces you to 0 Hit Points, <i>Blackrazor</i> devours your soul (see "Devour Soul" below).</p>
			<p class="indent">While you hold this weapon, you have Immunity to the Charmed and Frightened conditions, and you have Blindsight with a range of 30 feet.</p>
			<p><b><i>Devour Soul.</i></b> Whenever you use <i>Blackrazor</i> to reduce a creature to 0 Hit Points, the sword slays the creature and devours its soul unless it is a Construct or an Undead. A creature whose soul has been devoured by <i>Blackrazor</i> can be restored to life only by a <i>Wish</i> spell.</p> 
			<p class="indent">When <i>Blackrazor</i> devours a soul that isn't yours, you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to the slain creature's Hit Point maximum.</p> 
			<p><b><i>Haste.</i></b> <i>Blackrazor</i> can cast <i>Haste</i> on you, after which it can't cast this spell again until the next dawn. <i>Blackrazor</i> decides when to cast the spell, which takes effect at the start of your turn. The spell lasts for 1 minute (no Concentration required) or until <i>Blackrazor</i> decides to end it, which it can do at the end of any of your turns.</p>
			<p><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> <i>Blackrazor</i> is a sentient Chaotic Neutral weapon with an Intelligence of 17, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 19. It has hearing and Darkvision out to 120 feet.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The weapon speaks Common and can communicate with its wielder telepathically. Its voice is deep and echoing. While you are attuned to it, <i>Blackrazor</i> also understands every language you know.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Personality.</i></b> <i>Blackrazor</i> speaks with an imperious tone, as though accustomed to being obeyed. The sword's purpose is to consume souls. It doesn't care whose souls it eats, including the wielder's. The sword believes that all matter and energy sprang from a void of negative energy and will one day return to it. <i>Blackrazor</i> is meant to hurry that process along.</p> 
			<p class="indent">Despite its nihilism, <i>Blackrazor</i> feels a strange kinship to <i>Wave</i> and <i>Whelm</i>, two other weapons locked away under White Plume Mountain. It wants the three weapons to be reunited and wielded together in combat, even though it violently disagrees with <i>Whelm</i> and finds <i>Wave</i> tedious.</p> 
			<p class="indent"><i>Blackrazor's</i> hunger for souls must be regularly fed. If the sword goes 3 days or more without consuming a soul, a conflict between it and its wielder occurs at the next sunset.</p>
			<p><b><i>Destroying Blackrazor.</i></b> <i>Blackrazor</i> can be destroyed by crushing it in the great gears of Mechanus. Primus, the creator of the modrons, also knows a series of musical tones that <i>Blackrazor</i> can't stand to hear, causing the sword to shatter.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_HASTE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT" />
			<stat name="blindsight:range" value="30" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dagger of Venom" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_DAGGER_OF_VENOM">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can take a Bonus Action to magically coat the blade with poison. The poison remains for 1 minute or until an attack using this weapon hits a creature. That creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or take 2d10 Poison damage and have the Poisoned condition for 1 minute. The weapon can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dagger</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4002</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dancing Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_DANCING_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>You can take a Bonus Action to toss this magic weapon into the air. When you do so, the weapon begins to hover, flies up to 30 feet, and attacks one creature of your choice within 5 feet of itself. The weapon uses your attack roll and adds your ability modifier to damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the weapon hovers, you can take a Bonus Action to cause it to fly up to 30 feet to another spot within 30 feet of you. As part of the same Bonus Action, you can cause the weapon to attack one creature within 5 feet of the weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">After the hovering weapon attacks for the fourth time, it flies back to you and tries to return to your hand. If you have no hand free, the weapon falls to the ground in your space. If the weapon has no unobstructed path to you, it moves as close to you as it can and then falls to the ground. It also ceases to hover if you grasp it or are more than 30 feet away from it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Dancing {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Defender" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_DEFENDER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The first time you attack with the weapon on each of your turns, you can transfer some or all of the weapon's bonus to your Armor Class. For example, you could reduce the bonus to your attack rolls and damage rolls to +1 and gain a +2 bonus to Armor Class. The adjusted bonuses remain in effect until the start of your next turn, although you must hold the weapon to gain a bonus to AC from it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">melee</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any melee weapon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dragon Slayer" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_DRAGON_SLAYER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon deals an extra 3d6 damage of the weapon's type if the target is a Dragon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dwarven Thrower" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_DWARVEN_THROWER">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has Thrown with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with a ranged attack using this weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 Force damage, or an extra 2d8 Force damage if the target is a Giant. Immediately after hitting or missing, the weapon flies back to your hand.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">warhammer, dwarf</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40015</set>
			<set name="type" addition="warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a dwarf">true</set>
			<set name="range">20/60</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Energy Bow" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENERGY_BOW">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, which has no string. Each time you pull your arm back in a firing motion, a magical arrow made of golden energy appears nocked and ready to fire. An arrow produced by this weapon deals Force damage instead of Piercing damage on a hit, and it disappears after it hits or misses its target. Until it disappears, the arrow emits Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet.</p>
			<p>This weapon has the following additional properties.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Arrow of Restraint.</i></b> Whenever you use this weapon to make a ranged attack against a creature, you can try to restrain the target instead of dealing damage to it. If the arrow hits, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or have the Restrained condition for 1 minute. As an action, a creature Restrained by an arrow can make a DC 20 Strength (Athletics) check to try to break the restraint, ending the effect on itself on a successful check.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Arrow of Transport.</i></b> As a Magic action, you can fire one energy arrow from this weapon at a target you can see within 60 feet of yourself. The target can be either a willing Medium or smaller creature or an object that isn't being worn or carried, provided the object is small enough to fit inside a 5-foot Cube. The arrow teleports the target to an unoccupied space you can see within 10 feet of you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Energy Ladder.</i></b> As a Magic action, you can loose a flurry of energy arrows from this weapon at a wall up to 60 feet away from yourself. The arrows become glowing rungs that stick out of the wall, forming a magical ladder up to 60 feet long on the wall. This ladder lasts for 1 minute before disappearing.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any shortbow or longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Energy {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Cantrip)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_CANTRIP">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a cantrip. The cantrip is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 13, and its attack bonus is +5.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Cantrip)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Cantrip)" supports="0,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 1)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_1">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 1 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 13, and its attack bonus is +5.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 1)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 1)" supports="1,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 2)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_2">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 2 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 13, and its attack bonus is +5.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 2)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 2)" supports="2,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 3)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_3">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 3 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 15, and its attack bonus is +7.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 3)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 3)" supports="3,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 4)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_4">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 4 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 15, and its attack bonus is +7.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 4)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 4)" supports="4,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 5)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_5">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 5 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 17, and its attack bonus is +9.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 5)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 5)" supports="5,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 6)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_6">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 6 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 17, and its attack bonus is +9.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 6)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 6)" supports="6,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 7)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_7">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 7 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 18, and its attack bonus is +10.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 7)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 7)" supports="7,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 8)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSPELLED_WEAPON_LEVEL_8">
		<description>
			<p>Bound into this weapon is a level 8 spell. The spell is determined when the weapon is created and must belong to the Conjuration, Divination, Evocation, Necromancy, or Transmutation school of magic. The weapon has 6 charges and regains 1d6 expended charges daily at dawn. While wielding the weapon, you can expend 1 charge to cast its spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's saving throw DC is 18, and its attack bonus is +10.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Enspelled {{parent}} (Level 8)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Enspelled Weapon (Level 8)" supports="8,(Conjuration||Divination||Evocation||Necromancy||Transmutation)" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Executioner’s Axe" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_EXECUTIONERS_AXE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any Humanoid you hit with the weapon takes an extra 2d6 Slashing damage, and you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to the extra damage dealt.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">axe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe or halberd">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES||Halberd</set>
			<set name="name-format">Executioner's {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Flame Tongue" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_FLAME_TONGUE">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this magic weapon, you can take a Bonus Action and use a command word to cause flames to engulf the damage-dealing part of the weapon. These flames shed Bright Light in a 40-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 40 feet. While the weapon is ablaze, it deals an extra 2d6 Fire damage on a hit. The flames last until you take a Bonus Action to issue the command again or until you drop, stow, or sheathe the weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire, damage</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any melee weapon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Frost Brand" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_FROST_BRAND">
		<description>
			<p>When you hit with an attack roll using this magic weapon, the target takes an extra 1d6 Cold damage. In addition, while you hold the weapon, you have Resistance to Fire damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">In freezing temperatures, the weapon sheds Bright Light in a 10-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 10 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you draw this weapon, you can extinguish all nonmagical flames within 30 feet of yourself. Once used, this property can't be used again for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword,glaive</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword or glaive">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||Glaive</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Giant Slayer" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_GIANT_SLAYER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a Giant with this weapon, the Giant takes an extra 2d6 damage of the weapon's type and must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or have the Prone condition.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Giant Slayer {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hammer of Thunderbolts" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMMER_OF_THUNDERBOLTS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon has 5 charges. You can expend 1 charge and make a ranged attack with the weapon, hurling it as if it had Thrown with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the attack hits, the weapon unleashes a thunderclap audible out to 300 feet. The target and every creature within 30 feet of it other than you must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or have the Stunned condition until the end of your next turn. Immediately after hitting or missing, the weapon flies back to your hand. The weapon regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p><b><i>Giant’s Bane.</i></b> While you are attuned to the weapon and wearing either a <i>Belt of Giant Strength</i> or <i>Gauntlets of Ogre Power</i> to which you are also attuned, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Giants' Bane.</i></b> When you roll a 20 on the d20 for an attack roll made with this weapon against a Giant, the creature must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or die.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Might of Giants.</i></b> The Strength score bestowed by your Belt of Giant Strength or Gauntlets of Ogre Power increases by 4, to a maximum of 30.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">maul</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="maul">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MAULS||Warhammer</set>
			<set name="charges">5</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Thunderbolts</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="4" equipped="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_GAUNTLETS_OF_OGRE_POWER||(ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_HILL_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_STONE_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_FROST_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_FIRE_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_CLOUD_GIANT_STRENGTH||ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_STORM_GIANT_STRENGTH)" />
			<stat name="strength:max" value="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Holy Avenger" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_HOLY_AVENGER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit a Fiend or an Undead with it, that creature takes an extra 2d10 Radiant damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you hold the drawn weapon, it creates a 10-foot Emanation originating from you. You and all creatures Friendly to you in the Emanation have Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. If you have 17 or more levels in the Paladin class, the size of the Emanation increases to 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">paladin</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a paladin">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Holy Avenger {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Javelin of Lightning" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_JAVELIN_OF_LIGHTNING">
		<description>
			<p>Each time you make an attack roll with this magic weapon and hit, you can have it deal Lightning damage instead of Piercing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Lightning Bolt.</i></b> When you throw this weapon at a target no farther than 120 feet from you, you can forgo making a ranged attack roll and instead turn the weapon into a bolt of lightning. This bolt forms a 5-foot-wide Line between you and the target. The target and each other creature in the Line (excluding you) makes a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 Lightning damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. Immediately after dealing this damage, the weapon reappears in your hand. This property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">javelin</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">405</set>
			<set name="type" addition="javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Javelin</set>
			<set name="name-format">Javelin of Lightning</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Luck Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_LUCK_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While the weapon is on your person, you also gain a +1 bonus to saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Luck.</i></b> If the weapon is on your person, you can call on its luck (no action required) to reroll one failed D20 Test if you don't have the Incapacitated condition. You must use the second roll. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Wish.</i></b> The weapon has 1d3 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge and cast <i>Wish</i> from it. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn. The weapon loses this property if it has no charges.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_WISH" />
			</div>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword,glaive,sickle</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword, glaive, or sickle">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||Glaive||Sickle</set>
			<set name="charges">1d3</set>
			<set name="name-format">Luck {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lute of Thunderous Thumping" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_LUTE_OF_THUNDEROUS_THUMPING">
		<description>
			<p>This reinforced lute can be wielded as a magic Club that deals an extra 2d8 Thunder damage on a hit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sing and Swing.</i></b> If you're a Bard, you can use your Charisma modifier instead of your Strength modifier when making a melee attack roll with the lute, provided you sing or hum while making the attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">club</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="club">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">Lute of Thunderous Thumping</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mace of Disruption" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_DISRUPTION">
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a Fiend or an Undead with this magic weapon, that creature takes an extra 2d6 Radiant damage. If the target has 25 Hit Points or fewer after taking this damage, it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be destroyed. On a successful save, the creature has the Frightened condition until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Light.</i></b> While you hold this weapon, it sheds Bright Light in a 20-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 20 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4005</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mace of Smiting" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_SMITING">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The bonus increases to +3 when you use the weapon to attack a Construct.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, the target takes an extra 7 Bludgeoning damage, or 14 Bludgeoning damage if it's a Construct. If a Construct has 25 Hit Points or fewer after taking this damage, it is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4005</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mace of Terror" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_MACE_OF_TERROR">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the weapon, you can take a Magic action and expend 1 charge to release a wave of terror from it. Each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or have the Frightened condition for 1 minute. While Frightened in this way, a creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't make Opportunity Attacks. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If it has nowhere it can move, the creature can take the Dodge action. At the end of each of its turns, a creature repeats the save, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4005</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Moon-Touched Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_MOONTOUCHED_SWORD">		
		<description>
			<p>In Darkness, the unsheathed blade of this weapon sheds moonlight, creating Bright Light in a 15-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 15 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Moon-Touched {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Moonblade" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_MOONBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>Of all the magic items created by elves, one of the most prized and jealously guarded is a <i>Moonblade.</i> In ancient times, nearly all elven noble houses claimed one such weapon. Over the centuries, some of these weapons have faded from the world, their magic lost as family lines have become extinct. Others have vanished with their bearers during great quests. Thus, only a few of these weapons remain.</p>
			<p class="indent">Every <i>Moonblade</i> longs for a bearer whose disposition and goals are compatible with its own. If you try to attune to a <i>Moonblade</i> that doesn't want you as its bearer, the weapon not only rejects you but also places a curse on you, causing you to make D20 Tests with Disadvantage for 24 hours or until the curse is ended by a <i>Remove Curse</i> spell or similar magic. If you're accepted by the weapon and try to attune to it, you become attuned to it instantly, and a new rune appears on it. You remain attuned to the weapon until you die or the weapon is destroyed. A <i>Moonblade</i> functions like a nonmagical weapon of its kind for anyone other than its chosen bearer.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <i>Moonblade</i> has one rune on it for each bearer it has willingly served (typically 1d6 + 1). The first rune grants a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Each rune beyond the first grants the <i>Moonblade</i> an additional property. The DM chooses each property or determines it randomly by rolling on the Moonblade Properties table.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Minor Property.</i></b> In addition to its aforementioned properties, each <i>Moonblade</i> has a minor property determined by rolling on the Magic Item's Minor Property table.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> A <i>Moonblade</i> is a sentient weapon with an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 12. It has hearing and Darkvision out to 120 feet. Its alignment matches that of its creator.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates by transmitting emotions, sending a tingling sensation through the wielder's hand when it wants to communicate something it has sensed. It can communicate through visions or dreams when the wielder is either in a trance or asleep.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Personality.</i></b> A <i>Moonblade</i> has a personality similar to that of its creator. Once a <i>Moonblade</i> has decided on an owner, it believes that only that person should wield it, even if the bearer's alignment differs from that of the weapon's or the bearer's goals later clash with the weapon's goals.</p>
			<h5>MOONBLADE PROPERTIES</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d100</td><td>Property</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>01-60</td><td>Increase the weapon's bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls by 1, to a maximum of +3. Reroll if the <i>Moonblade</i> already has a +3 bonus.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>61-75</td><td>When you hit with an attack roll using the <i>Moonblade</i>, you deal an extra 1d6 Force damage. Each time the weapon gains this property after the first, the extra damage increases by 1d6, to a maximum of 3d6. Reroll if the <i>Moonblade</i> already deals an extra 3d6 Force damage on a hit.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>76-80</td><td>The <i>Moonblade</i> gains Thrown with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. Each time you throw the weapon, it flies back to your hand after the attack.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>81-85</td><td>The <i>Moonblade</i> scores a Critical Hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>86-95</td><td>You can take a Bonus Action to cause the <i>Moonblade</i> to flash brightly. Each other creature that is within 30 feet of you and not behind Total Cover must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or have the Blinded condition for 1 minute. A creature repeats the save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. You can't use this property again until you finish a Short or Long Rest.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>96-99</td><td>The <i>Moonblade</i> has the properties of a <i>Ring of Spell Storing.</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>100</td><td>You can take a Magic action to conjure a spectral entity that resembles a shadowy elf if you don't already have one serving you. The entity appears in an unoccupied space within 120 feet of you. It uses the Shadow stat block with these changes: it is a Fey, has a Neutral alignment, and doesn't create new shadows. You control this entity, deciding how it acts and moves. It remains until it drops to 0 Hit Points or you dismiss it as a Magic action.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">swords</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature of the weapon's choice">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Moonblade {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Nine Lives Stealer" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_NINE_LIVES_STEALER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Life Stealing.</i></b> The weapon has 1d8 + 1 charges. When you attack a creature that has fewer than 100 Hit Points with this weapon and roll a 20 on the d20 for the attack roll, the creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be slain instantly as the sword tears its life force from its body. Constructs and Undead succeed on the save automatically. The weapon loses 1 charge if the creature is slain. When the weapon has no charges remaining, it loses this property.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="charges">1d8+1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Oathbow" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_OATHBOW">
		<description>
			<p>When you nock an arrow on this bow, it whispers in Elvish, "Swift defeat to my enemies." When you use this weapon to make a ranged attack, you can utter or sign the following command words: "Swift death to you who have wronged me." The target of your attack becomes your sworn enemy until it dies or until dawn 7 days later. You can have only one such sworn enemy at a time. When your sworn enemy dies, you can choose a new one after the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you make a ranged attack roll with this weapon against your sworn enemy, you have Advantage on the roll. In addition, your target gains no benefit from Half Cover or Three-Quarters Cover, and you suffer no Disadvantage due to long range. If the attack hits, your sworn enemy takes an extra 3d6 Piercing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">While your sworn enemy lives, you have Disadvantage on attack rolls with all other weapons.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortbow or longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Oath {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Scimitar of Speed" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SCIMITAR_OF_SPEED">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, you can make one attack with it as a Bonus Action on each of your turns.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">scimitar</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40025</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silvered Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVERED_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>An alchemical process has bonded silver to this magic weapon. When you score a Critical Hit with it against a creature that is shape-shifted, the weapon deals one additional die of damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Silvered {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sun Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SUN_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This item appears to be a sword hilt.</p>
			<p><b><i>Blade of Radiance.</i></b> While grasping the hilt, you can take a Bonus Action to cause a blade of pure radiance to spring into existence or make the blade disappear. While the blade exists, this magic weapon functions as a Longsword with Finesse. If you are proficient with Longswords or Shortswords, you are proficient with the <i>Sun Blade.</i></p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this weapon, which deals Radiant damage instead of Slashing damage. When you hit an Undead with it, that target takes an extra 1d8 Radiant damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sunlight.</i></b> The sword's luminous blade emits Bright Light in a 15-foot radius and Dim Light for an additional 15 feet. The light is sunlight. While the blade persists, you can take a Magic action to expand or reduce its radius of Bright Light and Dim Light by 5 feet each, to a maximum of 30 feet each or a minimum of 10 feet each.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword,radiant</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4015</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD||ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Answering" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_ANSWERING">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this sword. In addition, while you hold the sword, you can take a Reaction to make one melee attack with it against any creature in your reach that deals damage to you. You have Advantage on the attack roll, and any damage dealt with this special attack ignores any Immunity or Resistance the target has to that damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">200015</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Kas" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_KAS">
		<description>
			<p>Kas was a powerful warrior who served Vecna and whose loyalty was rewarded with this sword. As Kas's power grew, so did his hubris. The sword urged Kas to destroy Vecna and usurp his throne. Legend says Vecna's destruction came at Kas's hand, but Vecna also wrought his rebellious lieutenant's doom, leaving only Kas's sword behind.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Bloodthirst.</i></b> The sword thirsts for blood. If the sword doesn't taste blood on its blade within 1 minute of being drawn from its scabbard, its wielder makes a DC 15 Charisma saving throw. On a successful save, the wielder takes 3d6 Psychic damage. On a failed save, the wielder is dominated by the sword, as if by the Dominate Monster spell, and the sword demands blood. The spell effect ends when the sword's demand is met.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Magic Weapon.</i></b> You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with the sword, which scores a Critical Hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20 and deals an extra 2d10 Slashing damage to Undead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> The sword has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells.</i></b> Spells. While the sword is on your person, you can cast the following spells (save DC 18) from it:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><i>Call Lightning</i></li>
				<li><i>Divine Word</i></li>
				<li><i>Finger of Death</i></li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">Once you use the sword to cast a spell, you can't cast that spell again from it until the next dawn.</p>
			<p><b><i>Spirit of Kas.</i></b> While the sword is on your person, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Battle Hunger.</i></b> You add 1d10 to your Initiative rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Blade of Defense.</i></b> When you take an action to attack with the sword, you can transfer some or all of its attack bonus to your Armor Class instead. The adjusted bonuses remain in effect until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Necrotic Resistance.</i></b> You have Resistance to Necrotic damage.</p>
			<p><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> The <i>Sword of Kas</i> is a sentient Chaotic Evil weapon with an Intelligence of 15, a Wisdom of 13, and a Charisma of 16. It has hearing and Darkvision out to 120 feet.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and speaks Common.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Personality.</i></b> The sword's purpose is to bring ruin to Vecna. Killing Vecna's worshipers, destroying the lich's works, and foiling his machinations all help to fulfill this goal.</p> 
			<p class="indent">The <i>Sword of Kas</i> also seeks to destroy anyone corrupted by the <i>Eye</i> and <i>Hand of Vecna</i>.</p>
			<p><b><i>Destroying the Sword.</i></b> A creature attuned to both the <i>Eye of Vecna</i> and the <i>Hand of Vecna</i> can use the <i>Wish</i> property of those combined Artifacts to unmake the <i>Sword of Kas</i>, provided the sword is within 30 feet of the spell's caster. Upon casting <i>Wish</i>, the creature makes a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, nothing happens, and the <i>Wish</i> spell is wasted. On a successful save, the <i>Sword of Kas</i> is destroyed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG24_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DIVINE_WORD" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Life Stealing" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_LIFE_STEALING">
		<description>
			<p>When you attack a creature with this magic weapon and roll a 20 on the d20 for the attack roll, that target takes an extra 15 Necrotic damage if it isn't a Construct or an Undead, and you gain Temporary Hit Points equal to the amount of Necrotic damage taken.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||Glaive</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Life Stealing</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Sharpness" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_SHARPNESS">
		<description>
			<p>When you attack an object with this magic weapon and hit, maximize your weapon damage dice against the target.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you attack a creature with this weapon and roll a 20 on the d20 for the attack roll, that target takes an extra 14 Slashing damage and gains 1 Exhaustion level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword that deals slashing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword||Greatsword||Scimitar||Glaive</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Sharpness</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Vengeance" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_VENGEANCE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> This weapon is cursed and possessed by a vengeful spirit. Becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the weapon, keeping it on your person at all times. While attuned to this weapon, you have Disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while the weapon is on your person, you must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw whenever you take damage from another creature in combat. On a failed save, you must attack the creature that damaged you until you drop to 0 Hit Points or it does or until you can't reach the creature to make a melee attack against it.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can break the curse in the usual ways. Alternatively, casting <i>Banishment</i> on the weapon forces the vengeful spirit to leave it. The weapon then becomes a +1 Weapon with no other properties.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword or glaive">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||Glaive</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Vengeance</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Wounding" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_WOUNDING">
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an attack using this magic weapon, the target takes an extra 2d6 Necrotic damage and must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be unable to regain Hit Points for 1 hour. The target repeats the save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword or glaive</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword or glaive">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||Glaive</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Wounding</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sylvan Talon" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_SYLVAN_TALON">
		<description>
			<p>While this weapon is on your person, you understand the nonwritten communication of all Fey, and they understand yours.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Secret Message.</i></b> As a Magic action, you can use the weapon to cast <i>Message.</i> Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_MESSAGE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">daqgger,rapier,scimitar,shortsword,sickle,spear</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any dagger, rapier, scimitar, shortsword, sickle, or spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger||Rapier||Scimitar||Shortsword||Sickle||Spear</set>
			<set name="name-format">Sylvan Talon {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Thunderous Greatclub" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_THUNDEROUS_GREATCLUB">
		<description>
			<p>While you are attuned to this magic weapon, your Strength is 20 unless your Strength is already equal to or greater than that score. The weapon deals an extra 1d8 Thunder damage to any creature it hits and an extra 3d8 Thunder damage to objects it hits that aren't being worn or carried.</p>
			<p>The weapon has the following additional properties.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Clap of Thunder.</i></b> As a Magic action, you can strike the weapon against a hard surface to create a loud clap of thunder audible out to 300 feet. You also create a 30-foot Cone of thunderous energy. Each creature in the Cone must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or have the Prone condition. Nonmagical objects in the Cone that aren't being worn or carried take 3d8 Thunder damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Earthquake.</i></b> As a Magic action, you can strike the weapon against the ground to create an intense seismic disturbance in a 50-foot-radius circle centered on the point of impact. Structures in contact with the ground in that area take 50 Bludgeoning damage, and each creature on the ground in that area must succeed on a DC 20 Dexterity saving throw or have the Prone condition. If that creature is also Concentrating, it must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw or its Concentration is broken. In addition, you can cause a 30-foot-deep, 10-foot-wide fissure to open up on the ground anywhere in the area. Any creature on a spot where the fissure opens must make a DC 20 Dexterity saving throw, falling into the fissure on a failed save or moving with the fissure's edge on a successful one. Any structure on a spot where the fissure opens collapses into the fissure. Once you use this property, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatclub</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatclub">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatclub</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:score:set" value="20" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Trident of Fish Command" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_TRIDENT_OF_FISH_COMMAND">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While you carry it, you can expend 1 charge to cast <i>Dominate Beast</i> (save DC 15) from it on a Beast that has a Swim Speed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" />
			</div>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">trident</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">405</set>
			<set name="type" addition="trident">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Trident</set>
			<set name="name-format">Trident of Fish Command</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vicious Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_VICIOUS_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon deals an extra 2d6 damage to any creature it hits. This extra damage is of the same type as the weapon's normal damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Vicious {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vorpal Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_VORPAL_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, the weapon ignores Resistance to Slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this weapon to attack a creature that has at least one head and roll a 20 on the d20 for the attack roll, you cut off one of the creature's heads. The creature dies if it can't survive without the lost head. A creature is immune to this effect if it has Immunity to Slashing damage, if it doesn't have or need a head, or if the DM decides that the creature is too big for its head to be cut off with this weapon. Such a creature instead takes an extra 30 Slashing damage from the hit. If the creature has Legendary Resistance, it can expend one daily use of that trait to avoid losing its head, taking the extra damage instead.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword that deals slashing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Glaive||Greatsword||Longsword||Scimitar</set>
			<set name="name-format">Vorpal {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Wave" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_WAVE">
		<description>
			<p>Held in the dungeon of White Plume Mountain, <i>Wave</i> is engraved with images of waves, shells, and sea creatures.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you roll a 20 on the d20 for an attack roll with this weapon, the target takes an extra 21 Necrotic damage.</p>
			<p>While holding <i>Wave</i>, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Combat Ready.</i></b> You have Advantage on Initiative rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Underwater Adaptation.</i></b> A bubble of air forms around your head while you are underwater, allowing you to breathe normally in that environment.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Aquatic Command.</i></b> <i>Wave</i> has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While you carry it, you can expend 1 charge to cast <i>Dominate Beast</i> (save DC 20) from it on a Beast that has a Swim Speed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Globe of Invulnerability.</i></b> While holding <i>Wave</i>, you can cast the level 9 version of <i>Globe of Invulnerability</i> from it. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> <i>Wave</i> is a sentient weapon of Neutral alignment, with an Intelligence of 14, a Wisdom of 10, and a Charisma of 18. It has hearing and Darkvision out to 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and speaks Aquan.</p>
			<p><b><i>Personality.</i></b> <i>Wave</i> zealously encourages mortals to worship sea gods and has a habit of humming sea chanteys. Conflict arises if the wielder fails to further the weapon's objectives in the world.</p>
			<p><b><i>Destroying Wave.</i></b> <i>Wave</i> can be destroyed only on the island of Thunderforge, where it was forged. The weapon must be melted down by a storm giant or someone imbued with a storm giant's strength. Destroying <i>Wave</i> angers a god of the sea, who sends powerful agents to attack the island and punish the destroyers.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_GLOBE_OF_INVULNERABILITY" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">trident</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="trident">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement"> true</set>
			<set name="charges">3</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Trident</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon of Warning" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_OF_WARNING">
		<description>
			<p>As long as this weapon is within your reach and you are attuned to it, you and allies within 30 feet of you gain the following benefits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Alarm.</i></b> The weapon magically awakens each subject who is sleeping naturally when combat begins. This benefit doesn't wake a subject from magically induced sleep.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Supernatural Readiness.</i></b> Each subject has Advantage on its Initiative rolls.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Warning</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Whelm" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_WHELM">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p><i>Whelm</i> is a powerful weapon forged by dwarves and lost in the dungeon of White Plume Mountain.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Hurl.</i></b> <i>Whelm</i> has Thrown with a normal range of 60 feet and a long range of 180 feet. When you hit with a ranged attack roll using Whelm, the target takes an extra 1d8 Force damage, or an extra 4d8 Force damage if the target is a Construct, an Elemental, or a Giant. Immediately after hitting or missing, the weapon flies back to your hand.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Shock Wave.</i></b> You can take a Magic action to strike the ground with <i>Whelm</i> and send a shock wave out from the point of impact. Each creature of your choice on the ground within 60 feet of that point must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw or have the Stunned condition for 1 minute. A creature repeats the save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Supernatural Awareness.</i></b> While you are holding the weapon, it alerts you to the location of any secret or concealed doors within 30 feet of you. In addition, you can cast <i>Detect Evil and Good</i> or <i>Locate Object</i> from the weapon. Once you cast either spell, you can't cast it from the weapon again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> <i>Whelm</i> is a sentient, Lawful Neutral weapon with an Intelligence of 15, a Wisdom of 12, and a Charisma of 15. It has hearing and Darkvision out to 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon communicates telepathically with its wielder and speaks Dwarvish, Giant, and Goblin.</p>
			<p><b><i>Personality.</i></b> <i>Whelm's</i> has ties to the dwarf clan that created it, called the Dankil or the Mightyhammer clan. It longs to be returned to that clan. <i>Whelm's</i> purpose is to protect dwarves. Conflict arises if the wielder doesn't share this goal.</p>
			<p><b><i>Destroying Whelm.</i></b> <i>Whelm</i> can be dissolved in the acidic bile of a recently slain ancient black dragon. It can also be melted down in the forges of the Mightyhammer dwarf clan, but only by the rightful leader of that clan.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD" />
			</div>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT" />
			</div>		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">warhammer</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a dwarf or a creature attuned to a belt of dwarvenkind">true</set>
			<set name="range">60/180</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- ammunition -->
	<element name="Ammunition, +1" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_1">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this piece of magic ammunition. Once it hits a target, the ammunition is no longer magical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition, +2" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_2">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this piece of magic ammunition. Once it hits a target, the ammunition is no longer magical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">4000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition, +3" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_3">
		<description>
			<p>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this piece of magic ammunition. Once it hits a target, the ammunition is no longer magical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adamantine Ammunition" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_ADAMANTINE">
		<description>
			<p>This piece of ammunition is made of adamantine, one of the hardest substances in existence. Whenever this weapon or piece of ammunition hits an object, the hit is a Critical Hit.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="name-format">Adamantine {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Aberration Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_ABERRATION_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Aberrations. If an Aberration takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to an Aberration, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Aberration Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Beast Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_BEAST_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Beasts. If a Beast takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Beast, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Beast Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Celestial Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_CELESTIAL_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Celestial. If a Celestial takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Celestial, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Celestial Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Construct Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_CONSTRUCT_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Constructs. If a Construct takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Construct, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Construct Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Dragon Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_DRAGON_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Dragons. If a Dragon takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Dragon, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Dragon Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Elemental Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_ELEMENTAL_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Elementals. If an Elemental takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to an Elemental, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Elemental Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Humanoid Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_HUMANOID_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Humanoids. If a Humanoid takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Humanoid, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Humanoid Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Fey Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_FEY_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Fey. If a Fey takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Fey, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Fey Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Fiend Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_FIEND_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Fiends. If a Fiend takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Fiend, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Fiend Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Giant Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_GIANT_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Giants. If a Giant takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Giant, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Giant Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Monstrosity Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_MONSTROSITY_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Monstrosities. If a Monstrosity takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Monstrosity, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Monstrosity Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Ooze Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_OOZE_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Oozes. If an Ooze takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to an Ooze, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Ooze Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Plant Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_PLANT_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Plants. If a Plant takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to a Plant, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Plant Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ammunition of Undead Slaying" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_OF_UNDEAD_SLAYING">
		<description>
			<p>This magic ammunition is meant to slay Undead. If an Undead takes damage from the ammunition, it makes a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking an extra 6d10 Force damage on a failed save or half as much extra damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">After dealing its extra damage to an Undead, the ammunition becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">40000</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Undead Slaying</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Walloping Ammunition" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_DMG24_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMUNITION_ADAMANTINE">
		<description>
			<p>A creature hit by this ammunition must succeed on a DC 10 Strength saving throw or have the Prone condition.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="name-format">Walloping {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
