<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/vecna-eve-of-ruin/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Vecna: Eve of Ruin" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_VECNA_EVE_OF_RUIN">
		<description>
			<h5 style="margin-top:-1em">WHO WILL SAVE EXISTENCE?</h5>
			<p><strong>Save existence from annihilation in this epic, multiverse-spanning adventure.</strong></p>
			<p>The notorious lich Vecna is weaving a ritual to eliminate good, obliterate the gods, and subjugate all worlds. To stop Vecna before he remakes the universe, the heroes work with three of the multiverse’s most famous archmages, travel to far-flung locales, and rebuild the legendary Rod of Seven Parts. </p>
			<p><i>Vecna: Eve of Ruin</i> is a high-stakes DUNGEON &amp; DRAGONS adventure in which the fate of the multiverse hangs in the balance. The heroes begin in the Forgotten Realms and travel to Planescape, Spelljammer, Eberron, Ravenloft, Dragonlance, and Greyhawk as they race to save existence from obliteration. </p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>HIGH-LEVEL ADVENTURE FOR LEVELS 10-20.</b> Dungeon Masters and players alike will unlock their full potential in this epic high-level Dungeons &amp; Dragons adventure for characters level 10-20. You hold the power to change the multiverse, so what are you waiting for? Legends aren't born—they're made.</li>
				<li><b>DARE YOU SAY HIS NAME?</b> Fans of <i>Stranger Things</i> will be delighted to discover that Vecna is back—with a vengeance. This notorious D&amp;D villain has set his sights on something more terrifying than ever: the end of existence itself.</li>
				<li><b>BATTLE ALONGSIDE D&amp;D LEGENDS.</b> Join the battle for the multiverse alongside legendary allies who you may recognize from other D&amp;D adventures. This book includes detailed character dossiers with exclusive insight into these illustrious figures.</li>
				<li><b>AN EPIC, MULTIVERSE-SPANNING ADVENTURE.</b> Journey through memorable fantasy locations during your race to save existence. From the wild space galaxies of Spelljammer to the mist-shrouded vistas of Ravenloft, your quest will carry you all over the D&amp;D multiverse.</li>
				<li><b>VANQUISH EVIL.</b> In <i>Vecna: Eve of Ruin</i>, players will take on over 30 terrifying new monsters spawning from all over the multiverse. Battling these beasts will bring you one step closer to foiling Vecna's plans and vanquishing evil, once and for all.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">VER</set>
			<set name="url">https://dndstore.wizards.com/us/product/924703/vecna-eve-of-ruin-digital-plus-physical-bundle</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/vecna-eve-of-ruin/VER.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20240521</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
