<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Weapon Properties</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rpg_playershandbook">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="properties-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/core/players-handbook-2024/misc/properties-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<!-- weapon properties -->
	<element name="Ammunition" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION">
		<description>
			<p>You can use a weapon that has the Ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from it. The type of ammunition required is specified with the weapon's range. Each attack expends one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition is part of the attack (you need a free hand to load a one-handed weapon). After a fight, you can spend 1 minute to recover half the ammunition (round down) you used in the fight; the rest is lost.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Finesse" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE">
		<description>
			<p>When making an attack with a Finesse weapon, use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Heavy" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_HEAVY">
		<description>
			<p>You have Disadvantage on attack rolls with a Heavy weapon if it's a Melee weapon and your Strength score isn't at least 13 or if it's a Ranged weapon and your Dexterity score isn't at least 13.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Light" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>When you take the Attack action on your turn and attack with a Light weapon, you can make one extra attack as a Bonus Action later on the same turn. That extra attack must be made with a different Light weapon, and you don't add your ability modifier to the extra attack's damage unless that modifier is negative. For example, you can attack with a Shortsword in one hand and a Dagger in the other using the Attack action and a Bonus Action, but you don't add your Strength or Dexterity modifier to the damage roll of the Bonus Action unless that modifier is negative.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Loading" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LOADING">
		<description>
			<p>You can fire only one piece of ammunition from a Loading weapon when you use an Action, a Bonus Action, or a Reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Range" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_RANGE">
		<description>
			<p>A Range weapon has a range in parentheses after the Ammunition or Thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second is the weapon's long range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have Disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the long range.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Reach" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_REACH">
		<description>
			<p>A Reach weapon adds 5 feet to your reach when you attack with it, as well as when determining your reach for Opportunity Attacks with it.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Thrown" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN">
		<description>
			<p>If a weapon has the Thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack, and you can draw that weapon as part of the attack. If the weapon is a Melee weapon, use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls that you use for a melee attack with that weapon.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Two-Handed" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED">
		<description>
			<p>A Two-Handed weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Versatile" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_VERSATILE">
		<description>
			<p>A Versatile weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property. The weapon deals that damage when used with two hands to make a melee attack.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Improvised" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_IMPROVISED">
		<description>
			<p>An improvised weapon is an object wielded as a makeshift weapon, such as broken glass, a table leg, or a frying pan. A Simple or Martial weapon also counts as an improvised weapon if it's wielded in a way contrary to its design; if you use a Ranged weapon to make a melee attack or throw a Melee weapon that lacks the Thrown property, the weapon counts as an improvised weapon. An improvised weapon follows the rules below.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i>Proficiency.</i> Don't add your Proficiency Bonus to attack rolls with an improvised weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i>Damage.</i> On a hit, the weapon deals ld4 damage of a type the DM thinks is appropriate for the object.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i>Range.</i> If you throw the weapon, it has a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i>Weapon Equivalents.</i> If an improvised weapon resembles a Simple or Martial weapon, the DM may say it functions as that weapon and uses that weapon's rules. For example, the DM could treat a table leg as a Club.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<!-- 
	<element name="Special" type="Weapon Property" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL">
		<description>
			<p>A weapon with the special property has unusual rules governing its use, explained in the weapon's description.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Special (Lance)" type="Weapon Property" source="Player’s Handbook 2024" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_LANCE">
		<description>
			<p>You have disadvantage when you use a lance to attack a target within 5 feet of you. Also, a lance requires two hands to wield when you aren't mounted.</p>
		</description>
	</element>-->

		
	<!-- weapon category 
	<element name="Simple Melee" type="Weapon Category" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE" />
	<element name="Simple Ranged" type="Weapon Category" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED" />
	<element name="Martial Melee" type="Weapon Category" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE" />
	<element name="Martial Ranged" type="Weapon Category" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED" />-->

	<!-- weapon groups 
	<element name="Weapon Group (Swords)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Axes)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Maces)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MACES" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Hammers)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_HAMMERS" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Mauls)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_MAULS" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Bows)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Crossbows)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CROSSBOWS" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Spears)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SPEARS" />
	<element name="Weapon Group (Clubs)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CLUBS" />-->


</elements>