<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="bloodhunter-lycan.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/collaborations/blood-hunter-2022/bloodhunter-lycan.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Order of the Lycan" type="Archetype" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN">
		<supports>Blood Hunter Order 2022</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The ancient curse of lycanthropy is feared by nearly all peoples and cultures, passed through blood and seeding a host with the savage strength and hunger for violence of a wicked beast. The Order of the Lycan is a proud group of blood hunters who undergo “the Taming”—the ceremonial infliction of lycanthropy by a senior member of the order, for those who do not already carry the curse before seeking this path. These hunters then use the magic of their blood to harness the power of the monster they harbor, without losing themselves to it. Using intense will and secret blood magic rituals, members of the Order of the Lycan learn to control and unleash their hybrid forms for short periods of time. Enhanced physical prowess, unnatural resilience, and razor-sharp claws make these warriors a terrible foe to any evil that crosses their path. Yet no training is perfect, and without care and complete focus, even the greatest of blood hunters can temporarily lose themselves to their own hunger.</p>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5>The Burden of Lycanthropy</h5>
				<p>Those inducted into the Order of the Lycan choose this path with conviction, understanding the terrible weight it imposes on them and the challenges it brings. Where most afflicted by the curse of lycanthropy grow wicked, deranged, and even murderous, Lycan blood hunters accept the gifts of the beast while maintaining control through intense training and the power of their blood magic. A member of the Order of the Lycan cannot spread their curse through blood unless they wish to, and one of the most sacred oaths of this order is to never infect another creature without the order’s sanction.</p>
				<p class="indent">If a member of the Order of the Lycan is ever cured of their lycanthropic curse, it brings terrible shame to their name and the order. Members who have been cleansed against their will readily return to the order to undergo a renewed initiation of the Taming, reintroducing the curse to their bodies and restoring their honor.</p>
				<p class="indent">Lycanthropy comes in many forms bound to specific beasts, with wolf, bear, tiger, boar, and rat the best-known variations. The particular strain of the lycanthropic curse defines the physical traits that manifest in a Lycan blood hunter’s hybrid transformation, even as the benefits the curse bestows remain relatively uniform.</p>
			</div>
			<div element="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES" />
			<div element="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION" />
			<div element="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS" />
			<div element="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION" />
			<div element="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_BRAND_OF_THE_VORACIOUS" />
			<div element="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY" />
			<br/>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_BRAND_OF_THE_VORACIOUS" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Heightened Senses" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES">
		<requirements>!ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the improved senses of a natural predator. You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain advantage on Perception checks that rely on hearing or smell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Hybrid Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION">
		<requirements>!ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Also at 3rd level, you learn to control the lycanthropic curse that courses through your veins. As a bonus action, you transform into a special hybrid form for up to 1 hour. You can speak, use equipment, and wear armor while in this form, and can revert to your normal form as a bonus action. You automatically revert to your normal form if you fall unconscious or die.</p>
			<p class="indent">This feature replaces the rules for lycanthropy in the Monster Manual. Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you are transformed, you gain the following benefits and drawbacks:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Feral Might.</em></strong> You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws, and you have a +1 bonus to melee damage rolls. This bonus increases to +2 at 11th level and to +3 at 18th level.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Resilient Hide.</em></strong> You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks not made with silvered weapons. Additionally, while you are not wearing heavy armor, you have a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Predatory Strikes.</em></strong> Your can apply your Crimson Rite feature to your unarmed strikes. You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes. When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you use the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make one additional unarmed strike as a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bloodlust.</em></strong> If you start your turn with fewer hit points than half your hit point maximum, you must succeed on a DC 8 Wisdom saving throw or move directly toward the nearest creature and use the Attack action against that creature. If you’re concentrating on a spell or are under an effect that prevents you from concentrating (such as the barbarian’s Rage feature), you automatically fail this saving throw.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you have your Extra Attack feature, you can choose whether to use it for this frenzied attack. If more than one creature is equally near to you, roll randomly to determine your target. Once your attack is resolved, you regain control of yourself.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{hybrid transformation:usage}}/Rest">
			<description>You can transform into your hybrid form for up to 1 hour. You can speak, use equipment, and wear armor in this form. You can revert to your normal form earlier as a bonus action. You automatically revert to your normal form if you fall unconscious or die.</description>
			<description usage="" level="18">You can transform into your hybrid form indefinitely. You can speak, use equipment, and wear armor in this form. You can revert to your normal form earlier as a bonus action. You automatically revert to your normal form if you fall unconscious or die.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_FERAL_MIGHT" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_RESILIENT_HIDE" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_PREDATORY_STRIKES" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_BLOODLUST" />

			<stat name="hybrid transformation:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feral Might" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_FERAL_MIGHT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws, and you have a +1 bonus to melee damage rolls. This bonus increases to +2 at 11th level and to +3 at 18th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Hybrid Form">
			<description>You gain a +1 to melee damage rolls. You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</description>
			<description level="11">You gain a +2 to melee damage rolls. You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</description>
			<description level="18">You gain a +3 to melee damage rolls. You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Resilient Hide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_RESILIENT_HIDE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks not made with silvered weapons. Additionally, while you are not wearing heavy armor, you have a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Hybrid Form">
			<description>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks not made with silvered weapons. Additionally, while you are not wearing heavy armor, you have a +1 bonus to AC.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Predatory Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_PREDATORY_STRIKES">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>You can apply your Crimson Rite feature to your unarmed strikes, which you treat as one weapon. You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes, which deal 1d6 bludgeoning or slashing damage (your choice). This damage increases to 1d8 at 11th level.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you use the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make one additional unarmed strike as a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Hybrid Form">
			<description>You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes, which deal 1d6 bludgeoning or slashing damage. When you use the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed attack as a bonus action. You can apply your Crimson Rite feature to your unarmed strikes, which are considered a single weapon.</description>
			<description level="7" alt="Improved Predatory Strikes">You have a +1 bonus to the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes, and you can use Dexterity instead of Strength for them. Your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 bludgeoning or slashing damage. When you use the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed attack as a bonus action. You can apply your Crimson Rite feature to your unarmed strikes, which are considered a single weapon. While Crimson Rite is active in this way, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
			<description level="11" alt="Improved Predatory Strikes">You have a +2 bonus to the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes, and you can use Dexterity instead of Strength for them. Your unarmed strikes deal 1d8 bludgeoning or slashing damage. When you use the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed attack as a bonus action. You can apply your Crimson Rite feature to your unarmed strikes, which are considered a single weapon. While Crimson Rite is active in this way, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
			<description level="18" alt="Improved Predatory Strikes">You have a +3 bonus to the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes, and you can use Dexterity instead of Strength for them. Your unarmed strikes deal 1d8 bludgeoning or slashing damage. When you use the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed attack as a bonus action. You can apply your Crimson Rite feature to your unarmed strikes, which are considered a single weapon. While Crimson Rite is active in this way, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Bloodlust" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_BLOODLUST">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>If you start your turn with fewer hit points than half your hit point maximum, you must succeed on a DC 8 Wisdom saving throw or move directly toward the nearest creature and use the Attack action against that creature. If you’re concentrating on a spell or are under an effect that prevents you from concentrating (such as the barbarian’s Rage feature), you automatically fail this saving throw.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you have your Extra Attack feature, you can choose whether to use it for this frenzied attack. If more than one creature is equally near to you, roll randomly to determine your target. Once your attack is resolved, you regain control of yourself.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Hybrid Form">
			<description>If you start your turn with fewer than half of your maximum hit points, you must succeed on a DC{{lycan bloodlust:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or move directly towards the nearest creature and use the Attack action against that creature. If you’re concentrating on a spell or are under an effect that prevents you from concentrating, you automatically fail this saving throw. If you have the Extra Attack feature, you can choose whether to use it for this frenzied attack. If more than one creature is equally near to you, roll randomly to determine your target. Once your attack is resolved, you regain control of yourself.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="lycan bloodlust:dc" value="8" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Lycan Regeneration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION_LYCAN_REGENERATION">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>At the start of each of your turns when you have at least 1 hit point but fewer hit points than half your hit point maximum, you gain hit points equal to 1 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1). If you are in hybrid form, you gain these hit points before you must make the saving throw for your bloodlust.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Hybrid Form">
			<description>At the start of each of your turns, you regain {{lycan regeneration:hp}} hit points if you have at least 1 hit point and no more than half of your hit points left. If you are in hybrid form, you gain these hit points before you must make the saving throw for your bloodlust.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="lycan regeneration:hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="lycan regeneration:hp" value="lycan regeneration:hp:bonus" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="lycan regeneration:hp:bonus" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="lycan regeneration:hp:bonus" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Stalker’s Prowess" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS">
		<requirements>!ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level, your speed increases by 10 feet, and you add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 3 feet to your high jump distance. Your hybrid form also gains the following additional benefit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Predatory Strikes.</em></strong> You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with your unarmed strike. This bonus increases to +2 at 11th level and to +3 at 18th level. Additionally, when you have an active crimson rite on your unarmed strike while in your hybrid form, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 3 feet to your high jump distance.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:misc" value="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Advanced Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION">
		<requirements>!ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>At 11th level, you learn to unleash and control more of the beast within. You can use your Hybrid Transformation feature twice, regaining all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest. Your hybrid form also gains the following additional benefit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Lycan Regeneration.</em></strong> At the start of each of your turns when you have at least 1 hit point but fewer hit points than half your hit point maximum, you gain hit points equal to 1 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1). If you are in hybrid form, you gain these hit points before you must make the saving throw for your bloodlust.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="hybrid transformation:usage" value="2" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION_LYCAN_REGENERATION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Brand of the Voracious" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_BRAND_OF_THE_VORACIOUS">
		<requirements>!ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BRAND_OF_THE_VORACIOUS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 15th level, you have advantage on the saving throw for your bloodlust while in hybrid form. Additionally, your Brand of Castigation can now bind a foe to your hunter’s ferocity. While in your hybrid form, you have advantage on attack rolls against a creature branded by you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on the saving throw for your bloodlust while in hybrid form. Additionally, your Brand of Castigation can now bind a foe to your hunter’s ferocity. While in your hybrid form, you have advantage on attack rolls against a creature branded by you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Hybrid Transformation Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Blood Hunter (2022)" id="ID_CR_BH22_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY">
		<requirements>!ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, you have mastered your inner predator. You can use your Hybrid Transformation feature an unlimited number of times, and your hybrid form lasts until you revert to your normal form, fall unconscious, or die.</p>
			<p class="indent">You also gain the Blood Curse of the Howl for your Blood Maledict feature. This doesn’t count against your number of blood curses known.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CR_BH22_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_HOWL" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Feature Replacement Grants-->
	<element name="Heightened Senses Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES" />
	<element name="Hybrid Transformation Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION" />
	<element name="Stalker's Prowess Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS" />
	<element name="Advanced Transformation Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION" />
	<element name="Brand of the Voracious Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BRAND_OF_THE_VORACIOUS" />
	<element name="Hybrid Transformation Mastery Feature Replacement" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_CR_BH22_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY" />
	
</elements>
