<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Planar Philosopher Background</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="background-planar-philosopher.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/sigil-and-the-outlands/backgrounds/background-planar-philosopher.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Planar Philosopher" type="Background" source="Sigil and the Outlands" id="ID_WOTC_SATO_BACKGROUND_PLANAR_PHILOSOPHER">
		<prerequisite>Planescape Campaign</prerequisite>
		<description>
		<p><em>Prerequisite: Planescape Campaign</em></p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Arcana, the skill associated with your faction (see the Sigil Faction Affinities table) or one skill of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A portal key (such as a bag of golden tea leaves or the tooth of a planar beast), a manifesto of your guiding philosophy, a set of common clothes in your faction's style, and a pouch containing 10 gp worth of coins from different worlds and planes</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>Sigil Faction Affinities</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Faction</td><td>Skill</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Athar</td><td>Religion</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Bleak Cabal</td><td>Insight</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Doomguard</td><td>Nature.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Fated</td><td>Intimidation.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Fraternity of Order</td><td>History</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Hands of Havoc</td><td>Stealth</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Harmonium</td><td>Perception</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Heralds of Dust</td><td>Medicine</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Mercykillers</td><td>Survival</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Mind's Eye</td><td>Persuasion</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Society of Sensation</td><td>Performance</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Transcendent Order</td><td>Athletics</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>FACTIONS OF SIGIL</h5>
			<p>Twelve factions have risen to prominence in the City of Doors, though many more exist. Your character might belong to one of these groups or another ideological faction, perhaps one of your own creation.</p>
			<p class="indent">The primary factions of Sigil, which are further detailed in chapter 2, adhere to the following philosophies:</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Athar.</strong> Deities are frauds and merely channel the might of a true, higher power.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Bleak Cabal.</strong> There is no greater truth to the multiverse. Each being must discover their own meaning.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Doomguard.</strong> Nothing lasts forever. The purpose of everything is to crumble and decay.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Fated.</strong> Everyone makes their own fate and is entitled to whatever they can take and hold.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Fraternity of Order.</strong> All of existence is governed by laws, and power comes from understanding and exploiting them.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Hands of Havoc.</strong> Those who try to impose a single order on the multiverse are doomed to fail.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Harmonium.</strong> The multiverse will be perfect only when everything is acting in harmony, whether it wants to or not.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Heralds of Dust.</strong> Everyone is already dead; the entirety of the multiverse is an afterlife. Undeath holds the key to the next stage of existence.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Mercykillers.</strong> Cold, relentless justice is absolute, and no one is above it.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Mind's Eye.</strong> The multiverse exists to be explored. It shapes us, and we shape it in turn.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Society of Sensation.</strong> Sensation is the proof of existence. By experiencing everything, we can understand the multiverse in all its complexity.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Transcendent Order.</strong> Thought clouds action. To fall in step with the multiverse, one must act on instinct alone.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_SATO_BACKGROUND_PLANAR_PHILOSOPHER_CONVICTION" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>The influence of an Outer Plane shapes your perspective. The Planar Philosopher Personality Traits table suggests traits you might adopt for your character.Adventurers who dedicate themselves to a particular philosophy regarding the multiverse are welcomed among factions that embrace those beliefs. The Planar Philosopher Personality Traits table suggests various traits you might adopt for your character.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">d6</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>I don't venerate any gods. With time, we can be as powerful as them or greater.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Experience is everything; live in the moment.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>When things crumble, I find meaning in the dust.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Life thrives through order, and I seek to maintain that order.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>When others make plans, the multiverse laughs and so do I.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>I know what's right, and none will stand in my way.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>BUILDING A PLANAR PHILOSOPHER CHARACTER</h5>
			<p>Some groups of planar philosophers might prefer certain types of characters, but by and large any character who upholds and furthers the beliefs of such a group is welcome within its ranks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Planar Philosopher Trinkets.</b> When you make your character, you can roll once on the Planar Philosopher Trinkets table, instead of on the Trinkets table in the Player's Handbook, for your starting trinket.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_SATO_FEAT_SCION_OF_THE_OUTER_PLANES" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Arcana, 1 other Skill, 2 Languages</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_SATO_BACKGROUND_PLANAR_PHILOSOPHER_CONVICTION" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I don't venerate any gods. With time, we can be as powerful as them or greater.</item>
				<item id="2">Experience is everything; live in the moment.</item>
				<item id="3">When things crumble, I find meaning in the dust.</item>
				<item id="4">Life thrives through order, and I seek to maintain that order.</item>
				<item id="5">When others make plans, the multiverse laughs and so do I.</item>
				<item id="6">I know what's right, and none will stand in my way.</item>
			</select>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="2nd Skill Proficiency (Planar Philosopher)" supports="Skill" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Planar Philosopher)" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Feature: Conviction" type="Background Feature" source="Sigil and the Outlands" id="ID_WOTC_SATO_BACKGROUND_PLANAR_PHILOSOPHER_CONVICTION">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain the Scion of the Outer Planes feat. In addition, members of your organization provide you free, modest lodging and food at any of their holdings or the homes of other faction members.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_SATO_FEAT_SCION_OF_THE_OUTER_PLANES" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Conviction">
			<description>Members of your organization provide you free, modest lodging and food at any of their holdings or the homes of other faction members.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Feat" id="ID_WOTC_SATO_FEAT_SCION_OF_THE_OUTER_PLANES" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_BACKGROUND_WITH_A_FEAT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
