<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items from Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/strixhaven-a-curriculum-of-chaos/items-magic.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!--Magic Items-->
	<element name="Bottle of Boundless Coffee" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_BOTTLE_OF_BOUNDLESS_COFFEE">
		<description>
			<p>This metal bottle carries delicious, warm coffee. The bottle comes with a stopper, which is attached to the bottle by a little chain. Even when open, the bottle won’t accept any liquid other than the coffee it produces. The coffee inside is always comfortably warm, and none of the heat can be felt through the bottle. </p>
			<p class="indent">Each time you drink the coffee, roll a d20. On a 1, the bottle refuses to dispense coffee for the next hour. If you pour coffee from the bottle, rather than drinking from it, the coffee vanishes the moment it leaves the bottle. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cuddly Strixhaven Mascot" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_CUDDLY_STRIXHAVEN_MASCOT">
		<description>
			<p>Representing one of the mascots of Strixhaven, this soft, Tiny, magic toy is perfect for cuddling. If you press it to your arm, shoulder, or leg as an action, the toy stays attached there for 1 hour or until you use an action to remove it.</p>
			<p class="indent">This toy can also be used to fight off fear. When you make a saving throw to avoid or end the frightened condition on yourself, you can give yourself advantage on the roll if the toy is on your person. You must decide to do so before rolling the d20. If the save succeeds, you can’t use the toy in this way again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">frightened, advantage</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	<element name="Lorehold Primer" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_LOREHOLD_PRIMER">
		<description>
			<p>The Lorehold Primer is a magic textbook created at Strixhaven’s Lorehold College. The primer has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. If you make an Intelligence (History) or an Intelligence (Religion) check while holding the primer, you can expend 1 charge to give yourself a 1d4 bonus to the check, immediately after you roll the d20.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, if you study the primer at the end of a long rest, you can choose one 1st-level spell from the cleric or wizard spell list. Before you finish your next long rest, you can cast the chosen spell once without a spell slot if you are holding the primer. Your spellcasting ability for this spell is your choice of Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">history, religion, spell, cleric, wizard</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">300</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	<element name="Prismari Primer" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_PRISMARI_PRIMER">
		<description>
			<p>The Prismari Primer is a magic textbook created at Strixhaven’s Prismari College. The primer has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. If you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) or a Charisma (Performance) check while holding the primer,you can expend 1 charge to give yourself a 1d4 bonus to the check, immediately after you roll the d20.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, if you study the primer at the end of a long rest, you can choose one 1st-level spell from the bard or sorcerer spell list. Before you finish your next long rest, you can cast the chosen spell once without a spell slot if you are holding the primer. Your spellcasting ability for this spell is your choice of Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">acrobatics, performance, spell, bard, sorcerer</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">300</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	<element name="Quadrix Primer" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_QUANDRIX_PRIMER">
		<description>
			<p>The Quandrix Primer is a magic textbook created at Strixhaven’s Quandrix College. The primer has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. If you make an Intelligence (Arcana) or an Intelligence (Nature) check while holding the primer, you can expend 1 charge to give yourself a 1d4bonus to the check, immediately after you roll the d20.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, if you study the primer at the end of a long rest, you can choose one 1st-level spell from the druid or wizard spell list. Before you finish your next long rest, you can cast the chosen spell once without a spell slot if you are holding the primer. Your spellcasting ability for this spell is your choice of Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arcana, nature, spell, druid, wizard</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">300</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silverquill Primer" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVERQUILL_PRIMER">
		<description>
			<p>The Silverquill Primer is a magic textbook created at Strixhaven’s Silverquill College. The primer has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. If you make a Charisma (Intimidation) or a Charisma (Persuasion) check while holding the primer, you can expend 1 charge to give yourself a1d4 bonus to the check, immediately after you roll the d20.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, if you study the primer at the end of a long rest, you can choose one 1st-level spell from the bard or cleric spell list. Before you finish your next long rest, you can cast the chosen spell once without a spell slot if you are holding the primer. Your spellcasting ability for this spell is your choice of Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">intimidation, persuasion, spell, bard, cleric</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">300</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Strixhaven Pennant" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_STRIXHAVEN_PENNANT">
		<description>
			<p>This magic pennant bears the symbol of Strixhaven or one of its colleges: Lorehold, Prismari, Quandrix, Silverquill, or Witherbloom. While you wave the pennant, the symbol on it glitters, and the pennant sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bright, dim, light</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Witherbloom Primer" type="Magic Item" source="Strixhaven: A Curriculum Of Chaos" id="ID_WOTC_SCOC_MAGIC_ITEM_WITHERBLOOM_PRIMER">
		<description>
			<p>The Witherbloom Primer is a magic textbook created at Strixhaven’s Witherbloom College. The primer has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. If you make an Intelligence (Nature) or Wisdom (Survival) check while holding the primer, you can expend 1 charge to give yourself a 1d4 bonus to the check, immediately after you roll the d20.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, if you study the primer at the end of a long rest, you can choose one 1st-level spell from the druid or wizard spell list. Before you finish your next long rest, you can cast the chosen spell once without a spell slot if you are holding the primer. Your spellcasting ability for this spell is your choice of Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">nature, survival, spell, druid, wizard</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">300</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
