<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Artificer</name>
		<description>The Artificer from Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/tashas-cauldron-everything">Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="class-artificer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/tashas-cauldron-of-everything/archetypes/class-artificer.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
  <element name="Artificer" type="Class" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_ARTIFICER">
		<description>
			<p>Masters of invention, artificers use ingenuity and magic to unlock extraordinary capabilities in objects. They see magic as a complex system waiting to be decoded and then harnessed in their spells and inventions. You can find everything you need to play one of these inventors in the next few sections.</p>
			<p class="indent">Artificers use a variety of tools to channel their arcane power. To cast a spell, an artificer might use alchemist's supplies to create a potent elixir, calligrapher's supplies to inscribe a sigil of power, or tinker's tools to craft a temporary charm. The magic of artificers is tied to their tools and their talents, and few other characters can produce the right tool for a job as well as an artificer.</p>
			<h4>ARTIFICERS IN MANY WORLDS</h4>
			<p>Throughout the multiverse, artificers create inventions and magic items of peace and war. Many lives have been brightened or saved because of the work of kind artificers, but countless lives have also been lost because of the mass destruction unleashed by certain artificers' creations.</p>
			<p class="indent">In the Forgotten Realms, the island of Lantan is home to many artificers, and in the world of Dragonlance, tinker gnomes are often members of this class. The strange technologies in the Barrier Peaks of the world of Greyhawk have inspired some folk to walk the path of the artificer, and in Mystara, various nations employ artificers to keep airships and other wondrous devices operational.</p>
			<p class="indent">Artificers in the City of Sigil share discoveries from throughout the multiverse, and from there, the gnome artificer Vi runs a cosmos-spanning business that hires adventurers to fix problems that others deem unfixable. In Vi's home world, Eberron, magic is harnessed as a form of science and deployed throughout society, largely as a result of the wondrous ingenuity of artificers.</p>
			<h4>CREATING AN ARTIFICER</h4>
			<p>To create an artificer, consult the following subsections, which give you hit points, proficiencies, and starting equipment. Then look at the Artificer table to see which features you get at each level. The descriptions of those features appear in the "Artificer Features" section.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make an artificer quickly by following these suggestions. First, put your highest ability score in Intelligence, followed by Constitution or Dexterity. Second, choose the guild artisan background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a barbarian, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> ld8 per artificer level</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> ld8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per artificer level after 1 st</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
				<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
				<li><strong>Tools:</strong> Thieves' tools, tinker's tools, one type of artisan's tools of your choice</li>
			</ul>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
				<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand</li>
			</ul>
      <p>The secrets of gunpowder weapons have been discovered in various corners of the DnD multiverse. If your Dungeon Master uses the rules on firearms in the Dungeon Master's Guide and your artificer has been exposed to the operation of such weapons, your artificer is proficient with them.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>any two simple weapons of your choice</li>
				<li>a light crossbow and 20 bolts</li>
				<li>your choice of studded leather armor or scale mail</li>
        <li>thieves' tools and a dungeoneer's pack</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE ARTIFICER</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Infusions Known</td><td class="col-10">Infused Items</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 1st</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td class="left">Magical Tinkering, Spellcasting</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 2nd</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Infuse Item</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 3nd</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Artificer Specialist, The Right Tool for the Job</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Artificer Specialist feature</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Tool Expertise</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Flash of Genius</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Artificer Specialist feature</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 10th</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Magic Item Adept</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 11th</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Spell-Storing Item</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 12th</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 13th</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 14th</td><td>10</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Magic Item Savant</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 15th</td><td>10</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Artificer Specialist feature</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 16th</td><td>10</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 17th</td><td>10</td><td>5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 18th</td><td>12</td><td>6</td><td class="left">Magic Item Master</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 19th</td><td>12</td><td>6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 20th</td><td>12</td><td>6</td><td class="left">Soul of Artifice</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
				</table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGICAL_TINKERING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELLCASTING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_INFUSE_ITEM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARTIFICER_SPECIALIST" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_THE_RIGHT_TOOL_FOR_THE_JOB" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_TOOL_EXPERTISE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_FLASH_OF_GENIUS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_ADEPT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELL_STORING_ITEM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_SAVANT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_MASTER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SOUL_OF_ARTIFICE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A master of unlocking magic in everyday objects and supreme inventor.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A master of unlocking magic in everyday objects and supreme inventor.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Artificer)" number="1" supports="Artisan tools" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Artificer)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGICAL_TINKERING" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_INFUSE_ITEM" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARTIFICER_SPECIALIST" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_THE_RIGHT_TOOL_FOR_THE_JOB" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_TOOL_EXPERTISE" level="5" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_FLASH_OF_GENIUS" level="6" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_ADEPT" level="10" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELL_STORING_ITEM" level="11" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_SAVANT" level="14" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_MASTER" level="18" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SOUL_OF_ARTIFICE" level="20" />
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER">
			<prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light Armor, Medium Armor, Shields, Thieves' Tools, Tinker's Tools</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			  <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			  <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			  <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			  <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_MULTICLASS_ARTIFICER" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="Magical Tinkering" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGICAL_TINKERING">
		<description>
			<p>You've learned how to invest a spark of magic into mundane objects. To use this ability, you must have thieves' tools or artisan's tools in hand. You then touch a Tiny nonmagical object as an action and give it one of the following magical properties of your choice:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The object sheds bright light in a 5-foot radius and dim light for an additional 5 feet.</li>
				<li>Whenever tapped by a creature, the object emits a recorded message that can be heard up to 10 feet away. You utter the message when you bestow this property on the object, and the recording can be no more than 6 seconds long.</li>
				<li>The object continuously emits your choice of an odor or a nonverbal sound (wind, waves, chirping, or the like). The chosen phenomenon is perceivable up to 10 feet away.</li>
        <li>A static visual effect appears on one of the object's surfaces. This effect can be a picture, up to 25 words of text, lines and shapes, or a mixture of these elements, as you like.</li>
      </ul>
      <p class="indent">The chosen property lasts indefinitely. As an action, you can touch the object and end the property early.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can bestow magic on multiple objects, touching one object each time you use this feature, though a single object can only bear one property at a time. The maximum number of objects you can affect with this feature at one time is equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one object). If you try to exceed your maximum, the oldest property immediately ends, and then the new property applies.</p>
    </description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>Touch a Tiny nonmagical object to give it a magical property:
      • sheds bright light for 5ft and dim light for an additional 5 feet.
      • Record a 6 second message uttered object that will replay(percivable up to 10ft) when tapped by creature
      • The object emits an odor or nonverbal sound percivable up to 10ft
      • apply static visual effect(picture, 25 words, lines/shapes or a mixture of these.
      property last indefiniatly or until you use and action and touch the object to end it.
      Works on multiple objects, one at a time, one property per object, up to $(intelligence:modifier) objects, if exceeded oldest object property ends.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="artificer magical tinkering:count" value="intelligence:modifier" level="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELLCASTING">
		<description>
			<p>You've studied the workings of magic and how to cast spells, channeling the magic through objects. To observers, you don't appear to be casting spells in a conventional way; you appear to produce wonders from mundane items and outlandish inventions.·</p>
			<h5>TOOLS REQUIRED</h5>
      <p>You produce your artificer spell effects through your tools. You must have a spellcasting focus-specifically thieves' tools or some kind of artisan's tool-in hand when you cast any spell with this Spellcasting feature (meaning the spell has an "M" componentwhen you cast it). You must be proficient with the tool to use it in this way. See the equipment chapter in the Player's Handbook for descriptions of these tools.</p>
      <p class="indent">After you gain the Infuse Item feature at 2nd level, you can also use any item bearing one of your infusions as a spellcasting focus.</p>
      <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
			<p>You know two cantrips of your choice from the artificer spell list. At higher levels, you learn additional artificer cantrips of your choice, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Artificer table.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the artificer can trips you know with another cantrip from the artificer spell list.</p>
      <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
			<p>The Artificer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your artificer spells. To cast one of your artificer spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You prepare the list of artificer spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the artificer spell list. When you do so, choose a number of artificer spells equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your artificer level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
			<p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level artificer, you have four 1 st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1 st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
      <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of artificer spells requires time spent tinkering with your spellcasting focuses: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
      <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your artificer spells; your understanding of the theory behind magic allows you to wield these spells with superior skill. You use your Intelligence whenever an artificer spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an artificer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
			</center>
			<h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
			<p>You can cast an artificer spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have the ability to cast spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Artificer" ability="Intelligence" allowReplace="true" prepare="true">
			<list known="true">Artificer</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />

			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			<stat name="artificer:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:artificer:half" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Artificer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Artificer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Artificer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Artificer" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Artificer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="14" number="1" spellcasting="Artificer" />
    </rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Infuse Item" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_INFUSE_ITEM">
		<description>
			<p>You've gained the ability to imbue mundane items with certain magical infusions, turning those objects into magic items.</p>
			<h5>INFUSIONS KNOWN</h5>
			<p>When you gain this feature, pick four artificer infusions to learn, choosing from the "Artificer Infusions" section at the end of the class's description. You learn additional infusions of your choice when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Infusions Known column of the Artificer table.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the artificer infusions you learned with a new one.</p>
			<h5>INFUSING AN ITEM</h5>
			<p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch a nonmagical object and imbue it with one of your artificer infusions, turning it into a magic item. An infusion works on only certain kinds of objects, as specified in the infusion's description. If the item requires attunement, you can attune yourself to it the instant you infuse the item. If you decide to attune to the item later, you must do so using the normal process for attunement (see the attunement rules in the Dungeon Master's Guide).</p>
			<p class="indent">Your infusion remains in an item indefinitely, but when you die, the infusion vanishes after a number of days equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1 day). The infusion also vanishes if you replace your knowledge of the infusion.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can infuse more than one nonmagical object at the end of a long rest; the maximum number of objects appears in the Infused Items column of the Artificer table. You must touch each of the objects, and each of your infusions can be in only one object at a time. Moreover, no object can bear more than one of your infusions at a time. If you try to exceed your maximum number of infusions, the oldest infusion ends, and then the new infusion applies.</p>
		  <p class="indent">If an infusion ends on an item that contains other things, like a bag of holding, its contents harmlessly appear in and around its space.</p>
    </description>
		<sheet usage="{{infusion:spellcasting:prepare}} Maximum">
			<description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch a nonmagical object and imbue it with one of your artificer infusions, turning it into a magic item.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Infusion" ability="Intelligence" allowReplace="true" prepare="true">
			<list>Infusion</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>			
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:slots:1" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:slots:1" value="6" bonus="base" level="6" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:slots:1" value="8" bonus="base" level="10" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:slots:1" value="10" bonus="base" level="14" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:slots:1" value="12" bonus="base" level="18" />

			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:prepare" value="2" bonus="base" level="2" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:prepare" value="3" bonus="base" level="6" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:prepare" value="4" bonus="base" level="10" />
			<stat name="infusion:spellcasting:prepare" value="5" bonus="base" level="14" />
      <stat name="infusion:spellcasting:prepare" value="6" bonus="base" level="18" />

			<stat name="infusion:vanish" value="1" bonus="infusions" />
			<stat name="infusion:vanish" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="infusions" />

      <stat name="infusion:spellcasting:slot" value="level:half:up" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Infusion, Level 2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" number="4" level="2" spellcasting="Infusion" />
      <select type="Spell" name="Infusion, Level 6" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" number="2" level="6" spellcasting="Infusion" />
      <select type="Spell" name="Infusion, Level 10" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" number="2" level="10" spellcasting="Infusion" />
      <select type="Spell" name="Infusion, Level 14" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" number="2" level="14" spellcasting="Infusion" />
      <select type="Spell" name="Infusion, Level 18" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" number="2" level="18" spellcasting="Infusion" />
    </rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Artificer Specialist" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ARTIFICER_SPECIALIST">
		<description>
			<p>Choose the type of specialist you are: Alchemist, Armorer, Artillerist, or Battle Smith, each of which is detailed after the class's description. Your choice grants you features at 5th level and again at 9th and 15th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Artificer Specialist" supports="Artificer Specialist" level="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="The Right Tool For The Job" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_THE_RIGHT_TOOL_FOR_THE_JOB">
		<description>
			<p>You've learned how to produce exactly the tool you need: with thieves' tools or artisan's tools in hand, you can magically create one set of artisan's tools in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. This creation requires 1 hour of uninterrupted work, which can coincide with a short or long rest. Though the product of magic, the tools are nonmagical, and they vanish when you use this feature again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Create 1 set of artisans tools with thieves' tools or artisan's tools and 1 hour of uniterupted work. They vanish if you use this feature again.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th level and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Artificer 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Artificer,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Artificer 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Artificer,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Artificer 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Artificer,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Artificer 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Artificer,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Artificer 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Artificer,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Tool Expertise" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_TOOL_EXPERTISE">
		<description>
			<p>Your proficiency bonus is now doubled for any ability check you make that uses your proficiency with a tool.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your tool proficecy is doubled</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Flash of Genius" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_FLASH_OF_GENIUS">
		<description>
			<p>You've gained the ability to come up with solutions under pressure. When you or another creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an ability check or a saving throw, you can use your reaction to add your Intelligence modifier to the roll.</p>
      <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/long rest">
			<description>Add +$(intelligence:modifier) to an ability checks/saving throw made within 30ft you can see</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Magic Item Adept" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_ADEPT">
    <description>
			<p>You've achieved a profound understanding of how to use and make magic items:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>You can attune to up to four magic items at once.</li>
				<li>If you craft a magic item with a rarity of common or uncommon, it takes you a quarter of the normal time, and it costs you half as much of the usual gold.</li>
      </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can craft common/uncommon magic items in 1/4 time at 1/2 cost.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="attunement:max" value="4" bonus="base" level="10"/>
      <stat name="attunement:max" value="5" bonus="base" level="14"/>
      <stat name="attunement:max" value="6" bonus="base" level="18"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Spell Storing Item" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SPELL_STORING_ITEM">
		<description>
			<p>You can now store a spell in an object. Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch one simple or martial weapon or one item that you can use as a spellcasting focus, and you store a spell in it, choosing a 1st- or 2nd-level spell from the artificer spell list that requires 1 action to cast (you needn't have it prepared).</p>
      <p class="indent">While holding the object, a creature can take an action to produce the spell's effect from it, using your spellcasting ability modifier. If the spell requires concentration, the creature must concentrate. The spell stays in the object until it's been used a number of times equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of twice) or until you use this feature again to store a spell in an object.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/long rest">
			<description>Store a 1st/2nd level spell that casts in 1 action into an object/weapon. A creature can use 1 action to cast the spell with a +$(intelligence:modifier) modifier for $(Spell Storing Charges:count) charges</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="Spell Storing Charges:count" value="intelligence:modifier" />
      <stat name="Spell Storing Charges:count" value="intelligence:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Magic Item Savant" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_SAVANT">
    <description>
			<p>Your skill with magic items deepens:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>You can attune to up to 5 magic items at once.</li>
				<li>You ignore all class, race, spell, and level requirements on attuning to or using a magic item.</li>
      </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Ignore class, race, spell, and level requirements for magic items.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="attunement:max" value="5" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Magic Item Master" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_MAGIC_ITEM_MASTER">
		<description>
			<p>You can attune to up to 6 magic items at once.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You can attune 6 magic items</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="attunement:max" value="6" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Soul of Artifice" type="Class Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_CLASS_FEATURE_ARTIFICER_SOUL_OF_ARTIFICE">
		<description>
			<p>You have developed a mystical connection to your magic items, which you can draw on for protection:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to all saving throws per magic item you are currently attuned to.</li>
				<li>If you're reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can use your reaction to end one of your artificer infusions, causing you to drop to 1 hit point instead of 0.</li>
      </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>+1/attuned item to all saving throws. If reduced to 0HP and still alive, you can use your reaction to end 1 infusion and be at 1HP vs 0HP</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:save:misc" value="attunement:current" />
      <stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="attunement:current" />
      <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="attunement:current" />
      <stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="attunement:current" />
      <stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="attunement:current" />
      <stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="attunement:current" />
		</rules>
	</element>

  <element name="Alchemist" type="Archetype" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_ARTIFICER_ALCHEMIST">
		<supports>Artificer Specialist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An Alchemist is an expert at combining reagents to produce mystical effects. Alchemists use their creations to give life and to leech it away. Alchemy is the oldest of artificer traditions, and its versatility has long been valued during times of war and peace.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMICAL_SAVANT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_RESTORATIVE_REAGANTS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_CHEMICAL_MASTERY" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMICAL_SAVANT" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_RESTORATIVE_REAGANTS" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_CHEMICAL_MASTERY" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Tool Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_TOOL_PROFICIENCY">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with alchemist's supplies. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan's tools of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Tools of the Trade" supports="Artisan tools" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Alchemist Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Alchemist Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Alchemist Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Artificer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>healing word, ray of sickness</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>flaming sphere, Melf's acid arrow</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>gaseous form, mass healing word</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>blight, death ward</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>cloudkill, raise dead</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_ACID_ARROW" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Experimental Elixir" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR">
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can magically produce an experimental elixir in an empty flask you touch. Roll on the Experimental Elixir table for the elixir's effect, which is triggered when someone drinks the elixir. As an action, a creature can drink the elixir or administer it to an incapacitated creature.</p>
      <p class="indent">You can create additional experimental elixirs by expending a spell slot of 1 st level or higher for each one. When you do so, you use your action to create the elixir in an empty flask you touch, and you choose the elixir's effect from the Experimental Elixir table.</p>
      <p class="indent">Creating an experimental elixir requires you to have alchemist supplies on your person, and any elixir you create with this feature lasts until it is drunk or until the end of your next long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you reach certain levels in this class, you can make more elixirs at the end of a long rest: two at 6th level and three at 1 5th level. Roll for each elixir's effect separately. Each elixir requires its own flask.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Experimental Elixir</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>d6</td><td>Effect</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td><em><strong>Healing.</strong> The drinker regains a number of hit points equal to 2d4 + your Intelligence modifier.</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td><em><strong>Swiftness.</strong>The drinker's walking speed increased by 10 feet for 1 hour.</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td><em><strong>Resilience.</strong>The driker gains a +1 bonus to AC for 10 minutes</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td><em><strong>boldness.</strong>The drinker can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to every attack roll and saving trow they make for the next minute</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td><em><strong>Flight.</strong>The drinker gains a flying speed of 10 feet for 10 minutes.</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>6</td><td><em><strong>Transformation.</strong>The drinker's body is transformed as if by the alter self spell. The drinker determines the transformation caused by teh spell effects of which last for 10 minutes.</em></td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
		<sheet usage="1/long rest">
			<description>You can produce $(Alchemist Elixer:count) elixer in an empty flask you touch using alchemist supplies, with a random property that is triggered when drunk.
      You can create elixers with chosen properties by expending spell slots. Elixers last until drunk or the end of a long rest.
      1)Healing:2d4+$(intelligence:modifier), 2)Swiftness:walk speed +10 for 1hr, 3)Resillience:+1 AC for 10min, 4)Boldness:+d4 to attack rolls/saving thorws for 10min, 5)Flight:fly speed +10 for 10min, 6)Transformation:tranformed as if by alter self spell for 10mins</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="Alchemist Elixer:count" value="1" level="3" />
      <stat name="Alchemist Elixer:count" value="1" level="6" />
      <stat name="Alchemist Elixer:count" value="1" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Alchemical Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMICAL_SAVANT">
		<description>
			<p>You've developed masterful command of magical chemicals, enhancing the healing and damage you create through them. Whenever you cast a spell using your alchemist's supplies as the spellcasting focus, you gain a bonus to one roll of the spell. That roll must restore hit points or be a damage roll that deals acid, fire, necrotic, or poison damage, and the bonus equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +l).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>using achemical supplies to cast a spell grants +$(intelligence:modifier) to any healing or damage roll(acid, fire, necrotic, or poison)</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>  
  <element name="Restorative Reagants" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_RESTORATIVE_REAGANTS">
		<description>
			<p>You can incorporate restorative reagents into some of your works:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>Whenever a creature drinks an experimental elixir you created, the creature gains temporary hit points equal to 2d6 + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point).</li>
				<li>You can cast lesser restoration without expending a spell slot and without preparing the spell, provided you use alchemist's supplies as the spellcasting focus. You can do so a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>any experimental elixer grants 2d6+$(intelligence:modifier) temporary hit points
      $(intelligence:modifier)/long rest - cast lesser restoration using alchemical supplies</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Artificer" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Chemical Matery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_CHEMICAL_MASTERY">
		<description>
			<p>You have been exposed to so many chemicals that they pose little risk to you, and you can use them to quickly end certain ailments:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>You gain resistance to acid damage and poison damage, and you are immune to the poisoned condition.</li>
				<li>You can cast greater restoration and heal without expending a spell slot, without preparing the spell, and without material components, provided you use alchemist's supplies as the spellcasting focus. Once you cast ·either spell with this feature, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>resistant to acid and poison damage and immune to poisoned condidtion
      1/long rest - may cast greater restoration and heal using alchemical supplies</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Artificer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAL" spellcasting="Artificer" />
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Armorer" type="Archetype" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_ARTIFICER_ARMORER">
		<supports>Artificer Specialist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An artificer who specializes as an Armorer modifies armor to function almost like a second skin. The armor is enhanced to hone the artificer's magic, unleash potent attacks, and generate a formidable defense. The artificer bonds with this armor, becoming one with it even as they experiment with it and refine its magical capabilities.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_TOOLS_OF_THE_TRADE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMORER_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARCANE_ARMOR" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODIFICATIONS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_TOOLS_OF_THE_TRADE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMORER_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARCANE_ARMOR" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODIFICATIONS" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tools of the Trade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_TOOLS_OF_THE_TRADE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with heavy armor. You also gain proficiency with smith's tools. If you already have this tool proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan's tools of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Tools of the Trade" supports="Artisan tools" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Armorer Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMORER_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Armorer Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Armorer Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Artificer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic missile, thunderwave</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>mirror image, shatter</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>hypnotic pattern, lightning bolt</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>fire shield, greater invisibility</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>passwall, wall of force</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASSWALL" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARCANE_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>Your metallurgical pursuits have led to you making armor a conduit for your magic. As an action, you can turn a suit of armor you are wearing into Arcane Armor, provided you have smith's tools in hand.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain the following benefits while wearing this armor:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>If the armor normally has a Strength requirement, the arcane armor lacks this requirement for you.</li>
				<li>You can use the arcane armor as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells.</li>
				<li>The armor attaches to you and can’t be removed against your will. It also expands to cover your entire body, although you can retract or deploy the helmet as a bonus action. The armor replaces any missing limbs, functioning identically to a limb it replaces.</li>
				<li>You can doff or don the armor as an action.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">The armor continues to be Arcane Armor until you don another suit of armor or you die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can turn a suit of armor you are wearing into Arcane Armor, provided you have smith’s tools in hand. You gain the following benefits while wearing this armor:  &#13;
			• If the armor normally has a Strength requirement, the arcane armor lacks this requirement for you. &#13;
			• You can use the arcane armor as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells. &#13;
			• The armor attaches to you and can’t be removed against your will. It also expands to cover your entire body, although you can retract or deploy the helmet as a bonus action. The armor replaces any missing limbs, functioning identically to a limb it replaces. &#13;
			• You can doff or don the armor as an action.
			The armor continues to be Arcane Armor until you don another suit of armor or you die.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed" value="0" bonus="armor" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Armor Model" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL">
		<description>
			<p>You can customize your Arcane Armor. When you do so, choose one of the following armor models: Guardian or Infiltrator. The model you choose gives you special benefits while you wear it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each model includes a special weapon. When you attack with that weapon, you can add your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, to the attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can change the armor’s model whenever you finish a short or long rest, provided you have smith’s tools in hand.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR" />
    </description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can customize your Arcane Armor. Each model includes a special weapon. When you attack with that weapon, you can add your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, to the attack and damage rolls. 
			You can change the armor’s model whenever you finish a short or long rest, provided you have smith’s tools in hand.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN" />
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN_THUNDER_GAUNTLETS" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN_DEFENSIVE_FIELD" />
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR" />
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR_LIGHTNING_LAUNCHER" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR_POWERED_STEPS" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Armor Model, Armorer" supports="Armor Model" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR_DAMPENING_FIELD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You design your armor to be in the front line of conflict. It has the following features:</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Thunder Gauntlets.</strong> Each of the armor’s gauntlets counts as a simple melee weapon while you aren’t holding anything in it, and it deals 1d8 thunder damage on a hit. A creature hit by the gauntlet has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the start of your next turn, as the armor magically emits a distracting pulse when the creature attacks someone else. </p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Defensive Field.</strong> As a bonus action, you can gain temporary hit points equal to your level in this class, replacing any temporary hit points you already have. You lose these temporary hit points if you doff the armor. You can use this bonus action a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Armor Model">
			<description>You design your armor to be in the front line of conflict.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Thunder Gauntlets" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN_THUNDER_GAUNTLETS">
		<compendium display="false" />
    <supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Each of the armor’s gauntlets counts as a simple melee weapon while you aren’t holding anything in it, and it deals 1d8 thunder damage on a hit. A creature hit by the gauntlet has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the start of your next turn, as the armor magically emits a distracting pulse when the creature attacks someone else.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet >
			<description>Each of the armor’s gauntlets counts as a simple melee weapon while you aren’t holding anything in it, and it deals 1d8 thunder damage on a hit. A creature hit by the gauntlet has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the start of your next turn, as the armor magically emits a distracting pulse when the creature attacks someone else.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Defensive Field" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_GUARDIAN_DEFENSIVE_FIELD">
		<compendium display="false" />
    <supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can gain temporary hit points equal to your level in this class, replacing any temporary hit points you already have. You lose these temporary hit points if you doff the armor. You can use this bonus action a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You can gain {{level:artificer}} temporary hps, replacing any temporary hps you already have. You lose these temporary hps if you doff the armor.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Infiltrator" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can customize your armor for subtle undertakings. It has the following features:</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Lightning Launcher.</strong> A gemlike node appears on one of your armored fists or on the chest (your choice). It counts as a simple ranged weapon, with a normal range of 90 feet and a long range of 300 feet, and it deals 1d6 lightning damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with it, you can deal an extra 1d6 lightning damage to that target.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Powered Steps.</strong> Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
			<p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>Dampening Field.</strong> You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. If the armor normally imposes disadvantage on such checks, the advantage and disadvantage cancel each other, as normal.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Armor Model">
			<description>You can customize your armor for subtle undertakings.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Lightning Launcher" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR_LIGHTNING_LAUNCHER">
		<compendium display="false" />
    <supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A gemlike node appears on one of your armored fists or on the chest (your choice). It counts as a simple ranged weapon, with a normal range of 90 feet and a long range of 300 feet, and it deals 1d6 lightning damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with it, you can deal an extra 1d6 lightning damage to that target.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>A gemlike node appears on one of your armored fists or on the chest. It counts as a simple ranged weapon, with a normal range of 90 feet and a long range of 300 feet, and it deals 1d6 lightning damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with it, you can deal an extra 1d6 lightning damage to that target.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Powered Steps" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR_POWERED_STEPS">
		<compendium display="false" />
    <supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:misc" value="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dampening Field" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODEL_INFILTRATOR_DAMPENING_FIELD">
		<compendium display="false" />
    <supports>Armor Model</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. If the armor normally imposes disadvantage on such checks, the advantage and disadvantage cancel each other, as normal.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on Stealth checks. If the armor normally imposes disadvantage on such checks, the advantage and disadvantage cancel each other, as normal.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>You can attack twice, rather than once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, rather than once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Armor Modifications" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_ARMOR_MODIFICATIONS">
		<description>
			<p>You learn how to use your artificer infusions to specially modify your Arcane Armor. That armor now counts as separate items for the purposes of your Infuse Items feature: armor (the chest piece), boots, helmet, and the armor’s special weapon. Each of those items can bear one of your infusions, and the infusions transfer over if you change your armor’s model with the Armor Model feature. In addition, the maximum number of items you can infuse at once increases by 2, but those extra items must be part of your Arcane Armor.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>That armor now counts as separate items for the purposes of your Infuse Items feature: armor, boots, helmet, and the armor’s special weapon. Each of those items can bear one of your infusions, and the infusions transfer over if you change your armor’s model with the Armor Model feature.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>		
			<stat name="item infusions:max" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Perfected Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>Your Arcane Armor gains additional benefits based on its model, as shown below.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Guardian.</em></strong> When a Huge or smaller creature you can see ends its turn within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to magically force the creature to make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC, pulling the creature up to 30 feet toward you to an unoccupied space. If you pull the target to a space within 5 feet of you, you can make a melee weapon attack against it as part of this reaction.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this reaction a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Infiltrator.</em></strong> Any creature that takes lightning damage from your Lightning Launcher glimmers with magical light until the start of your next turn. The glimmering creature sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius, and it has disadvantage on attack rolls against you, as the light jolts it if it attacks you. In addition, the next attack roll against it has advantage, and if that attack hits, the target takes an extra 1d6 lightning damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your Arcane Armor gains additional benefits based on its model.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR_GUARDIAN" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR_INFILTRATOR" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Perfected Guardian Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR_GUARDIAN">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When a Huge or smaller creature you can see ends its turn within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to magically force the creature to make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC, pulling the creature up to 30 feet toward you to an unoccupied space. If you pull the target to a space within 5 feet of you, you can make a melee weapon attack against it as part of this reaction.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this reaction a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When a Huge or smaller creature you can see ends its turn within 30 feet of you, you can magically force the creature to make a DC{{artificer:spellcasting:dc}} Strength save, pulling the creature up to 30 feet toward you to an unoccupied space. If you pull the target to a space within 5 feet of you, you can make a melee weapon attack against it as part of this reaction.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Perfected Infiltrator Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMORER_PERFECTED_ARMOR_INFILTRATOR">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Any creature that takes lightning damage from your Lightning Launcher glimmers with magical light until the start of your next turn. The glimmering creature sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius, and it has disadvantage on attack rolls against you, as the light jolts it if it attacks you. In addition, the next attack roll against it has advantage, and if that attack hits, the target takes an extra 1d6 lightning damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Any creature that takes lightning damage from your Lightning Launcher glimmers with magical light until the start of your next turn. The glimmering creature sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius, and it has disadvantage on attack rolls against you, as the light jolts it if it attacks you. In addition, the next attack roll against it has advantage, and if that attack hits, the target takes an extra 1d6 lightning damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

  <element name="Artillerist" type="Archetype" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_ARTIFICER_ARTILLERIST">
		<supports>Artificer Specialist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An Artillerist specializes in using magic to hurl energy, projectiles, and explosions on a battlefield. This destructive power is valued by armies in the wars on many different worlds. And when war passes, some members of this specialization seek to build a more peaceful world by using their powers to fight the resurgence of strife. The world-hopping gnome artificer Vi has been especially vocal about making things right: "It's about time we fixed things instead of blowing them all to hell."</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_ELDRITCH_CANNON" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_ARCANE_FIREARM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_EXPLOSIVE_CANNON" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FORTIFIED_POSITION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_ELDRITCH_CANNON" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_ARCANE_FIREARM" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_EXPLOSIVE_CANNON" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FORTIFIED_POSITION" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Tool Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_TOOL_PROFICIENCY">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with woodcarver's tools. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan's tools of your choice.</p>
    </description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Tools of the Trade" supports="Artisan tools" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_WOODCARVERS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Artillerist Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Artillerist Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Artillerist Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Artillerist Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>shield, thunderwave</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>scorching ray, shatter</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>fireball, wind wall</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>ice storm, wall of fire</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>cone of cold, wall of force</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Eldritch Cannon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_ELDRITCH_CANNON">
		<description>
			<p>You've learned how to create a magical cannon. Using woodcarver's tools or smith's tools, you can take an action to magically create a Small or Tiny eldritch cannon in an unoccupied space on a horizontal surface within 5 feet of you. A Small eldritch cannon occupies its space, and a Tiny one can be held in one hand.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you create a cannon, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot to create one. You can have only one cannon at a time and can't create one while your cannon is present.</p>
      <p class="indent">The cannon is a magical object. Regardless of size, the cannon has an AC of 18 and a number of hit points equal to five times your artificer level. It is immune to poison damage and psychic damage. If it is forced to make an ability check or a saving throw, treat all its ability scores as 10 (+O). If the mending spell is cast on it, it regains 2d6 hit points. It disappears if it is reduced to 0 hit points or after 1 hour. You can dismiss it early as an action.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you create the cannon, you determine its appearance and whether it has legs. You also decide which type it is, choosing from the options on the Eldritch Cannons table. On each of your turns, you can take a bonus action to cause the cannon to activate if you are within 60 feet of it. As part of the same bonus action, you can direct the cannon to walk or climb up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space, provided it has legs.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Eldritch Cannons</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Cannon</td><td>Activation</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>Flamethrower</td><td><em>The cannon exhales fire in an adjacent 15-foot cone that you designate. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 2d8 fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>Force Ballista</td><td><em>Make a ranged spell attack, originating from the cannon, at one creature or object with in 120 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 force damage, and if the target is a creature, it is pushed up to 5. feet away from the cannon.</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>Protector</td><td><em>The cannon emits a burst of positive energy that grants itself and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of it a number of temporary hit points equal to ld8 + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +l).</em></td></tr>
			</table>
    </description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="1/long rest">
			<description>Use woodcarvers tools or smiths tools to creae a small or tiny eldritch cannon on an unoccupied horizontal surace within 5ft of you. tiny cannons can be held in hand. You can only have 1 at a time.
      The cannon is a magical object with an AC of 18, HP is 5 X artificer level, immune to poison and physcic damage, all saving throws and ability scores are 10(+0)
      Casting mending on the cannon restores 2d6 hit points.
      it disaperas if reduced to 0 hit points or after 1 hour or you dismiss it.
      You can use a bonus action, if you are within 60ft, you can move the cannon up to 15ft and activate it.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Eldritch Cannon, Artillerist" supports="Eldritch Cannon" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FLAMETHROWER" />
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Eldritch Cannon, Artillerist" supports="Eldritch Cannon" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FORCE_BALLISTA" />
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Eldritch Cannon, Artillerist" supports="Eldritch Cannon" default="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_PROTECTOR" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Flamethrower" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FLAMETHROWER">
		<supports>Eldritch Cannon</supports>
    <description>
			<p>The cannon exhales fire in an adjacent 15-foot cone that you designate. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 2d8 fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Cannon fires a 15ft cone, each creature inside makes a dexterity saving throw against your spell DC, taking 2d8 fire damage on a failed save and half as much if successful. The fire ignites any flamible objects that aren't being worn or carried.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Force Ballista" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FORCE_BALLISTA">
		<supports>Eldritch Cannon</supports>
    <description>
			<p>Make a ranged spell attack, originating from the cannon, at one creature or object with in 120 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 force damage, and if the target is a creature, it is pushed up to 5. feet away from the cannon.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="range 120ft">
			<description>cannon makes a ranged spell attack. Does 2d8 force damage on hit and target is pushed 5ft away from cannon.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Protector" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_PROTECTOR">
		<supports>Eldritch Cannon</supports>
    <description>
			<p>The cannon emits a burst of positive energy that grants itself and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of it a number of temporary hit points equal to ld8 + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +l).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>cannon heals itself and each creature of your choice within 10ft 1d8 +$(intelligence:modifier) temporary hit points</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Arcane Firearm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_ARCANE_FIREARM">
		<description>
			<p>You know how to turn a wand, staff, or rod into an arcane firearm, a conduit for your destructive spells. When you finish a long rest, you can use woodcarver's tools to carve special sigils into a wand, staff, or rod and thereby turn it into your arcane firearm. The sigils disappear from the object if you later carve them on a different item. The sigils otherwise last indefinitely.</p>
      <p class="indent">You can use your arcane firearm as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells. When you cast an artificer spell through the firearm, roll a d8, and you gain a bonus to one of the spell's damage rolls equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/long rest">
			<description>Turn a rod, staff, or wand into your arcane firearm. When arcane firearm used as your spellcasting focus, add 1d8 to one of the spells damage rolls</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>  
  <element name="Explosive Cannon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_EXPLOSIVE_CANNON">
		<description>
			<p>Every eldritch cannon you create is now more destructive:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>The cannon's damage rolls all increase by ld8.</li>
        <li>As an action, you can command the cannon to detonate if you are within 60 feet of it. Doing so destroys the cannon and forces each creature within 20 feet of it to make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 3d8 force damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>Each cannon gains +1d8 to damage rolls
      if you are within 60ft, use an action to command the cannon to detonate, destroying itself. each creature within 20ft makes a dexterity saving throw vs your spell DC, taking 3d8 force damage on a failed save and half as much on a successful one.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>  
  <element name="Fortified Position" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTILLERIST_FORTIFIED_POSITION">
		<description>
			<p>You're a master at forming well-defended emplacements using your Eldritch Cannon:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>You and your allies have half cover while within 10 feet of a cannon you create with Eldritch Cannon, as a result of a shimmering field of magical protection that the cannon emits.</li>
        <li>You can now have two cannons at the same time. You can create two with the same action (but not the same spell slot), and you can activate both of them with the same bonus action. You determine whether the cannons are identical to each other or different. You can't create a third cannon while you have two.</li>
      </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>a shimmering field provides you and your allies half cover within 10ft of your cannon
      You can create 2 cannons with your action and command them both with the same bonus action. The cannons may be different and you cannot create a third while you have 2.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="attunement:max" value="6" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

  <element name="Battle Smith" type="Archetype" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_ARTIFICER_BATTLE_SMITH">
		<supports>Artificer Specialist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Armies require protection, and someone has to put things back together if defenses fail. A combination of protector and medic, a Battle Smith is an expert at defending others and repairing both materiel and personnel. To aid in their work, Battle Smiths are accompanied by a steel defender, a protective companion of their own creation. Many soldiers tell stories of nearly dying before being saved by a Battle Smith and a steel defender.</p>
			<p class="indent">In t.he world of Eberron, Battle Smiths played a key role in House Cannith's work on battle constructs and the original warforged, and after the Last War, these artificers led efforts to aid those who were injured in the war's horrific battles.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_BATTLE_READY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_STEEL_DEFENDER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_ARCANE_JOLT" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_IMPROVED_DEFENDER" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_BATTLE_READY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_STEEL_DEFENDER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_ARCANE_JOLT" level="9" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_IMPROVED_DEFENDER" level="9" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Tool Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_TOOL_PROFICIENCY">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with smith's tools. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan's tools of your choice.</p>
      <p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Tools of the Trade" supports="Artisan tools" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Battle Smith Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Battle Smith Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Battle Smith Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Battle Smith Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>shield, heroism</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>branding smite, warding bond</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>aura of vitality, conjure barrage</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>aura of purity, fire shield</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>banishing smite, mass cure wounds</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_VITALITY" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_BARRAGE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Battle Ready" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_BATTLE_READY">
		<description>
			<p>Your combat training and your experiments with magic have paid off in two ways:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>You gain proficiency with martial weapons.</li>
        <li>When you attack with a magic weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity modifier, for the attack and damage rolls.</li>
      </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you attack with a magic weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity modifier, for the attack and damage rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Steel Defender" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_STEEL_DEFENDER">
		<description>
			<p>Your tinkering has borne you a companion, a steel defender. It's friendly to you and your companions, and it obeys your commands. See its game statistics in the Steel Defender stat block, which uses your proficiency bonus (PB) in several places. You determine the creature's appearance and whether it has two legs or four; your choice has no effect on its game statistics.</p>
      <p class="indent">In combat, the defender shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It can move and use its reaction on its own, but the only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take another action. That action can be one in its stat block or some other action. If you are incapacitated, the defender can take any action of its choice, not just Dodge.</p>
      <p class="indent">If the mending spell is cast on the defender, it regains 2d6 hit points. If it has died within the last hour, you can use your smith's tools as an action to revive it, provided you are within 5 feet of it and you expend a spell slot of 1 st level or higher. The defender returns to life after 1 minute with all its hit points restored.</p>
      <p class="indent">At the end of a long rest, you can create a new steel defender if you have smith's tools with you. If you already have a defender from this feature, the first one immediately perishes. The defender also perishes if you die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>once per long rest you can create a companion that uses the steel defender stat block and dies when you die.
      In combat the defender shares yoru initiative and takes it turn immediatly after yours, it can move and react on its own but can only take the dodge action unless you use your bonus action to command it otherwise. If you are incapacitates, the defender can take any action.
      casting mending on the defender restores 2d6 HP. If it has died within the last hour, you can use your smith's tools as an action to revive it, if you are within 5ft and you expend a spell slot, otherwise it returns to life after 1 minute with full HP.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="attunement:max" value="6" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>You can attack twice, rather than once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, rather than once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>  
  <element name="Arcane Jolt" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_ARCANE_JOLT">
		<description>
			<p>You've learned new ways to channel arcane energy to harm or heal. When either you hit a target with a magic weapon attack or your steel defender hits a target, you can channel magical energy through the strike to create one of the following effects:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>The target takes an extra 2d6 force damage.</li>
        <li>Choose one creature or object you can see within 30 feet of the target. Healing energy flows into the chosen recipient, restoring 2d6 hit points to it.</li>
      </ul>
      <p class="indent">You can use this energy a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), but you can do so no more than once on a turn. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="$(intelligence:modifier)/long rest">
			<description>once per turn, cause one of these effect when you hit with a magic weapon attack or your steel defender hits
      target takes +2d6 force damage
      heal createure within 30ft for 2d6 hit points</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <element name="Improved Defender" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_SMITH_IMPROVED_DEFENDER">
		<description>
			<p>Your Arcane jolt and steel defender have become more powerful:</p>
      <ul>
				<li>The extra damage and the healing of your Arcane Jolt both increase to 4d6.</li>
        <li>Your steel defender gains a +2 bonus to Armor Class.</li>
        <li>Whenever your steel defender uses its Deflect Attack, the attacker takes force damage equal to ld4 + your Intelligence modifier.</li>
      </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The extra damage and the healing of your Arcane Jolt both increase to 4d6.
      Your steel defender gains a +2 bonus to Armor Class.
      Whenever your steel defender uses its Deflect Attack, the attacker takes force damage equal to ld4 +$(intelligence:modifier).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="attunement:max" value="6" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>