<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Eberron: Forge of the Artificer" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_EBERRON_FORGE_OF_THE_ARTIFICER">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>In the shadowed underlayers of Sharn — the City of Towers — secrets trade hands in steam-filled alleys, and invention sparks beneath the weight of power and ambition. Here, Artificers are visionaries who blend spellcraft and invention, using gears and magic in equal measure to turn the impossible into reality. They see the arcane not merely as mystery, but as mechanism — something to be decoded, refined, and brought to life.</p>
			<p class="indent">Forge wonders with the Artificer — the ultimate creative class! This 112-page expansion unlocks your workshop of the arcane:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>5 subclasses</b> (four reimagined and one new): The Cartographer, who charts the unknown with maps that reshape reality.</li>
				<li><b>5 revised species</b>, <b>17 evocative backgrounds</b>, and <b>28 feats</b> that let your imagination defy gravity.</li>
				<li><b>A new spell</b>, <b>bastions</b>, and <b>magical innovations</b> that turn every choice into a creation.</li>
				<li><b>3 campaign frameworks</b> to channel Eberron's wild genres: noir intrigue, sky-high pulp, and political peril.</li>
				<li><b>20+ new monsters</b>, each tailors to haunt, thrill, or awe in the genre you're forging.</li>
			</ul>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">EFOTA</set>
			<set name="url">https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/category/5147000?pid=DB5147000/</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/eberron-forge-of-the-artificer/EFOTA.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="information">D&amp;D 5.5e</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="core">false</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20251209</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
